[
    {
        "question": "Which are characteristics of a cold air mass moving over a warm surface?\n",
        "answer": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds, smooth air, and poor visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which meteorological environment\nhighest rate of accumulation?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High humidity and freezing temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of center of gravity on the spin characteristics of an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A flat spin may develop if the CG is too far aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the CG is too far forward, spin entry will be difficult.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If the CG is too far aft, spins can become high-speed spirals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) of P6SM implies that the\nprevailing visibility is expected to be greater than\n",
        "answer": "6 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 nautical miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 kilometers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 6.) With regard to the soundings taken at 0900 hours, from 2,500 feet to\n1,000 feet, as shown on the Adiabatic Chart, what minimum surface temperature is\n\nrequired for instability to occur and for good thermals to develop from the surface to\n15,000 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "80 degrees F.\n",
        "choiceone": "58 degrees F.\n",
        "choicetwo": "68 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "RB\" wind entry in a Terminal Aerodome Forecast (TAF) will be\nwind is\n",
        "answer": "3 knots or less.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 knots or less.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 knots or less.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The general characteristics of unstable air are\n",
        "answer": "good visibility, showery precipitation, and cumuliform-type clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "good visibility, steady precipitation, and stratiform-type clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "poor visibility, intermittent precipitation, and cumuliform-type clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fog produced by frontal activity is a result of saturation due to\n",
        "answer": "evaporation of precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "nocturnal cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "adiabatic cooling.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the normal location of the jetstream relative to surface lows and fronts?\n",
        "answer": "The jetstream is located north of the surface systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "The jetstream is located south of the low and warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The jetstream is located over the low and crosses both the warm front and the cold\nfront.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are the only cloud types forecast in the Terminal Aerodrome Forecast?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus\n",
        "choiceone": "Altocumulus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are characteristics of an unstable cold air mass moving over a warm surface?\n",
        "answer": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds, smooth air, and poor visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect does haze have on the ability to see traffic or terrain features during flight?\n",
        "answer": "All traffic or terrain features appear to be farther away than their actual distance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Haze causes the eyes to focus at infinity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The eyes tend to overwork in haze and do not detect relative movement easily.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common type of ground or surface based temperature inversion is that which is\n\nproduced by\n",
        "answer": "ground radiation on clear, cool nights when the wind is light.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air being lifted rapidly aloft in the vicinity of mountainous terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the movement of colder air over warm air, or the movement of warm air under cold\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dashed lines on a Surface Analysis Chart, if depicted,\ngradient is\n\n",
        "answer": "weak.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 154.) What is the height of the 300-millibar level at the low pressure?\n",
        "answer": "9,120 meters MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 meters MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11,850 meters MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the requirements for the formation of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Sufficient moisture, an unstable lapse rate, and a lifting action.\n",
        "choiceone": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture and an inverted lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary cause of all changes in the Earth's weather is\n",
        "answer": "variation of solar energy received by the Earth's regions.\n",
        "choiceone": "changes in air pressure over the Earth's surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "movement of the air masses.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an indication that downdrafts have developed and the thunderstorm cell has\nentered the mature stage?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation begins to fall from the cloud base.\n",
        "choiceone": "The anvil top has completed its development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gust front forms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is a body of air that\n",
        "answer": "covers an extensive area and has fairly uniform properties of temperature and\nmoisture.\n",
        "choiceone": "has similar cloud formations associated with it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "creates a wind shift as it moves across the Earth's surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 2.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative to\nISA) should a pilot expect when planning for a flight over ALB at FL 270?\n",
        "answer": "275 degrees true at 97 knots; ISA +4 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees magnetic at 97 knots; ISA -4 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees true at 110 knots; ISA +5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high cloud is composed mostly of\n",
        "answer": "ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "ozone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "condensation nuclei.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area forecasts generally include a forecast period of 18 hours and cover a geographical\n",
        "answer": "area the size of several states.\n",
        "choiceone": "terminal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "area less than 3000 square miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement pertaining to the life cycle of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "answer": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the mature stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Updrafts continue to develop throughout the dissipating stage of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the dissipating stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding ridge soaring with the wind direction perpendicular to the\nridge?\n",
        "answer": "If the glider drifts downwind from the ridge and sinks slightly lower than the crest of\nthe ridge, the glider should be turned away from the ridge and a high speed attained.\n",
        "choiceone": "When very close to the surface of the ridge, the glider's speed should be reduced to\nthe minimum sink speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the wind and lift are very strong on the windward side of the ridge, a weak sink\ncondition will exist on the leeward side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 152.) What weather conditions are depicted in the area\narrow C on the Radar Summary Chart?\n\n",
        "answer": "Area movement toward the northeast at 20 knots; strong to very strong echoes;\necho tops 28,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Average echo bases 2,800 feet MSL; thundershowers; intense to extreme echo\nintensity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cell movement toward the northwest at 20 knots; intense echoes; echo bases\n28,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant Pressure Analysis Charts contain contours, isotherms and some con\nisotachs. The contours depict\n",
        "answer": "ridges, lows, troughs and highs aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges on the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges corrected to MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ice pellets encountered during flight are normally evidence that\n",
        "answer": "freezing rain exists at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed is represented by the entry 9900+00 for 9,000 feet, on an\nWinds and Temperatures Aloft Forecast (FD)?\n",
        "answer": "Light and variable; less than 5 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Vortex winds exceeding 200 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light and variable; less than 10 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During departure, under conditions of suspected low-level wind shear, a sudden\ndecrease in headwind will cause\n",
        "answer": "a loss in airspeed equal to the decrease in wind velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "a gain in airspeed equal to the decrease in wind velocity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "no change in airspeed, but groundspeed will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix 'nimbus\u2019, used in naming clouds, means a\n",
        "answer": "rain cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "cloud with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dark massive, towering cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When in summer calm and clear conditions exist, a station on the shore of a large body\nof water will experience wind\n",
        "answer": "from the water in daytime and from the land at night\n",
        "choiceone": "continually from land to water\n",
        "choicetwo": "continually from water to the land\n",
        "choicethree": "from the land in daytime and from the water at night\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms suddenly by day but not by night\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is formed when the air is unstable\n",
        "choicethree": "It develops slowly and dissipates rapidly\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Snow grains\n",
        "answer": "fall from stratus or supercooled fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "are normally transparent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "are mainly formed inside altostratus and nimbostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "are typically formed inside a CB, where they are being tossed up and down while\ngrowing to such size that they could no longer be supported in the updraught.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10766A)\nThe weather most likely to be experienced at position \"S\" is\n",
        "answer": "overcast with drizzle and orographic fog\n",
        "choiceone": "scattered thunderstorms and good visibility\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing AS and NS with moderate to heavy rain\n",
        "choicethree": "small amounts of CU with generally good visibility\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the colours with which a stationary front is shown on a surface chart?\n",
        "answer": "Red and blue\n",
        "choiceone": "Violet and red\n",
        "choicetwo": "Red and green\n",
        "choicethree": "Blue and violet\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes changes in altitude and/or\nattitude more than two-thirds of the time, with the aircraft remaining in positive control at\nall times?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous severe chop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Intermittent moderate turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What determines the structure or type of clouds which will form as a result of air being\nforced to ascend?\n",
        "answer": "The stability of the air before lifting occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "The method by which the air is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The relative humidity of the air after lifting occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The section of the Aviation Area Forecast (FA) entitled VFR Clouds and Weather\ncontains a summary of\n",
        "answer": "sky condition, cloud heights, visibility, obstructions to vision, precipitation, and\nsustained surface winds of 20 knots or greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "forecast sky cover, cloud tops, visibility, and obstructions to vision along specific\nroutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only those weather systems producing liquid or frozen precipitation, fog,\nthunderstorms, or IFR ceilings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common type of ground or surface based temperature inversion is that which is\n\nproduced by\n",
        "answer": "ground radiation on clear, cool nights when the wind is light.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air being lifted rapidly aloft in the vicinity of mountainous terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the movement of colder air over warm air, or the movement of warm air under cold\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which primary source contains information regarding the expected weather at the\ndestination airport, at the ETA?\n",
        "answer": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low-Level Prog Chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar Summary and Weather Depiction Charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather condition is an example of a nonfrontal instability band?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advective fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frontogenesis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest Flight contol center\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFlight control center broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum weather conditions must be forecast for your ETA at an alternate airport,\nthat has only a VOR approach with standard alternate minimums, for the airport to be\nlisted as an alternate on the IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "800-foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "800-foot ceiling and 1 statute mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000-foot ceiling and visibility to allow descent from minimum en route altitude\n(MEA), approach, and landing under basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes slight, rapid, and somewhat\nrhythmic bumpiness without appreciable changes in attitude or altitude, less than one-\nthird of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wind shear forecast in the following TAF?|TAF|KCVG 231051Z 231212\n12012KT 4SM -RA BR OVC008|/WS005/27050KT TEMPO 1719 1/2SM -RA FG|FM1930\n09012KT 1SM -DZ BR VV003 BECMG 2021 5SM HZ=\n",
        "answer": "500 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the winds at 2,000 feet above the surface and the\nsurface winds?\n",
        "answer": "The winds at 2,000 feet tend to parallel the isobars while the surface winds cross the\nisobars at an angle toward lower pressure and are weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "The winds at 2,000 feet and the surface winds flow in the same direction, but the\nsurface winds are weaker due to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface winds tend to veer to the right of the winds at 2,000 feet and are usually\nweaker.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an effect of ice, snow, or frost formation on an airplane?\n",
        "answer": "Increased stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increased pitchdown tendencies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increased angle of attack for stalls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) of P6SM implies that the\nprevailing visibility is expected to be greater than\n",
        "answer": "6 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 nautical miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 kilometers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying over the top of a severe thunderstorm, the cloud should be overflown by at\nleast\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet for each 10 knots windspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 feet above any moderate to severe turbulence layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absence of the sky condition and visibility on an ATIS broadcast indicates that\n",
        "answer": "the ceiling is at least 5,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "weather conditions are at or above VFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the sky condition is clear and visibility is unrestricted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding ridge soaring with the wind direction perpendicular to the\nridge?\n",
        "answer": "If the glider drifts downwind from the ridge and sinks slightly lower than the crest of\nthe ridge, the glider should be turned away from the ridge and a high speed attained.\n",
        "choiceone": "When very close to the surface of the ridge, the glider's speed should be reduced to\nthe minimum sink speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the wind and lift are very strong on the windward side of the ridge, a weak sink\ncondition will exist on the leeward side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation is advection fog most likely to form?\n",
        "answer": "An air mass moving inland from the coast in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "A light breeze blowing colder air out to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm, moist air settling over a warmer surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 9.) The Severe Weather Outlook Chart depicts\n",
        "answer": "areas of probable severe thunderstorms by the use of single hatched areas on the\nchart.\n",
        "choiceone": "areas of forecast, severe or extreme turbulence, and areas of severe icing for the\nnext 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "areas of general thunderstorm activity (excluding severe) by the use of hatching on\nthe chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather feature occurs at altitude levels near the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "Maximum winds and narrow wind shear zones.\n",
        "choiceone": "Abrupt temperature increase above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thin layers of cirrus (ice crystal) clouds at the tropopause level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What values are used for Winds Aloft Forecasts?\n",
        "answer": "True direction and knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "True direction and MPH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Magnetic direction and knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area forecasts generally include a forecast period of 18 hours and cover a geographical\n",
        "answer": "area the size of several states.\n",
        "choiceone": "terminal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "area less than 3000 square miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by the Special METAR weather observation for KBOI?|SPECI KBOI\n091854Z 32005KT 1 1/2SM RA BR OVC007 17/16 A2990 RMK RAB12\n",
        "answer": "Rain and mist obstructing visibility; rain began at 1812Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rain and fog obscuring two-tenths of the sky; rain began at 1912Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain and overcast at 1200 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFSS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time are current AIRMETs broadcast in their entirety by the Hazardous Inflight\nWeather Advisory Service (HIWAS)?\n",
        "answer": "There is a continuous broadcast over selected VORs of Inflight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 and 45 minutes after the hour during the first hour after issuance, and upon\nreceipt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it momentarily causes slight, erratic\nchanges in altitude andlor attitude, one-third to two-thirds of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Intermittent light turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement pertaining to the following Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) is true?\n|TAF|KMEM 091135Z 0915 15005KT 5SM HZ BKNO60|FM1600 VRBO4KT P6SM SKC\n",
        "answer": "SKC in the valid period indicates no significant weather and sky clear.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind in the valid period implies surface winds are forecast to be greater than 5 KTS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction is from 160__degrees__ at 4 KTS and reported vi\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 152.) What weather conditions are depicted in the area\narrow B on the Radar Summary Chart?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weak to moderate echoes; rain showers increasing in intensity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weak echoes; heavy rain showers; area movement toward the southeast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Strong echoes; moderate rain showers; no cell movement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what localities is advection fog most likely to occur?\n",
        "answer": "Coastal areas.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mountain slopes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Level inland areas.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which family of clouds is least likely to contribute to structural icing on an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "High clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What lifts advection fog into low stratus clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Surface winds of approximately 15 knots or stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nighttime cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dryness of the underlying land mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which forces are balanced in case of geostrophic winds?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure gradient force, Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "Friction force, pressure gradient force, Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure gradient force, Coriolis force, centrifugal force.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pressure gradient force, centrifugal force, friction force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high pressure area (slack pressure gradient) covers part of the Mediterranean Sea and\ncoastal region during the summer. What surface wind direction is likely at an airport at\nthe coast on a sunny afternoon?\n",
        "answer": "Sea to land.\n",
        "choiceone": "Land to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Variable.\n",
        "choicethree": "Parallel to the coastline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When advection fog has developed, what may tend to di\nstratus clouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Wind stronger than 15 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomen:\nCumulonimbus with thunderstorm ?\n\nleast likely to lead to the formation of a\n",
        "answer": "Ground radiation\n",
        "choiceone": "Convection\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convergence\n",
        "choicethree": "Orographic lifting\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special air-report\n",
        "answer": "may trigger a SIGMET message\n",
        "choiceone": "may be the reason for closing an airport due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be the reason for closing a part of an airway due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicethree": "is used to produce better aerodrome forecasts (TAF)\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the stability of the atmosphere be determined?\n",
        "answer": "Ambient temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Atmospheric pressure at various levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface temperature/dewpoint spread.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If clouds form as a result of very stable, moist air being forced to ascend a mountain\nslope, the clouds will be\n",
        "answer": "stratus type with little vertical development and little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "cirrus type with no vertical development or turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cumulus type with considerable vertical development and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What values are used for Winds Aloft Forecasts?\n",
        "answer": "True direction and knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "True direction and MPH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Magnetic direction and knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) The peak wind at KAMA was reported to be from 320 degrees true\nat 39 knots,\n",
        "answer": "which occurred at 1743Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "with gusts to 43 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with .43 of an inch liquid precipitation since the last report.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated by the term \u2018embedded thunderstorms\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are obscured by massive cloud layers and cannot be seen.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms are embedded within a squall line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are predicted to develop in a stable air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are haze layers cleared or dispersed?\n",
        "answer": "By wind or the movement of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "By convective mixing in cool night air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By evaporation similar to the clearing of fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an effect of ice, snow, or frost formation on an airplane?\n",
        "answer": "Increased stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increased pitchdown tendencies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increased angle of attack for stalls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KSPS 131757Z 09014KT 6SM -RA SCT025 OVC090 24/22 A3005.|SPECI KSPS\n131820Z 01025KT 3SM +RA FC OVC015 22/21 A3000.|Which change took place at\nWichita Falls (KSPS) between 1757 and 1820 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "A funnel cloud was observed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rain became lighter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Atmospheric pressure increased.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions result in the formation of frost?\n",
        "answer": "Temperature of the collecting surface is below the dewpoint of surrounding air and\nthe dewpoint is colder than freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature of the collecting surface is at or below freezing and small droplets\nof moisture are falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When dew forms and the temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will an area of thunderstorm activity, that may grow to severe intensity, be\nindicated on the Severe Weather Outlook Chart?\n",
        "answer": "APCHG within any area.\n",
        "choiceone": "SLGT within cross-hatched areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SVR within any area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of center of gravity on the spin characteristics of an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A flat spin may develop if the CG is too far aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the CG is too far forward, spin entry will be difficult.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If the CG is too far aft, spins can become high-speed spirals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) The 12-Hour Significant Weather Prognostic Chart indicates that\neastern Kentucky and eastern Tennessee can expect probable ceilings\n\n",
        "answer": "less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles, and moderate turbulence\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles, and moderate turbulence\nabove 10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFSS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can wind shear associated with a thunderstorm be found? Choose the most\ncomplete answer.\n",
        "answer": "On all sides of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the right side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In front of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of weather can one expect from moist, unstable air, and very warm surface\ntemperatures?\n",
        "answer": "Strong updrafts and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fog and low stratus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous heavy precipitation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of either predominantly stratiform or predominantly cumuliform clouds is\ndependent upon the\n",
        "answer": "stability of the air being lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature of the air being lifted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steady precipitation, in contrast to showers, preceding a front is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "stratiform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratiform clouds with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cummuliform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of standing lenticular altocumulus clouds is a good indication of\n",
        "answer": "very strong turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "lenticular ice formatiot\n",
        "choicetwo": "heavy icing conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type precipitation is an indication that supercooled water is present?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wet snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ice pellets.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what localities is advection fog most likely to occur?\n",
        "answer": "Coastal areas.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mountain slopes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Level inland areas.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most midair colli\n\n",
        "answer": "clear days.\n",
        "choiceone": "hazy days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cloudy nights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moisture is added to a parcel of air by\n",
        "answer": "evaporation and sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "sublimation and condensation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evaporation and condensation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are indicated on a Weather Depiction Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Actual sky cover, visibility restrictions, and type of precipitation at reporting stations.\n",
        "choiceone": "Forecast ceilings and visibilities over a large geographic area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Actual en route weather conditions between reporting stations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapor which air can hold largely depends on\n",
        "answer": "air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability of air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant Pressure Analysis Charts contain contours, isotherms and some con\nisotachs. The contours depict\n",
        "answer": "ridges, lows, troughs and highs aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges on the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges corrected to MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A clear area in a line of thunderstorm echoes on a radar scope indicates\n",
        "answer": "an area where precipitation drops are not detected.\n",
        "choiceone": "the absence of clouds in the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area of no convective turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "Itis an atmospheric condition that may be associated with a low-level temperature\ninversion, a jet stream, or a frontal zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis an atmospheric condition that is associated exclusively with zones of\nconvergence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Coriolis phenomenon in both high- and low-level air masses is the principal\ngenerating force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which layer is most of the atmospheric humidity concentrated ?\n",
        "answer": "Troposphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratopause.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning an isothermal layer in the atmosphere\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "An isothermal layer is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air parcels that are forced to rise through an isothermal layer keep the same\ntemperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The vertical temperature gradient lies between the dry and saturated adiabatic lapse\nrates.\n",
        "choicethree": "An isothermal layer is formed when the air in the layer is well mixed by turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10722A)\nAssuming a generalised zonal system of world climatic and wind circulation, zone \"\nan area of\n\n",
        "answer": "subtropical high pressure systems\n",
        "choiceone": "SE trade winds\n",
        "choicetwo": "travelling low pressure systems\n",
        "choicethree": "NE trade winds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high pressure area (slack pressure gradient) covers part of the Mediterranean Sea and\ncoastal region during the summer. What surface wind direction is likely at an airport at\nthe coast on a sunny afternoon?\n",
        "answer": "Sea to land.\n",
        "choiceone": "Land to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Variable.\n",
        "choicethree": "Parallel to the coastline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sea breeze is a wind\n",
        "answer": "occurring only in the lower layers of the atmosphere in daytime\n",
        "choiceone": "that reaches up to the tropopause in daytime\n",
        "choicetwo": "blowing at night in mid-latitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "occurring only in mid-latitudes and in daytime\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When advection fog has developed, what may tend to di\nstratus clouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Wind stronger than 15 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parcel of unsaturated air is forced to rise through an isothermal layer. So long a\nremains unsaturated, the temperature of the parcel\n\n",
        "answer": "decreases 1\u00b0C per 100m\n",
        "choiceone": "remains constant\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases 0.65\u00b0C per 100m\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes equal to the temperature of the isothermal layer\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main factor which contributes to the formation of very low clouds ahead of a warm\nfrontis the\n",
        "answer": "saturation of the cold air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choiceone": "saturation of the warm air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduction of outgoing radiation due to clouds\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air moving over a cold surface\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical zero degree isotherm is\n",
        "answer": "16000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "12000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "19000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 9.) The Severe Weather Outlook Chart depicts\n",
        "answer": "areas of probable severe thunderstorms by the use of single hatched areas on the\nchart.\n",
        "choiceone": "areas of forecast, severe or extreme turbulence, and areas of severe icing for the\nnext 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "areas of general thunderstorm activity (excluding severe) by the use of hatching on\nthe chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time are current AIRMETs broadcast in their entirety by the Hazardous Inflight\nWeather Advisory Service (HIWAS)?\n",
        "answer": "There is a continuous broadcast over selected VORs of Inflight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 and 45 minutes after the hour during the first hour after issuance, and upon\nreceipt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather chart depicts conditions forecast to exist at a specific time in the future?\n",
        "answer": "12-Hour Significant Weather Prognostication Chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing Level Chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Weather Depiction Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following combinations of weather producing variables would likely result\ncumuliform-type clouds, good visibility, rain showers, and possible clear-type icing in\nclouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Unstable, moist air, and orographic lifting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Unstable, moist air, and no lifting mechanism.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stable, dry air, and orographic lifting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During departure, under conditions of suspected low-level wind shear, a sudden\ndecrease in headwind will cause\n",
        "answer": "a loss in airspeed equal to the decrease in wind velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "a gain in airspeed equal to the decrease in wind velocity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "no change in airspeed, but groundspeed will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect does haze have on the ability to see traffic or terrain features during flight?\n",
        "answer": "All traffic or terrain features appear to be farther away than their actual distance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Haze causes the eyes to focus at infinity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The eyes tend to overwork in haze and do not detect relative movement easily.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding ridge soaring with the wind direction perpendicular to the\nridge?\n",
        "answer": "If the glider drifts downwind from the ridge and sinks slightly lower than the crest of\nthe ridge, the glider should be turned away from the ridge and a high speed attained.\n",
        "choiceone": "When very close to the surface of the ridge, the glider's speed should be reduced to\nthe minimum sink speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the wind and lift are very strong on the windward side of the ridge, a weak sink\ncondition will exist on the leeward side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What weather improvement was reported at Lubbock (KLBB)\nbetween 1750 and 1818 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "The vertical visibility improved by 2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "The wind shift and frontal passage at 1812Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature and dewpoint spread improved.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) The chart symbols over southern California on the 12-Hour\n\nSignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicate\n",
        "answer": "pected top of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u2018pected base of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "light turbulence expected above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A clear area in a line of thunderstorm echoes on a radar scope indicates\n",
        "answer": "an area where precipitation drops are not detected.\n",
        "choiceone": "the absence of clouds in the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area of no convective turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "icated on the Weather Depiction Chart by a continuous smooth line\nenclosing a hatched geographic area?\n",
        "answer": "Reporting stations within the enclosed area are all showing IFR conditions at the\ntime of the report.\n",
        "choiceone": "The entire area has ceilings less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 50 percent of the area enclosed by the smooth line is predicted to have\nIFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the contraction VRB in the Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) mean?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction is variable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed is variable throughout the period.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloud base is variable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If airborne radar is indicating an extremely intense thunderstorm echo, tl\nthunderstorm should be avoided by a distance of at least\n",
        "answer": "20 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in the\ncircle 6 area?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which response most closely interprets the following PIREP?|UA/OV OKC 063064/TM\n1522/FLO80/TP C172/TA -04/WV 245040/TB LGT/RM IN CLR\n",
        "answer": "64 nautical miles on the 63 degrees radial from Oklahoma City VOR at 1522 UTC,\nflight level 8,000 ft. Type of aircraft is a Cessna 172.\n",
        "choiceone": "Reported by a Cessna 172, turbulence and light rime icing in climb to 8,000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "63 nautical miles on the 64 degrees radial from Oklahoma City, thunderstorm and\nlight rain at 1522 UTC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is frost considered hazardous to flight operation?\n",
        "answer": "Frost causes early airflow separation resulting in a loss of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost changes the basic aerodynamic shape of the airfoil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frost decreases control effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes slight, rapid, and somewhat\nrhythmic bumpiness without appreciable changes in attitude or altitude, less than one-\nthird of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type clouds can be expected when an unstable air mass is forced to ascend a\nmountain slope?\n",
        "answer": "Clouds with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Layered clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratified clouds with considerable associated turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is false lift dangerous?\n",
        "answer": "When the balloon's horizontal speed reaches wind speed, the balloon could\ndescend into obstructions downwind.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots are not aware of its effect until the burner sound changes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To commence a descent, the venting of air will nearly collapse the envelope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can wind shear associated with a thunderstorm be found? Choose the most\ncomplete answer.\n",
        "answer": "On all sides of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the right side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In front of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true concerning the hazards of hail?\n",
        "answer": "Hailstones may be encountered in clear air several miles from a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Hail damage in horizontal flight is minimal due to the vertical movement of hail in the\nclouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain at the surface is a reliable indication of no hail aloft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Summer thunderstorms in the arctic region will generally move\n",
        "answer": "northeast to southwest in polar easterlies.\n",
        "choiceone": "southwest to northeast with the jetstream flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "directly north to south with the low-level polar airflow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of jetstream can be expected to cause the greater turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "A curving jetstream associated with a deep low-pressure trough.\n",
        "choiceone": "A straight jetstream associated with a low-pressure trough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A jetstream occurring during the summer at the lower latitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area forecasts generally include a forecast period of 18 hours and cover a geographical\n",
        "answer": "area the size of several states.\n",
        "choiceone": "terminal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "area less than 3000 square miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ice pellets encountered during flight are normally evidence that\n",
        "answer": "freezing rain exists at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement pertaining to the life cycle of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "answer": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the mature stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Updrafts continue to develop throughout the dissipating stage of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the dissipating stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the winds at 2,000 feet above the surface and the\nsurface winds?\n",
        "answer": "The winds at 2,000 feet tend to parallel the isobars while the surface winds cross the\nisobars at an angle toward lower pressure and are weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "The winds at 2,000 feet and the surface winds flow in the same direction, but the\nsurface winds are weaker due to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface winds tend to veer to the right of the winds at 2,000 feet and are usually\nweaker.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Developing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4248A)\nAn aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the\npressure surface of the constant pressure chart. Which of the following statements is\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over A\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher over A than over B\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed over Madrid is higher than over A\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind speed over B is higher than over A\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing fog consists of\n",
        "answer": "supercooled water droplets\n",
        "choiceone": "frozen water droplets\n",
        "choicetwo": "frozen minute snow flakes\n",
        "choicethree": "ice crystals\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favours the development of orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "High relative humidity\n",
        "choiceone": "Absolutely unstable air\n",
        "choicetwo": "Katabatic winds\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear nights\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass which originates over the North Atlantic between 50 and 70 degrees north\nand is moving in over Scandinavia is called\n",
        "answer": "maritime polar air.\n",
        "choiceone": "continental arctic air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maritime arctic air.\n",
        "choicethree": "continental polar air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf a temperature inversion is encountered immediately after takeoff or during an\napproach to a landing, a potential hazard exists due to\n",
        "answer": "wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong surface winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong convective currents.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the cumulus stage of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Roll cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Beginning of rain at the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "It may be associated with either a wind shift or a wind speed gradient at any level in\nthe atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is primarily associated with the lateral vortices generated by thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It usually exists only in the vicinity of thunderstorms, but may be found near a strong\ntemperature inversion.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the wind-group at one of the forecast altitudes omitted at a specific location or\nstation in the Winds and Temperatures Aloft Forecast (FD)? When the wind\n\n",
        "answer": "at the altitude is within 1,500 feet of the station elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "is less than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is less than 10 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which arctic flying hazard is caused when a cloud layer of uniform thickness overlies a\n\nsnow or ice covered surface?\n",
        "answer": "Whiteout.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ice fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Blowing snow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes slight, rapid, and somewhat\nrhythmic bumpiness without appreciable changes in attitude or altitude, less than one-\nthird of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the air temperature is +8 degrees C at an elevation of 1,350 feet and a standard\n(average) temperature lapse rate exists, what will be the approximate freezing level?\n",
        "answer": "5,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) A planned low-altitude flight from central Oklahoma to western\nTennessee at 12002 is likely to encounter\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery rain over half or more of the area, moderate turbulence, and\nfreezing temperatures above 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous or intermittent rain or rain showers, moderate turbulence, and freezing\ntemperatures below 8,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "showery precipitation covering less than half the area, no turbulence below 18,000\nfeet, and freezing temperatures above 12,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Behind a stationary front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During preflight preparation, weather report forecasts which are not routinely available\nat the local service outlet can best be obtained by means of contacting the\n",
        "answer": "weather forecast office (WFD).\n",
        "choiceone": "air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot's automatic telephone answering service.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the stability of the atmosphere be determined?\n",
        "answer": "Ambient temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Atmospheric pressure at various levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface temperature/dewpoint spread.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The low-level wind shear Alert System (LLWAS) provides wind data and software\nprocess to detect the presence of a\n",
        "answer": "change in wind direction and/or speed within a very short distance above the airport\n",
        "choiceone": "rotating column of air extending from a cumulonimbus cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downward motion of the air associated with continuous winds blowing with an\neasterly component due to the rotation of the Earth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most frequent type of ground- or surface-based temperature inversion is that\n\nproduced by\n",
        "answer": "radiation on a clear, relatively still night.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air being lifted rapidly aloft in the vicinity of mountainous terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the movement of colder air under warm air, or the movement of warm air over cold\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station originating the following METAR observation has a field elevation of 3,500\nfeet MSL. If the sky cover is one continuous layer, what is the thickness of the cloud\nlayer? (Top of overcast reported at 7,500 feet MSL).|METAR KHOB 151250Z 17006KT\n4SM OVCO05 13/11 A2998\n",
        "answer": "3,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation is advection fog most likely to form?\n",
        "answer": "An air mass moving inland from the coast in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "A light breeze blowing colder air out to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm, moist air settling over a warmer surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type cloud is associated with violent turbulence and a tendency toward the\nproduction of funnel clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus mamma.\n",
        "choiceone": "Standing lenticular.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition produces weather on the lee side of a large lake?\n",
        "answer": "Warm air flowing over a colder lake may produce fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air flowing over a warmer lake may produce advection fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm air flowing over a cool lake may produce rain showers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Dallas (KDAL)?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter setting is 30.07.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tops of the overcast is 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature/dewpoint spread is 8 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are characteristics of a cold air mass moving over a warm surface?\n",
        "answer": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds, smooth air, and poor visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which correctly describes the purpose of convective SIGMETs (WST)?\n",
        "answer": "They consist of either an observation and a forecast or just a forecast for tornadoes,\nsignificant thunderstorm activity, or hail greater than or equal to 3/4 inch in diameter.\n",
        "choiceone": "They consist of an hourly observation of tornadoes, significant thunderstorm\nactivity, and large hailstone activity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They contain both an observation and a forecast of all thunderstorm and hailstone\nactivity. The forecast is valid for 1 hour only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What lifts advection fog into low stratus clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Surface winds of approximately 15 knots or stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nighttime cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dryness of the underlying land mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for a VFR-on-Top flight at 9,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) during daylight\nhours for the circle 3 area?\n",
        "answer": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (F) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet; (E) 1,000 feet; (F) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (F) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fog produced by frontal activity is a result of saturation due to\n",
        "answer": "evaporation of precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "nocturnal cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "adiabatic cooling.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective circulation patterns associated with sea breezes are caused by\n",
        "answer": "land absorbing and radiating heat faster than the water.\n",
        "choiceone": "water absorbing and radiating heat faster than the land.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cool and less dense air moving inland from over the water, causing it to rise.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are severe weather watch bulletins (WW) issued?\n",
        "answer": "Unscheduled and issued as required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 12 hours as required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 24 hours as required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 150.) The Weather Depiction Chart indicates that the coastal sections of\nTexas and Louisiana are reporting\n",
        "answer": "VFR conditions with scattered clouds at 3,200 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "all ceilings at or above 20,000 feet with visibilities of 20 miles or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "marginal VFR conditions due to broken ceilings of 3,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sudden penetration of fog can create the illusion of\n",
        "answer": "pitching up.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitching down.\n",
        "choicetwo": "leveling off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What situation is most conducive to the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Warm, moist air over low, flatland areas on clear, calm nights.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist, tropical air moving over cold, offshore water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The movement of cold air over much warmer water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the QFE at a position (200 metres above sea level) is 980 hPa, whatis the approximate\nQNH ?\n",
        "answer": "1005 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1015 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "1010 hPa\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most severe weather conditions, such as destructive winds, heavy hail, and\ntornadoes, are generally associated with\n",
        "answer": "squall lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "slow-moving warm fronts which slope above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fast-moving occluded fronts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The vertical extent of the friction layer depends primarily on\n",
        "answer": "stability, wind speed, roughness of surface\n",
        "choiceone": "wind speed, roughness of surface, temperature\n",
        "choicetwo": "roughness of surface, temperature, local time\n",
        "choicethree": "temperature, local time, environmental lapse rate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of ice pellets at the surface is the evidence that:\n",
        "answer": "temperatures are above freezing at some higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "choicethree": "after take-off you can climb to a higher altitude without encountering more than light\nicing conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of front / occlusion usually moves the fastest?\n",
        "answer": "Cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold occlusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "Warm occlusion.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4314A)\nContinuous freezing rain is observed at an airfield.\n\nWhich of the four diagrams is most likely to reflect temperatures above the airfield\nconcerned?\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 1\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clear ice is dangerous because it\n",
        "answer": "is heavy and is difficult to remove from the aircraft surfaces\n",
        "choiceone": "is translucent and only forms at the leading edges\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not translucent and forms at the leading edges\n",
        "choicethree": "spreads out and contains many air particles\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interprete this METAR ?\n\n00000KT 0200 R14/0800U R16/P1500U FZFG VV001 m03/m03 Q1022 BECMG 0800=\n",
        "answer": "RVR for runway 14 800 metres, vertical visibility 100 feet, calm, visibility improving to\n800 metres in the next 2 hours\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 200 metres, RVR for runway 16 1500 metres, temperature -3\u00b0C, vertical\nvisibility 100 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 200 feet, RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres, vertical visibility 100\nfeet, fog with hoar frost\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility for runway 14 800 metres, fog with hoar frost, RVR for runway 16 more than\n1500 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud types would indicate convective turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nimbostratus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Standing lenticular clouds, in mountainous areas, indicate\n",
        "answer": "turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "an inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it momentarily causes slight, erratic\nchanges in altitude andlor attitude, one-third to two-thirds of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Intermittent light turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest cloud in the stationary group associated with a mountain wave?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "Standing lenticular.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low stratus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reporting station originating this Aviation Routine Weather Report has a field\nelevation of 620 feet. If the reported sky cover is one continuous layer, what is its\nthickness? (tops of OVC are reported at 6500 feet)|METAR KMDW 121856Z AUTO\n32005KT 1 1/2SM +RABR OVCO07 17/16 A2980\n",
        "answer": "5,180 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5,800 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,880 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAF) are issued how many times a day and cover what\nperiod of time?\n",
        "answer": "Four times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period.\n",
        "choiceone": "Six times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period including a 4-hour\ncategorical outlook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four times daily and are valid for 12 hours including a 6-hour categorical outlook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the pilot obtain TWEB Route Forecast information?\n",
        "answer": "From the TEL TWEB and radio broadcasts.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the ATIS and Pilots Automatic Telephone Weather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From ARTCC and Automated Flight Service Station briefings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an STL MEM MSY\nflight at FL 330?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind shift from west to north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature increase 5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From which measurement of the atmosphere can stability be determined?\n",
        "answer": "The ambient lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding high- or low-pressure systems?\n",
        "answer": "A low-pressure area or trough is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Both high- and low-pressure areas are characterized by descending air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of either predominantly stratiform or predominantly cumuliform clouds is\ndependent upon the\n",
        "answer": "stability of the air being lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature of the air being lifted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an effect of ice, snow, or frost formation on an airplane?\n",
        "answer": "Increased stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increased pitchdown tendencies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increased angle of attack for stalls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "Itis an atmospheric condition that may be associated with a low-level temperature\ninversion, a jet stream, or a frontal zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis an atmospheric condition that is associated exclusively with zones of\nconvergence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Coriolis phenomenon in both high- and low-level air masses is the principal\ngenerating force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What causes surface winds to flow across the isobars at an angle rather than parallel to\nthe isobars?\n",
        "answer": "Surface friction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The greater density of the air at the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 154.) What is the height of the 300-millibar level at the low pressure?\n",
        "answer": "9,120 meters MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 meters MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11,850 meters MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions result in the formation of frost?\n",
        "answer": "Temperature of the collecting surface is below the dewpoint of surrounding air and\nthe dewpoint is colder than freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature of the collecting surface is at or below freezing and small droplets\nof moisture are falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When dew forms and the temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an indication that downdrafts have developed and the thunderstorm cell has\nentered the mature stage?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation begins to fall from the cloud base.\n",
        "choiceone": "The anvil top has completed its development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gust front forms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The section of the Aviation Area Forecast (FA) entitled VFR Clouds and Weather\ncontains a summary of\n",
        "answer": "sky condition, cloud heights, visibility, obstructions to vision, precipitation, and\nsustained surface winds of 20 knots or greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "forecast sky cover, cloud tops, visibility, and obstructions to vision along specific\nroutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only those weather systems producing liquid or frozen precipitation, fog,\nthunderstorms, or IFR ceilings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KHRO 131753Z 09007KT 7SM FEW020 BKN040 30/27 A3001.|SPECI KHRO-\n131815Z 13017G26KT 3SM +TSRA SCT020 BKNO45TCU 29/24 A2983 RMK|RAB12 WS:\nTKO LDG RW14R FRQ LTGICCG VC.|What change has taken place between 1753 and\n1815 UTC at Harrison (KHRO)?\n",
        "answer": "Thundershowers began at 12 minutes past the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling lowered and cumulonimbus clouds developed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility reduced to IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hazardous Inflight Weather Advisory Service (HIWAS) is a broadcast service over\nselected VORs that provides\n",
        "answer": "continuous broadcast of inflight weather advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "SIGMETs and AIRMETs at 15 minutes and 45 minutes past the hour for the first hour\nafter issuance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SIGMETs, CONVECTIVE SIGMETs and AIRMETs at 15 minutes and 45 minutes past\nthe hour.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapor which air can hold largely depends on\n",
        "answer": "air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability of air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four families of clouds?\n",
        "answer": "High, middle, low, and those with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus, cumulus, nimbus, and cirrus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds formed by updrafts, fronts, cooling layers of air, and precipitation into warm\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather condition is an example of a nonfrontal instability band?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advective fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frontogenesis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather is predicted by the term VCTS in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are expected in the vicinity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thunderstorms may occur over the station and within 50 miles of the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are expected between 5 and 25 miles of the runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix 'nimbus\u2019, used in naming clouds, means a\n",
        "answer": "rain cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "cloud with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dark massive, towering cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moisture is added to a parcel of air by\n",
        "answer": "evaporation and sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "sublimation and condensation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evaporation and condensation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A PROB40 (PROBability) HHhh group in an International Terminal Aerodrome Forecast\n(TAF) indicates the probability of\n\n",
        "answer": "thunderstorms or other precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "precipitation or low visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "thunderstorms or high wind.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an area of converging\n\n",
        "answer": "clouds can be formed\n",
        "choiceone": "convective clouds can be dissolved\n",
        "choicetwo": "stratified clouds can be dissolved\n",
        "choicethree": "clouds can not be formed\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For both saturated and unsaturated air instability will occur when the\n",
        "answer": "environmental lapse rate is greater than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choiceone": "environmental lapse rate is greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but less than\ndry adiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicetwo": "environmental lapse rate is less than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicethree": "dry adiabatic lapse rate is less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but greater than\nenvironmental lapse rate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are medium level clouds ?\n",
        "answer": "Altostratus and altocumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrocumulus and cirrostratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulonimbus\n",
        "choicethree": "All convective clouds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of morning fog before sunrise is possible if\n",
        "answer": "air temperature and dew point are equal or close to one another\n",
        "choiceone": "the wind is strong\n",
        "choicetwo": "the sky is overcast\n",
        "choicethree": "the turbulence in the lower layers is moderate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms suddenly by day but not by night\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is formed when the air is unstable\n",
        "choicethree": "It develops slowly and dissipates rapidly\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main factor which contributes to the formation of very low clouds ahead of a warm\nfrontis the\n",
        "answer": "saturation of the cold air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choiceone": "saturation of the warm air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduction of outgoing radiation due to clouds\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air moving over a cold surface\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical zero degree isotherm is\n",
        "answer": "16000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "12000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "19000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10798A)\nThe dotted line labelled \"Y\" represents the\n",
        "answer": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone during January\n",
        "choiceone": "axis of the subtropical jet stream during January\n",
        "choicetwo": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone during July\n",
        "choicethree": "axis of the equatorial jet stream during July\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud types would indicate convective turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nimbostratus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vertical wind shear can be determined directly from the dashed lines on the tropopause\ndata chart. The vertical wind shear that is critical for probability of turbulence is\n",
        "answer": "6 knots or more per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 knots or greater per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater than 8 knots per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are haze layers cleared or dispersed?\n",
        "answer": "By wind or the movement of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "By convective mixing in cool night air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By evaporation similar to the clearing of fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection fog has drifted over a coastal airport during the day. What may tend to\ndissipate or lift this fog into low stratus clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Wind 15 knots or stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nighttime cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unsaturated air flowing up slope will cool at the rate of approximately (dry adiabatic\nlapse rate)\n",
        "answer": "3 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fog is usually prevalent in industrial areas because of\n",
        "answer": "an abundance of condensation nuclei from combustion products.\n",
        "choiceone": "atmospheric stabilization around cities.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased temperatures due to industrial heating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SPECI KGLS 131802Z 10012G21KT 060V140 2SM +SHRA SCT005 BKN035 OVC050CB\n24/23 A2980 RMK RAB\u00a77 WS TKO RWOSL WSHFT 58 FROPA. This SPECI report at\nGalveston (KGLS) indicates which condition?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation started at 57 after the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind steady at 100 degree magnetic at 12 knots, gusts to 21.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet overcast with towering cumulus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When preparing for an autotow with a strong crosswind, where should the glider and\ntowrope be positioned?\n",
        "answer": "Obliquely to the line of takeoff on the downwind side of the tow vehicle.\n",
        "choiceone": "Obliquely to the line of takeoff on the upwind side of the tow vehicle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Directly behind the tow vehicle and crabbed into the wind with the wing runner\nholding the upwind wingtip.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What type of report is listed for Lubbock (KLBB) at 18182?\n",
        "answer": "A Special METAR weather observation, concerning significant weather changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "An Aviation selected special weather report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A special report concerning very low station pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KSPS 131757Z 09014KT 6SM -RA SCT025 OVC090 24/22 A3005.|SPECI KSPS\n131820Z 01025KT 3SM +RA FC OVC015 22/21 A3000.|Which change took place at\nWichita Falls (KSPS) between 1757 and 1820 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "A funnel cloud was observed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rain became lighter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Atmospheric pressure increased.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which primary source should be used to obtain forecast weather information at your\ndestination for the planned ETA?\n",
        "answer": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF).\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar Summary and Weather Depiction Charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which meteorological condition does the term \u2018dew point' refer?\n",
        "answer": "The temperature to which air must be cooled to become saturated.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature at which condensation and evaporation are equal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature at which dew will always form.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is most appropriate when an envelope over-temperature condition occurs?\n",
        "answer": "Land as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and allow envelope to cool before landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Throw all unnecessary equipment overboard in order to lighten the load.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather difference is found on each side of a \u2018dry line\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Dewpoint difference.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extreme temperature difference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratus versus cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To best determine observed weather conditions between weather reporting stations,\nthe pilot should refer to\n",
        "answer": "pilot reports.\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prognostic charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which event usually occurs after an aircraft passes through a front into the colder air?\n",
        "answer": "Atmospheric pressure increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature/dewpoint spread decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction shifts to the left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A PROB40 (PROBability) HHhh group in an International Terminal Aerodrome Forecast\n(TAF) indicates the probability of\n\n",
        "answer": "thunderstorms or other precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "precipitation or low visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "thunderstorms or high wind.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "temperature is forecast, one can expect what type of weather?\n",
        "answer": "Strong updrafts and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong updrafts and stratonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Restricted visibility near the surface over a large area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes slight, rapid, and somewhat\nrhythmic bumpiness without appreciable changes in attitude or altitude, less than one-\nthird of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absence of the sky condition and visibility on an ATIS broadcast specifically\nthat\n\n",
        "answer": "the ceiling is more than 5,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sky condition is clear and visibility is unrestricted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the ceiling is at least 3,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest Flight contol center\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFlight control center broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The body of a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) covers a geographical proximity\nwithin a\n",
        "answer": "5 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 nautical mile radius of the center of an airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 to 10 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 6.) At the soundings taken at 1400 hours, is the atmosphere stable or\nunstable and at what altitudes?\n",
        "answer": "Stable from 10,000 to 13,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stable from 6,000 to 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Unstable from 10,000 to 13,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of either predominantly stratiform or predominantly cumuliform clouds is\ndependent upon the\n",
        "answer": "stability of the air being lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature of the air being lifted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The section of the Aviation Area Forecast (FA) entitled VFR Clouds and Weather\ncontains a summary of\n",
        "answer": "sky condition, cloud heights, visibility, obstructions to vision, precipitation, and\nsustained surface winds of 20 knots or greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "forecast sky cover, cloud tops, visibility, and obstructions to vision along specific\nroutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only those weather systems producing liquid or frozen precipitation, fog,\nthunderstorms, or IFR ceilings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wind shear forecast in the following TAF?|TAF|KCVG 231051Z 231212\n12012KT 4SM -RA BR OVC008|/WS005/27050KT TEMPO 1719 1/2SM -RA FG|FM1930\n09012KT 1SM -DZ BR VV003 BECMG 2021 5SM HZ=\n",
        "answer": "500 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather condition is an example of a nonfrontal instability band?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advective fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frontogenesis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFF at an airfield in a location 69 metres below sea level is 1030 hPa. The air\ntemperature is 10\u00b0C lower than a standard atmosphere.\n\nDescribe the QNH?\n",
        "answer": "More than 1030 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "Less than 1030 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1030 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an adiabatic process\n",
        "answer": "heat is neither added nor lost\n",
        "choiceone": "heat is added\n",
        "choicetwo": "heat is lost\n",
        "choicethree": "the temperature does not change\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For both saturated and unsaturated air instability will occur when the\n",
        "answer": "environmental lapse rate is greater than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choiceone": "environmental lapse rate is greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but less than\ndry adiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicetwo": "environmental lapse rate is less than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicethree": "dry adiabatic lapse rate is less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but greater than\nenvironmental lapse rate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomen:\nCumulonimbus with thunderstorm ?\n\nleast likely to lead to the formation of a\n",
        "answer": "Ground radiation\n",
        "choiceone": "Convection\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convergence\n",
        "choicethree": "Orographic lifting\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favours the development of orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "High relative humidity\n",
        "choiceone": "Absolutely unstable air\n",
        "choicetwo": "Katabatic winds\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear nights\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special air-report\n",
        "answer": "may trigger a SIGMET message\n",
        "choiceone": "may be the reason for closing an airport due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be the reason for closing a part of an airway due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicethree": "is used to produce better aerodrome forecasts (TAF)\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum altitude an airship can reach under any given atmospheric condition and\nreturn safely to the surface is determined by\n",
        "answer": "ballonet capacity.\n",
        "choiceone": "the disposable weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ballonet capacity and disposable weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What values are used for Winds Aloft Forecasts?\n",
        "answer": "True direction and knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "True direction and MPH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Magnetic direction and knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The remarks section of the Aviation Routine Weather Report (METAR) contains the\nfollowing coded information. What does it mean?/|RMK FZDZB42 WSHFT 30 FROPA\n",
        "answer": "Wind shift at three zero due to frontal passage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing drizzle with cloud bases below 4,200 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Freezing drizzle below 4,200 feet and wind shear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is a body of air that\n",
        "answer": "covers an extensive area and has fairly uniform properties of temperature and\nmoisture.\n",
        "choiceone": "has similar cloud formations associated with it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "creates a wind shift as it moves across the Earth's surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in the\ncircle 6 area?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement concerning thermals.\n",
        "answer": "Strong thermals have proportionately increased sink in the air between them.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thermals are unaffected by winds aloft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A thermal invariably remains directly above the surface area from which it\ndeveloped.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf a temperature inversion is encountered immediately after takeoff or during an\napproach to a landing, a potential hazard exists due to\n",
        "answer": "wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong surface winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong convective currents.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "icated on the Weather Depiction Chart by a continuous smooth line\nenclosing a hatched geographic area?\n",
        "answer": "Reporting stations within the enclosed area are all showing IFR conditions at the\ntime of the report.\n",
        "choiceone": "The entire area has ceilings less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 50 percent of the area enclosed by the smooth line is predicted to have\nIFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What flight planning information can a pilot derive from constant pressure charts?\n",
        "answer": "Winds and temperatures aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clear air turbulence and icing conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Levels of widespread cloud coverage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is associated with a temperature inversion?\n",
        "answer": "A stable layer of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "An unstable layer of air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low-level wind shear may occur when\n",
        "answer": "there is a low-level temperature inversion with strong winds above the inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "surface winds are light and variable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "surface winds are above 15 knots and there is no change in wind direction and\nwindspeed with height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Surface Analysis Chart depicts\n",
        "answer": "actual frontal positions, pressure patterns, temperature, dewpoint, wind, weather,\nand obstructions to vision at the valid time of the chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "frontal locations and expected movement, pressure centers, cloud coverage, and\nobstructions to vision at the time of chart transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "actual pressure distribution, frontal systems, cloud heights and coverage,\ntemperature, dewpoint, and wind at the time shown on the chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative\nto ISA) are expected for a flight over OKC at FL 370?\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees true; 27 knots; ISA +6 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "265 degrees true; 27 knots; ISA +1 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 27 knots; ISA +10 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high cloud is composed mostly of\n",
        "answer": "ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "ozone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "condensation nuclei.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which in-flight hazard is most commonly associated with warm fronts?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation-induced fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advection fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radiation fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for a DEN ICT OKC\nflight at 11,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed increase slightly.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind shift from calm to a westerly direction.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 74.) What CAS should be used to maintain the filed TAS at the flight\nplanned altitude if the outside air temperature is +5 degrees C?\n",
        "answer": "133 KCAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "129 KCAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "139 KCAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which meteorological conditions can frontal waves and low pressure areas form?\n",
        "answer": "Slow-moving cold fronts or stationary fronts.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm fronts or occluded fronts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold front occlusions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strong wind shear can be expected\n",
        "answer": "on the low-pressure side of a jetstream core where the speed at the core is stronger\nthan 110 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "in the jetstream front above a core having a speed of 60 to 90 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the 5 degrees C isotherms are spaced between 7 degrees to 10 degrees of latitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What type of report is listed for Lubbock (KLBB) at 18182?\n",
        "answer": "A Special METAR weather observation, concerning significant weather changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "An Aviation selected special weather report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A special report concerning very low station pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) The chart symbols over southern California on the 12-Hour\n\nSignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicate\n",
        "answer": "pected top of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u2018pected base of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "light turbulence expected above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum forecast period for AIRMETs?\n",
        "answer": "Six hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is frost considered hazardous to flight operation?\n",
        "answer": "Frost causes early airflow separation resulting in a loss of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost changes the basic aerodynamic shape of the airfoil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frost decreases control effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type precipitation is an indication that supercooled water is present?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wet snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ice pellets.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thunderstorms generally produce the most severe conditions, such as heavy hi\nand destructive winds?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapor which air can hold largely depends on\n",
        "answer": "air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability of air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most severe weather conditions, such as destructive winds, heavy hail, and\ntornadoes, are generally associated with\n",
        "answer": "squall lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "slow-moving warm fronts which slope above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fast-moving occluded fronts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under anticyclone conditions in the northern hemisphere, with curved isobars the\nspeed of the gradient wind is\n",
        "answer": "greater than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choiceone": "less than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as the thermal component\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional only to the Coriolis force\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer in which the temperature remains constant with height is\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally unstable\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dry adiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "answer": "has a constant fixed value\n",
        "choiceone": "is greater in summer than in winter\n",
        "choicetwo": "is greater during the night than during the day\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases with increasing temperature\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10759A)\nThe cloud type most applicable to square 2D is\n",
        "answer": "AS\n",
        "choiceone": "CU\n",
        "choicetwo": "cB\n",
        "choicethree": "cs\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main factor which contributes to the formation of very low clouds ahead of a warm\nfrontis the\n",
        "answer": "saturation of the cold air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choiceone": "saturation of the warm air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduction of outgoing radiation due to clouds\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air moving over a cold surface\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Subsidence is:\n",
        "answer": "a downward air flow\n",
        "choiceone": "a horizontal air flow\n",
        "choicetwo": "an upward air flow\n",
        "choicethree": "the same as convection\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most tornadoes have a speed of movement that usually ranges from\n",
        "answer": "20 to 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "100 to 140 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 to 70 knots.\n",
        "choicethree": "120 to 180 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cloud base, reported in the METAR, is the height above\n",
        "answer": "airfield level\n",
        "choiceone": "mean sea level\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pressure altitude of the observation station at the time of observation\n",
        "choicethree": "the highest terrain within a radius of 8 km from the observation station\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special air-report\n",
        "answer": "may trigger a SIGMET message\n",
        "choiceone": "may be the reason for closing an airport due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be the reason for closing a part of an airway due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicethree": "is used to produce better aerodrome forecasts (TAF)\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMET information is issued as a warning for significant weather to\n",
        "answer": "all aircraft\n",
        "choiceone": "light aircraft only\n",
        "choicetwo": "VFR operations only\n",
        "choicethree": "heavy aircraft only\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection fog has drifted over a coastal airport during the day. What may tend to\ndissipate or lift this fog into low stratus clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Wind 15 knots or stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nighttime cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 9.) The Severe Weather Outlook Chart depicts\n",
        "answer": "areas of probable severe thunderstorms by the use of single hatched areas on the\nchart.\n",
        "choiceone": "areas of forecast, severe or extreme turbulence, and areas of severe icing for the\nnext 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "areas of general thunderstorm activity (excluding severe) by the use of hatching on\nthe chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thunderstorms generally produce the most severe conditions, such as heavy hi\nand destructive winds?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition produces weather on the lee side of a large lake?\n",
        "answer": "Warm air flowing over a colder lake may produce fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air flowing over a warmer lake may produce advection fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm air flowing over a cool lake may produce rain showers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A characteristic of the stratosphere is\n",
        "answer": "relatively small changes in temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "an overall decrease of temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a relatively even base altitude of approximately 35,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to a high- or low-pressure system?\n",
        "answer": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of descending air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A low-pressure area or trough is an area of descending air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area forecasts generally include a forecast period of 18 hours and cover a geographical\n",
        "answer": "area the size of several states.\n",
        "choiceone": "terminal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "area less than 3000 square miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If squalls are reported at your destination, what wind conditions should you anticipate?\n",
        "answer": "Sudden increases in wind speed of at least 16 knots, rising to 22 knots or more,\nlasting for at least 1 minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "Peak gusts of at least 35 knots for a sustained period of 1 minute or longer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rapid variation in wind direction of at least 20__degrees__ and changes in speed of\nat least 10 knots between peaks and lulls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KMAF 131756Z 02020KT 12SM BKN025 OVC250 27/18 A3009 RMK RAE44.\n\n|Which weather condition is indicated by this METAR report at Midland (KMAF)?\n",
        "answer": "Rain of unknown intensity ended 16 minutes before the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling was at 25,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind was 020 degrees magnetic at 20 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding ridge soaring with the wind direction perpendicular to the\nridge?\n",
        "answer": "If the glider drifts downwind from the ridge and sinks slightly lower than the crest of\nthe ridge, the glider should be turned away from the ridge and a high speed attained.\n",
        "choiceone": "When very close to the surface of the ridge, the glider's speed should be reduced to\nthe minimum sink speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the wind and lift are very strong on the windward side of the ridge, a weak sink\ncondition will exist on the leeward side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 146.) What method was used to obtain the METAR at Tyler (KTYR) at\n17532?\n",
        "answer": "Automated Surface Observing System (ASOS), having a precipitation discriminator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic Meteorological Observing Station (AMOS), with a precipitation\ndiscriminator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Automated Weather Observing System (AWOS), without a precipitation\ndiscriminator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Dallas (KDAL)?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter setting is 30.07.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tops of the overcast is 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature/dewpoint spread is 8 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 148.) What time period is covered by the outlook section of the\nConvective SIGMET?\n",
        "answer": "2 to 6 hours after the valid time.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 hours after the valid time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No more than 2 hours after the valid time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an operational consideration if you fly into rain which freezes on impact?\n",
        "answer": "Temperatures are above freezing at some higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "You have flown into an area of thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You have flown through a cold front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During preflight preparation, weather report forecasts which are not routinely available\nat the local service outlet can best be obtained by means of contacting the\n",
        "answer": "weather forecast office (WFD).\n",
        "choiceone": "air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot's automatic telephone answering service.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fog is usually prevalent in industrial areas because of\n",
        "answer": "an abundance of condensation nuclei from combustion products.\n",
        "choiceone": "atmospheric stabilization around cities.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased temperatures due to industrial heating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions result in the formation of frost?\n",
        "answer": "Temperature of the collecting surface is below the dewpoint of surrounding air and\nthe dewpoint is colder than freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature of the collecting surface is at or below freezing and small droplets\nof moisture are falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When dew forms and the temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of center of gravity on the spin characteristics of an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A flat spin may develop if the CG is too far aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the CG is too far forward, spin entry will be difficult.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If the CG is too far aft, spins can become high-speed spirals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Childress (KCDS)?\n",
        "answer": "Light rain showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heavy rain showers began 42 minutes after the hour.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ceiling is solid overcast at an estimated 1,800 feet above sea level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What type of report is listed for Lubbock (KLBB) at 18182?\n",
        "answer": "A Special METAR weather observation, concerning significant weather changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "An Aviation selected special weather report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A special report concerning very low station pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most midair colli\n\n",
        "answer": "clear days.\n",
        "choiceone": "hazy days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cloudy nights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does wind shear occur?\n",
        "answer": "With either a wind shift or a wind speed gradient at any level in the atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": ":xclusively in thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wherever there is an abrupt decrease in pressure and/or temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What weather improvement was reported at Lubbock (KLBB)\nbetween 1750 and 1818 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "The vertical visibility improved by 2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "The wind shift and frontal passage at 1812Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature and dewpoint spread improved.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated by the term \u2018embedded thunderstorms\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are obscured by other types of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms are embedded in a squall line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are predicted to develop in a stable air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding high- or low-pressure systems?\n",
        "answer": "A low-pressure area or trough is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Both high- and low-pressure areas are characterized by descending air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To best determine observed weather conditions between weather reporting stations,\nthe pilot should refer to\n",
        "answer": "pilot reports.\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prognostic charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAF) are issued how many times a day and cover what\nperiod of time?\n",
        "answer": "Four times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period.\n",
        "choiceone": "Six times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period including a 4-hour\ncategorical outlook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four times daily and are valid for 12 hours including a 6-hour categorical outlook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type service should normally be expected from an En Route Flight Advisory\nService?\n",
        "answer": "Weather advisories pertinent to the type of flight, intended route of flight, and\naltitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe weather information, changes in flight plans, and receipt of position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar vectors for traffic separation, route weather advisories, and altimeter settings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant Pressure Analysis Charts contain contours, isotherms and some con\nisotachs. The contours depict\n",
        "answer": "ridges, lows, troughs and highs aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges on the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges corrected to MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which primary source should be used to obtain forecast weather information at your\ndestination for the planned ETA?\n",
        "answer": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF).\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar Summary and Weather Depiction Charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an STL MEM MSY\nflight at FL 330?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind shift from west to north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature increase 5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A katabatic wind blows\n",
        "answer": "down the slope during the night.\n",
        "choiceone": "up the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "down the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicethree": "up the slope during the night.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For both saturated and unsaturated air instability will occur when the\n",
        "answer": "environmental lapse rate is greater than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choiceone": "environmental lapse rate is greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but less than\ndry adiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicetwo": "environmental lapse rate is less than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicethree": "dry adiabatic lapse rate is less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but greater than\nenvironmental lapse rate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms suddenly by day but not by night\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is formed when the air is unstable\n",
        "choicethree": "It develops slowly and dissipates rapidly\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical zero degree isotherm is\n",
        "answer": "16000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "12000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "19000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10798A)\nThe dotted line labelled \"Y\" represents the\n",
        "answer": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone during January\n",
        "choiceone": "axis of the subtropical jet stream during January\n",
        "choicetwo": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone during July\n",
        "choicethree": "axis of the equatorial jet stream during July\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which METAR report suggests that a thunderstorm is likely in the next few hours?\n",
        "answer": "201350Z 21005KT 9999 SCTO40CB SCT100 26/18 Q1016 TEMPO 24018G30KT TS=\n",
        "choiceone": "201350Z 16004KT 8000 SCT110 OVC220 02/M02 Q1008 NOSIG=\n",
        "choicetwo": "201350Z 34003KT 0800 SN VV002 M02/M04 Q1014 NOSIG=\n",
        "choicethree": "201350Z 04012KT 3000 BR OVC012 04/03 Q1022 BECMG 6000=\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will an area of thunderstorm activity, that may grow to severe intensity, be\nindicated on the Severe Weather Outlook Chart?\n",
        "answer": "APCHG within any area.\n",
        "choiceone": "SLGT within cross-hatched areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SVR within any area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 148.) Which system in the Convective SIGME\nof producing the most severe storm?\n\nsting has the potential\n",
        "answer": "The isolated storm 50 miles northeast of Memphis (MEM).\n",
        "choiceone": "The storms in Texas and Oklahoma.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The storms in Colorado, Kansas, and Oklahoma.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended if a pilot should unintentionally penetrate embedded\nthunderstorm activity?\n",
        "answer": "Set power for recommended turbulence penetration airspeed and attempt to\nmaintain a level flight attitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Reverse aircraft heading or proceed toward an area of known VFR conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce airspeed to maneuvering speed and maintain a constant altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of center of gravity on the spin characteristics of an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A flat spin may develop if the CG is too far aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the CG is too far forward, spin entry will be difficult.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If the CG is too far aft, spins can become high-speed spirals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What situation is most conducive to the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Warm, moist air over low, flatland areas on clear, calm nights.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist, tropical air moving over cold, offshore water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The movement of cold air over much warmer water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon is always associated with a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Supercooled raindrops.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation is advection fog most likely to form?\n",
        "answer": "An air mass moving inland from the coast in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "A light breeze blowing colder air out to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm, moist air settling over a warmer surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "temperature is forecast, one can expect what type of weather?\n",
        "answer": "Strong updrafts and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong updrafts and stratonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Restricted visibility near the surface over a large area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions result in the formation of frost?\n",
        "answer": "Temperature of the collecting surface is below the dewpoint of surrounding air and\nthe dewpoint is colder than freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature of the collecting surface is at or below freezing and small droplets\nof moisture are falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When dew forms and the temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What single reference contains information regarding volcanic eruption, that\noccurring or expected to occur?\n",
        "answer": "In-Flight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Terminal Area Forecasts (TAF).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Weather Depiction Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SPECI KGLS 131802Z 10012G21KT 060V140 2SM +SHRA SCT005 BKN035 OVC050CB\n24/23 A2980 RMK RAB\u00a77 WS TKO RWOSL WSHFT 58 FROPA. This SPECI report at\nGalveston (KGLS) indicates which condition?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation started at 57 after the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind steady at 100 degree magnetic at 12 knots, gusts to 21.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet overcast with towering cumulus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the winds at 2,000 feet above the surface and the\nsurface winds?\n",
        "answer": "The winds at 2,000 feet tend to parallel the isobars while the surface winds cross the\nisobars at an angle toward lower pressure and are weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "The winds at 2,000 feet and the surface winds flow in the same direction, but the\nsurface winds are weaker due to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface winds tend to veer to the right of the winds at 2,000 feet and are usually\nweaker.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect does haze have on the ability to see traffic or terrain features during flight?\n",
        "answer": "All traffic or terrain features appear to be farther away than their actual distance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Haze causes the eyes to focus at infinity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The eyes tend to overwork in haze and do not detect relative movement easily.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why does the wind have a tendency to flow parallel to the isobars above the friction\nlevel?\n",
        "answer": "Coriolis force tends to counterbalance the horizontal pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coriolis force acts perpendicular to a line connecting the highs and lows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Friction of the air with the Earth deflects the air perpendicular to the pressure\ngradient.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What significant cloud coverage is reported by tt\nMOB 1340Z/SK OVC 025/045 OVC 090\n\npilot report?|KMOB UA/OV 15NW\n",
        "answer": "The top of the lower overcast is 2,500 feet; base and top of second overcast layer is\n4,500 and 9,000 feet, respectively.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three (3) separate overcast layers exist with bases at 250, 7,500 and 9,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The base of the second overcast layer is 2,500 feet; top of second overcast layer is\n7,500 feet; base of third layer is 9,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated by the term \u2018embedded thunderstorms\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are obscured by other types of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms are embedded in a squall line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are predicted to develop in a stable air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather feature occurs at altitude levels near the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "Maximum winds and narrow wind shear zones.\n",
        "choiceone": "Abrupt temperature increase above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thin layers of cirrus (ice crystal) clouds at the tropopause level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) A planned low-altitude flight from central Oklahoma to western\nTennessee at 12002 is likely to encounter\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery rain over half or more of the area, moderate turbulence, and\nfreezing temperatures above 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous or intermittent rain or rain showers, moderate turbulence, and freezing\ntemperatures below 8,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "showery precipitation covering less than half the area, no turbulence below 18,000\nfeet, and freezing temperatures above 12,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant Pressure Analysis Charts contain contours, isotherms and some con\nisotachs. The contours depict\n",
        "answer": "ridges, lows, troughs and highs aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges on the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges corrected to MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four families of clouds?\n",
        "answer": "High, middle, low, and those with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus, cumulus, nimbus, and cirrus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds formed by updrafts, fronts, cooling layers of air, and precipitation into warm\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFSS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding ridge soaring with the wind direction perpendicular to the\nridge?\n",
        "answer": "If the glider drifts downwind from the ridge and sinks slightly lower than the crest of\nthe ridge, the glider should be turned away from the ridge and a high speed attained.\n",
        "choiceone": "When very close to the surface of the ridge, the glider's speed should be reduced to\nthe minimum sink speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the wind and lift are very strong on the windward side of the ridge, a weak sink\ncondition will exist on the leeward side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "RB\" wind entry in a Terminal Aerodome Forecast (TAF) will be\nwind is\n",
        "answer": "3 knots or less.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 knots or less.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 knots or less.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather condition is an example of a nonfrontal instability band?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advective fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frontogenesis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of low-level wind shear as it relates to frontal activity?\n",
        "answer": "With a warm front, the most critical period is before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "With a cold front, the most critical period is just before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence will always exist in wind-shear conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather is predicted by the term VCTS in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are expected in the vicinity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thunderstorms may occur over the station and within 50 miles of the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are expected between 5 and 25 miles of the runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon is always associated with the passage of a frontal system?\n",
        "answer": "A wind change.\n",
        "choiceone": "An abrupt decrease in pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds, either ahead or behind the front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the effect of fronts on soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "Frequently the air behind a cold front provides excellent soaring for several days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Good soaring conditions usually exist after passage of a warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "xcellent soaring conditions usually exist in the cold air ahead of a warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What determines the structure or type of clouds which will form as a result of air being\nforced to ascend?\n",
        "answer": "The stability of the air before lifting occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "The method by which the air is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The relative humidity of the air after lifting occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is most appropriate when an envelope over-temperature condition occurs?\n",
        "answer": "Land as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and allow envelope to cool before landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Throw all unnecessary equipment overboard in order to lighten the load.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements applies to the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "It separates the troposphere from the stratosphere\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis, by definition, an isothermal layer\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates a strong temperature lapse rate\n",
        "choicethree": "Itis, by definition, a temperature inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is\n",
        "answer": "an increase of temperature with height\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase of pressure with height\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease of pressure with height\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease of temperature with height\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by QFE?\n",
        "answer": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation, reduced to mean sea\nlevel in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pressure at MSL in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The present atmospheric pressure at an aerodrome converted to mean sea level in\naccordance with the actual conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions gives the highest value of the QNH?\n",
        "answer": "QFE = 995 hPa, elevation = 1600 ft (488m)\n",
        "choiceone": "QFE = 1000 hPa, elevation = 1200 ft (366m)\n",
        "choicetwo": "QFE = 1003 hPa, elevation = 1200 ft (366m)\n",
        "choicethree": "QFE = 995 hPa, elevation = 1200 ft (366m)\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an adiabatic process\n",
        "answer": "heat is neither added nor lost\n",
        "choiceone": "heat is added\n",
        "choicetwo": "heat is lost\n",
        "choicethree": "the temperature does not change\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For both saturated and unsaturated air instability will occur when the\n",
        "answer": "environmental lapse rate is greater than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choiceone": "environmental lapse rate is greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but less than\ndry adiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicetwo": "environmental lapse rate is less than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated\nadiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "choicethree": "dry adiabatic lapse rate is less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but greater than\nenvironmental lapse rate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "temperature is forecast, one can expect what type of weather?\n",
        "answer": "Strong updrafts and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong updrafts and stratonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Restricted visibility near the surface over a large area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Low-Level Significant Weather Prognostic Chart depicts weather conditions\n",
        "answer": "that are forecast to exist at a specific time shown on the chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "as they existed at the time the chart was prepared.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that are forecast to exist 6 hours after the chart was prepared.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common location of clear air turbulence is\n",
        "answer": "in an upper trough on the polar side of a jet stream.\n",
        "choiceone": "near a ridge aloft on the equatorial side of a high-pressure flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "south of an east/west oriented high-pressure ridge in its dissipating stage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which response most closely interprets the following PIREP?|UA/OV OKC 063064/TM\n1522/FLO80/TP C172/TA -04/WV 245040/TB LGT/RM IN CLR\n",
        "answer": "64 nautical miles on the 63 degrees radial from Oklahoma City VOR at 1522 UTC,\nflight level 8,000 ft. Type of aircraft is a Cessna 172.\n",
        "choiceone": "Reported by a Cessna 172, turbulence and light rime icing in climb to 8,000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "63 nautical miles on the 64 degrees radial from Oklahoma City, thunderstorm and\nlight rain at 1522 UTC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the cumulus stage of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Beginning of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frequent lightning.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 153.) What type weather system is approaching the C:\nfrom the west?\n",
        "answer": "LOW.\n",
        "choiceone": "HIGH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus clouds often indicate\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level.\n",
        "choiceone": "poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Virga is best described as\n",
        "answer": "streamers of precipitation trailing beneath clouds which evaporates before reaching\nthe ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "wall cloud torrents trailing beneath cumulonimbus clouds which dissipate before\nreaching the ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turbulent areas beneath cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is provided by a Convective Outlook (AC)?\n",
        "answer": "It provides prospects of both general and severe thunderstorm activity during the\nfollowing 24 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "It describes areas of probable severe icing and severe or extreme turbulence during\nthe next 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates areas of probable convective turbulence and the extent of instability in\nthe upper atmosphere (above 500 mb).\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an STL MEM MSY\nflight at FL 330?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind shift from west to north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature increase 5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the temperature at one of the forecast altitudes omitted at a specific location or\nstation in the Winds and Temperatures Aloft Forecast (FD)?\n\n",
        "answer": "For the 3,000-foot altitude (level) or when the level is within 2,500 feet of station\nelevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the temperature is standard for that altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the winds are omitted for that altitude (level).\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ions necessary for the formation of cumulonimbus clouds are a lifti\n\n",
        "answer": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If clouds form as a result of very stable, moist air being forced to ascend a mountain\nslope, the clouds will be\n",
        "answer": "stratus type with little vertical development and little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "cirrus type with no vertical development or turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cumulus type with considerable vertical development and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high cloud is composed mostly of\n",
        "answer": "ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "ozone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "condensation nuclei.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A prognostic chart depicts the conditions\n",
        "answer": "forecast to exist at a specific time in the future.\n",
        "choiceone": "existing at the surface during the past 6 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "which presently exist from the 1,000-millibar through the 700-millibar level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-on-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1,200 feet AGL). Whatis the in flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operations during daylight hours for the circle 1 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Summer thunderstorms in the arctic region will generally move\n",
        "answer": "northeast to southwest in polar easterlies.\n",
        "choiceone": "southwest to northeast with the jetstream flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "directly north to south with the low-level polar airflow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most midair colli\n\n",
        "answer": "clear days.\n",
        "choiceone": "hazy days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cloudy nights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of either predominantly stratiform or predominantly cumuliform clouds is\ndependent upon the\n",
        "answer": "stability of the air being lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature of the air being lifted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When total sky cover is few or scattered, the height shown on the Weather Depiction\nChartis the\n",
        "answer": "base of the lowest layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "top of the lowest layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "base of the highest layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum weather conditions must be forecast for your ETA at an alternate airport,\nthat has only a VOR approach with standard alternate minimums, for the airport to be\nlisted as an alternate on the IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "800-foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "800-foot ceiling and 1 statute mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000-foot ceiling and visibility to allow descent from minimum en route altitude\n(MEA), approach, and landing under basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type clouds can be expected when an unstable air mass is forced to ascend a\nmountain slope?\n",
        "answer": "Clouds with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Layered clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratified clouds with considerable associated turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of the cloud is at its maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement pertaining to the life cycle of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "answer": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the mature stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Updrafts continue to develop throughout the dissipating stage of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the dissipating stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absence of the sky condition and visibility on an ATIS broadcast specifically\nthat\n\n",
        "answer": "the ceiling is more than 5,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sky condition is clear and visibility is unrestricted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the ceiling is at least 3,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Winds at 5,000 feet AGL on a particular flight are southwesterly while most of the\nsurface winds are southerly. This difference in direction is primarily due to\n",
        "answer": "friction between the wind and the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "a stronger pressure gradient at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stronger Coriolis force at the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are haze layers cleared or dispersed?\n",
        "answer": "By wind or the movement of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "By convective mixing in cool night air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By evaporation similar to the clearing of fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes changes in altitude and/or\nattitude more than two-thirds of the time, with the aircraft remaining in positive control at\nall times?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous severe chop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Intermittent moderate turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four families of clouds?\n",
        "answer": "High, middle, low, and those with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus, cumulus, nimbus, and cirrus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds formed by updrafts, fronts, cooling layers of air, and precipitation into warm\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most severe weather conditions, such as destructive winds, heavy hail, and\ntornadoes, are generally associated with\n",
        "answer": "squall lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "slow-moving warm fronts which slope above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fast-moving occluded fronts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying in the southern hemisphere at 2000 feet, has to turn to the right in order\nto allow for drift. In which direction, relative to the track of the aircraft, is the centre of\nlow pressure ?\n",
        "answer": "In front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Behind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the left.\n",
        "choicethree": "To the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sea breezes are most likely to occur when\n",
        "answer": "slack pressure gradient and clear skies result in relatively high land temperatures\n",
        "choiceone": "a strong pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions\npersist\n",
        "choicetwo": "a strong pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and clear skies at night\nexist\n",
        "choicethree": "a slack pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions\npersist\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus often is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level\n",
        "choiceone": "poor visibility at surface\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions below the cloud level\n",
        "choicethree": "a high risk of thunderstorms\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of weather can usually be expected in a polar maritime air mass over Central\nEurope in the daytime during summer?\n",
        "answer": "Showers and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous rain and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Drizzle and low stratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sky clear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10759A)\nThe cloud type most applicable to square 2D is\n",
        "answer": "AS\n",
        "choiceone": "CU\n",
        "choicetwo": "cB\n",
        "choicethree": "cs\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10845A)\nFor an aircraft at FL 40, approaching the front (square 3C) from the direction of square\n3D a potential hazard exists before reaching the front in the form of\n",
        "answer": "clear ice accretion to the airframe\n",
        "choiceone": "severe turbulence associated with CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence and wind shear\n",
        "choicethree": "severe downdrafts from subsiding air\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the following weather messagerepresent?\nEDDM 241200Z 241322 VRBO3KT 1500 BR OVC004 BECMG 1517 00000KT 0500 FG\nVV002 TEMPO 2022 0400 FG Vv001=\n",
        "answer": "9 hour TAF.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 hour TAF.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SPECI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying into a low-pressure area\nand velocity will be from the\n\nthe Northern Hemisphere, the wind direction\n",
        "answer": "left and increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "left and decreasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "right and decreasing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the stability of the atmosphere be determined?\n",
        "answer": "Ambient temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Atmospheric pressure at various levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface temperature/dewpoint spread.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix 'nimbus\u2019, used in naming clouds, means a\n",
        "answer": "rain cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "cloud with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dark massive, towering cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which clouds have the greatest turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Towering cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus castellanus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A clear area in a line of thunderstorm echoes on a radar scope indicates\n",
        "answer": "an area where precipitation drops are not detected.\n",
        "choiceone": "the absence of clouds in the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area of no convective turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon is always associated with a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Supercooled raindrops.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clouds, fog, or dew will always form when\n",
        "answer": "water vapor condenses.\n",
        "choiceone": "water vapor is present.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the temperature and dew point are equal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During preflight preparation, weather report forecasts which are not routinely available\nat the local service outlet can best be obtained by means of contacting the\n",
        "answer": "weather forecast office (WFD).\n",
        "choiceone": "air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot's automatic telephone answering service.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steady precipitation, in contrast to showers, preceding a front is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "stratiform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratiform clouds with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cummuliform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is most appropriate when an envelope over-temperature condition occurs?\n",
        "answer": "Land as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and allow envelope to cool before landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Throw all unnecessary equipment overboard in order to lighten the load.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What causes surface winds to flow across the isobars at an angle rather than parallel to\nthe isobars?\n",
        "answer": "Surface friction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The greater density of the air at the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What weather improvement was reported at Lubbock (KLBB)\nbetween 1750 and 1818 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "The vertical visibility improved by 2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "The wind shift and frontal passage at 1812Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature and dewpoint spread improved.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A PROB40 (PROBability) HHhh group in an International Terminal Aerodrome Forecast\n(TAF) indicates the probability of\n\n",
        "answer": "thunderstorms or other precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "precipitation or low visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "thunderstorms or high wind.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest Flight contol center\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFlight control center broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common type of ground or surface based temperature inversion is that which is\n\nproduced by\n",
        "answer": "ground radiation on clear, cool nights when the wind is light.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air being lifted rapidly aloft in the vicinity of mountainous terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the movement of colder air over warm air, or the movement of warm air under cold\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying over the top of a severe thunderstorm, the cloud should be overflown by at\nleast\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet for each 10 knots windspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 feet above any moderate to severe turbulence layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 146.) What method was used to obtain the METAR at Tyler (KTYR) at\n17532?\n",
        "answer": "Automated Surface Observing System (ASOS), having a precipitation discriminator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic Meteorological Observing Station (AMOS), with a precipitation\ndiscriminator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Automated Weather Observing System (AWOS), without a precipitation\ndiscriminator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement pertaining to the following Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) is true?\n|TAF|KMEM 091135Z 0915 15005KT 5SM HZ BKNO60|FM1600 VRBO4KT P6SM SKC\n",
        "answer": "SKC in the valid period indicates no significant weather and sky clear.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind in the valid period implies surface winds are forecast to be greater than 5 KTS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction is from 160__degrees__ at 4 KTS and reported vi\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moisture is added to a parcel of air by\n",
        "answer": "evaporation and sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "sublimation and condensation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evaporation and condensation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wind shear forecast in the following TAF?|TAF|KCVG 231051Z 231212\n12012KT 4SM -RA BR OVC008|/WS005/27050KT TEMPO 1719 1/2SM -RA FG|FM1930\n09012KT 1SM -DZ BR VV003 BECMG 2021 5SM HZ=\n",
        "answer": "500 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can wind shear associated with a thunderstorm be found? Choose the most\ncomplete answer.\n",
        "answer": "On all sides of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the right side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In front of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which forecast provides specific information concerning expected sky cover, cloud\ntops, visibility, weather, and obstructions to vision in a route format?\n",
        "answer": "Transcribed Weather Broadcast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Terminal Forecast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of weather can one expect from moist, unstable air, and very warm surface\ntemperatures?\n",
        "answer": "Strong updrafts and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fog and low stratus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous heavy precipitation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sudden penetration of fog can create the illusion of\n",
        "answer": "pitching up.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitching down.\n",
        "choicetwo": "leveling off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated by the term \u2018embedded thunderstorms\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are obscured by massive cloud layers and cannot be seen.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms are embedded within a squall line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are predicted to develop in a stable air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What prevents air from flowing directly from high-pressure areas to low-pressure areas?\n",
        "answer": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "Surface friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure gradient force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will an area of thunderstorm activity, that may grow to severe intensity, be\nindicated on the Severe Weather Outlook Chart?\n",
        "answer": "APCHG within any area.\n",
        "choiceone": "SLGT within cross-hatched areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SVR within any area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination weather!\nshould be obtained from the\n\nformation for an instrument flight\n",
        "answer": "AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airman publications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes slight, rapid, and somewhat\nrhythmic bumpiness without appreciable changes in attitude or altitude, less than one-\nthird of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection fog has drifted over a coastal airport during the day. What may tend to\ndissipate or lift this fog into low stratus clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Wind 15 knots or stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nighttime cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station originating the following METAR observation has a field elevation of 3,500\nfeet MSL. If the sky cover is one continuous layer, what is the thickness of the cloud\nlayer? (Top of overcast reported at 7,500 feet MSL).|METAR KHOB 151250Z 17006KT\n4SM OVCO05 13/11 A2998\n",
        "answer": "3,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative\nto ISA) are expected for a flight over OKC at FL 370?\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees true; 27 knots; ISA +6 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "265 degrees true; 27 knots; ISA +1 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 27 knots; ISA +10 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What lifts advection fog into low stratus clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Surface winds of approximately 15 knots or stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nighttime cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dryness of the underlying land mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Dallas (KDAL)?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter setting is 30.07.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tops of the overcast is 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature/dewpoint spread is 8 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What values are used for Winds Aloft Forecasts?\n",
        "answer": "True direction and knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "True direction and MPH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Magnetic direction and knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sea breeze is a wind\n",
        "answer": "occurring only in the lower layers of the atmosphere in daytime\n",
        "choiceone": "that reaches up to the tropopause in daytime\n",
        "choicetwo": "blowing at night in mid-latitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "occurring only in mid-latitudes and in daytime\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are medium level clouds ?\n",
        "answer": "Altostratus and altocumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrocumulus and cirrostratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulonimbus\n",
        "choicethree": "All convective clouds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are severe weather watch bulletins (WW) issued?\n",
        "answer": "Unscheduled and issued as required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 12 hours as required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 24 hours as required.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The jet stream and associated clear\nin flight by\n\nturbulence can sometimes be visually identified\n",
        "answer": "long streaks of cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "dust or haze at flight level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a constant outside air temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions result in the formation of frost?\n",
        "answer": "Temperature of the collecting surface is below the dewpoint of surrounding air and\nthe dewpoint is colder than freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature of the collecting surface is at or below freezing and small droplets\nof moisture are falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When dew forms and the temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most frequent type of ground- or surface-based temperature inversion is that\n\nproduced by\n",
        "answer": "radiation on a clear, relatively still night.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air being lifted rapidly aloft in the vicinity of mountainous terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the movement of colder air under warm air, or the movement of warm air over cold\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can wind shear associated with a thunderstorm be found? Choose the most\ncomplete answer.\n",
        "answer": "On all sides of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the right side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In front of the thunderstorm cell and directly under the cell.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If clouds form as a result of very stable, moist air being forced to ascend a mountain\nslope, the clouds will be\n",
        "answer": "stratus type with little vertical development and little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "cirrus type with no vertical development or turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cumulus type with considerable vertical development and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A PROB40 (PROBability) HHhh group in an International Terminal Aerodrome Forecast\n(TAF) indicates the probability of\n\n",
        "answer": "thunderstorms or other precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "precipitation or low visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "thunderstorms or high wind.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an SATELP TUS\nflight at 16,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction shift from southwest to east.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease slightly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hazardous wind shear is commonly encountered\n",
        "answer": "in areas of temperature inversion and near thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "near warm or stationary frontal activity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when the wind velocity is stronger than 35 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning the radar weather report (SD) for KOKC?|KOKC 1934 LN\n8TRW++4/+ 86/40 164/60 199/115 15W L2425 MT 570 AT 159/65 2|INCH HAIL RPRTD THIS\nCELL\n",
        "answer": "The maximum tops of the cells is 57,000 feet located 65 NM southeast of the station.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are three cells with tops at 11,500, 40,000, and 60,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line of cells is moving 060 degrees with winds reported up to 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the effect of fronts on soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "Frequently the air behind a cold front provides excellent soaring for several days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Good soaring conditions usually exist after passage of a warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "xcellent soaring conditions usually exist in the cold air ahead of a warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the pilot obtain TWEB Route Forecast information?\n",
        "answer": "From the TEL TWEB and radio broadcasts.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the ATIS and Pilots Automatic Telephone Weather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From ARTCC and Automated Flight Service Station briefings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Childress (KCDS)?\n",
        "answer": "Light rain showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heavy rain showers began 42 minutes after the hour.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ceiling is solid overcast at an estimated 1,800 feet above sea level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To best determine observed weather conditions between weather reporting stations,\nthe pilot should refer to\n",
        "answer": "pilot reports.\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prognostic charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type jetstream can be expected to cause the greater turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "A curving jetstream associated with a deep low pressure trough.\n",
        "choiceone": "A straight jetstream associated with a high pressure ridge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A jetstream associated with a wide isotherm spacing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type service should normally be expected from an En Route Flight Advisory\nService?\n",
        "answer": "Weather advisories pertinent to the type of flight, intended route of flight, and\naltitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe weather information, changes in flight plans, and receipt of position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar vectors for traffic separation, route weather advisories, and altimeter settings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of clouds will be formed if very stable moist air is forced up slope?\n",
        "answer": "Stratified clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "First stratified clouds and then vertical clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical clouds with increasing height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If airborne radar is indicating an extremely intense thunderstorm echo, tl\nthunderstorm should be avoided by a distance of at least\n",
        "answer": "20 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During preflight preparation, weather report forecasts which are not routinely available\nat the local service outlet can best be obtained by means of contacting the\n",
        "answer": "weather forecast office (WFD).\n",
        "choiceone": "air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot's automatic telephone answering service.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the development of convective circulation?\n",
        "answer": "Cool air must sink to force the warm air upward.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm air is less dense and rises on its own accord.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warmer air covers a larger surface area than the cool air; therefore, the warmer air is\nless dense and rises.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 146.) What was the ceiling at Walnut Ridge (KARG)?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,400 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 154.) What is the height of the 300-millibar level at the low pressure?\n",
        "answer": "9,120 meters MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 meters MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11,850 meters MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which primary source should be used to obtain forecast weather information at your\ndestination for the planned ETA?\n",
        "answer": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF).\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar Summary and Weather Depiction Charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Behind a stationary front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steady precipitation, in contrast to showers, preceding a front is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "stratiform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratiform clouds with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cummuliform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What causes surface winds to flow across the isobars at an angle rather than parallel to\nthe isobars?\n",
        "answer": "Surface friction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The greater density of the air at the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition does advection fog usually form?\n",
        "answer": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm, moist air settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A land breeze blowing a cold air mass over a warm water current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the air temperature is +8 degrees C at an elevation of 1,350 feet and a standard\n(average) temperature lapse rate exists, what will be the approximate freezing level?\n",
        "answer": "5,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 6.) With regard to the soundings taken at 0900 hours, from 2,500 feet to\n1,000 feet, as shown on the Adiabatic Chart, what minimum surface temperature is\n\nrequired for instability to occur and for good thermals to develop from the surface to\n15,000 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "80 degrees F.\n",
        "choiceone": "58 degrees F.\n",
        "choicetwo": "68 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of weather can only be directly observed during flight and then reported in a\nPIREP?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and structural icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Jetstream-type winds and icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Level of the tropopause and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed aloft are forecast by this WINDS AND TEMPERATURE\nALOFT FORECAST (FD) for FL390 - '750649\u00b0?\n",
        "answer": "250 degrees at 106 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "350 degrees at 64 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "150 degrees at 6 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning an isothermal layer in the atmosphere\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "An isothermal layer is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air parcels that are forced to rise through an isothermal layer keep the same\ntemperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The vertical temperature gradient lies between the dry and saturated adiabatic lapse\nrates.\n",
        "choicethree": "An isothermal layer is formed when the air in the layer is well mixed by turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "About ten identical clouds are in the sky, well isolated from one another, dense, with\nwell defined contours, developing vertically in a cauliflower shape. The side of these\nclouds lit by the sun is bright white. Their base, relatively dark, is essentially horizontal\nand at FL 30, and their tops at FL 150. These clouds are\n",
        "answer": "towering Cumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "broken Cumulus humilis\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus castellanus\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratocumulus\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing fog consists of\n",
        "answer": "supercooled water droplets\n",
        "choiceone": "frozen water droplets\n",
        "choicetwo": "frozen minute snow flakes\n",
        "choicethree": "ice crystals\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The arctic front is the boundary between:\n",
        "answer": "polar air and arctic air.\n",
        "choiceone": "polar air and tropical air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold polar air and less cold polar air.\n",
        "choicethree": "arctic air and tropical air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-2388A)\nWhat wind direction will occur over the sea at point F?\n",
        "answer": "South\n",
        "choiceone": "Northeast\n",
        "choicetwo": "Northwest\n",
        "choicethree": "Southeast\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical zero degree isotherm is\n",
        "answer": "16000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "12000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "19000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interprete this METAR ?\n\n00000KT 0200 R14/0800U R16/P1500U FZFG VV001 m03/m03 Q1022 BECMG 0800=\n",
        "answer": "RVR for runway 14 800 metres, vertical visibility 100 feet, calm, visibility improving to\n800 metres in the next 2 hours\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 200 metres, RVR for runway 16 1500 metres, temperature -3\u00b0C, vertical\nvisibility 100 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 200 feet, RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres, vertical visibility 100\nfeet, fog with hoar frost\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility for runway 14 800 metres, fog with hoar frost, RVR for runway 16 more than\n1500 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed aloft are forecast by this WINDS AND TEMPERATURE\nALOFT FORECAST (FD) for FL390 - '750649\u00b0?\n",
        "answer": "250 degrees at 106 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "350 degrees at 64 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "150 degrees at 6 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The general characteristics of unstable air are\n",
        "answer": "good visibility, showery precipitation, and cumuliform-type clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "good visibility, steady precipitation, and stratiform-type clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "poor visibility, intermittent precipitation, and cumuliform-type clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) of P6SM implies that the\nprevailing visibility is expected to be greater than\n",
        "answer": "6 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 nautical miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 kilometers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus clouds often indicate\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level.\n",
        "choiceone": "poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of weather can only be directly observed during flight and then reported in a\nPIREP?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and structural icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Jetstream-type winds and icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Level of the tropopause and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 153.) What type weather system is approaching the C:\nfrom the west?\n",
        "answer": "LOW.\n",
        "choiceone": "HIGH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed is represented by the entry 9900+00 for 9,000 feet, on an\nWinds and Temperatures Aloft Forecast (FD)?\n",
        "answer": "Light and variable; less than 5 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Vortex winds exceeding 200 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light and variable; less than 10 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is a body of air that\n",
        "answer": "covers an extensive area and has fairly uniform properties of temperature and\nmoisture.\n",
        "choiceone": "has similar cloud formations associated with it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "creates a wind shift as it moves across the Earth's surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If squalls are reported at your destination, what wind conditions should you anticipate?\n",
        "answer": "Sudden increases in wind speed of at least 16 knots, rising to 22 knots or more,\nlasting for at least 1 minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "Peak gusts of at least 35 knots for a sustained period of 1 minute or longer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rapid variation in wind direction of at least 20__degrees__ and changes in speed of\nat least 10 knots between peaks and lulls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What type of report is listed for Lubbock (KLBB) at 18182?\n",
        "answer": "A Special METAR weather observation, concerning significant weather changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "An Aviation selected special weather report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A special report concerning very low station pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which information section is contained in the Aviation Area Forecast (FA)?\n",
        "answer": "VFR Clouds and Weather (VFR CLDS/WX).\n",
        "choiceone": "Winds aloft, speed and direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In-Flight Aviation Weather Advisories.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 146.) What was the ceiling at Walnut Ridge (KARG)?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,400 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type service should normally be expected from an En Route Flight Advisory\nService?\n",
        "answer": "Weather advisories pertinent to the type of flight, intended route of flight, and\naltitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe weather information, changes in flight plans, and receipt of position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar vectors for traffic separation, route weather advisories, and altimeter settings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 2.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative to\nISA) should a pilot expect when planning for a flight over EMI at FL 270?\n",
        "answer": "265 degrees true; 100 knots; ISA +3 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees true; 110 knots; ISA +5 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 100 knots; ISA -5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is associated with a temperature inversion?\n",
        "answer": "A stable layer of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "An unstable layer of air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a difference between an air mass thunderstorm and a steady-state\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Air mass thunderstorm downdrafts and precipitation retard and reverse the updrafts.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air mass thunderstorms produce precipitation which falls outside of the updraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steady-state thunderstorms are associated with local surface heating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which meteorological condition does the term \u2018dew point' refer?\n",
        "answer": "The temperature to which air must be cooled to become saturated.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature at which condensation and evaporation are equal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature at which dew will always form.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for a DSM LIT SHV\nflight at 12,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction shift from northwest to southeast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What single reference contains information regarding volcanic eruption, that\noccurring or expected to occur?\n",
        "answer": "In-Flight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Terminal Area Forecasts (TAF).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Weather Depiction Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for a DEN ICT OKC\nflight at 11,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed increase slightly.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind shift from calm to a westerly direction.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Childress (KCDS)?\n",
        "answer": "Light rain showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heavy rain showers began 42 minutes after the hour.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ceiling is solid overcast at an estimated 1,800 feet above sea level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicates that\nWest Virginia will likely experience\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery precipitation covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "thunderstorms and rain showers covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continuous rain covering less than half of the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "icated on the Weather Depiction Chart by a continuous smooth line\nenclosing a hatched geographic area?\n",
        "answer": "Reporting stations within the enclosed area are all showing IFR conditions at the\ntime of the report.\n",
        "choiceone": "The entire area has ceilings less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 50 percent of the area enclosed by the smooth line is predicted to have\nIFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Below pressure height, each 5 degrees F of positive superheat amounts to\napproximately\n",
        "answer": "1 percent of static lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 percent of net lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 percent of gross lift.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in VFR conditions during daylight hours\nfor the circle 4 area?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What temperature con\naltitude?\n\nindicated if wet snow is encountered at your flight\n",
        "answer": "The temperature is above freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature is below freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You are flying from a warm air mass into a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The vertical extent of the friction layer depends primarily on\n",
        "answer": "stability, wind speed, roughness of surface\n",
        "choiceone": "wind speed, roughness of surface, temperature\n",
        "choicetwo": "roughness of surface, temperature, local time\n",
        "choicethree": "temperature, local time, environmental lapse rate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus often is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level\n",
        "choiceone": "poor visibility at surface\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions below the cloud level\n",
        "choicethree": "a high risk of thunderstorms\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider a parcel of air being forced upwards in the atmosphere. The lapse rate of the\nsurrounding air is less than the saturated adiabatic lapse rate. After the initial force is no\nlonger effective, the parcel of air\n\n",
        "answer": "will tend to descend to its original altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "will tend to ascend further.\n",
        "choicetwo": "will tend to remain at the new altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "will become conditionally unstable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Snow grains\n",
        "answer": "fall from stratus or supercooled fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "are normally transparent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "are mainly formed inside altostratus and nimbostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "are typically formed inside a CB, where they are being tossed up and down while\ngrowing to such size that they could no longer be supported in the updraught.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main factor which contributes to the formation of very low clouds ahead of a warm\nfrontis the\n",
        "answer": "saturation of the cold air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choiceone": "saturation of the warm air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduction of outgoing radiation due to clouds\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air moving over a cold surface\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characterizes a stationary front ?\n",
        "answer": "The surface wind has its direction parallel to the front\n",
        "choiceone": "The surface wind has its direction perpendicular to the front\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warm air moves at approximately half the speed of the cold air\n",
        "choicethree": "The weather conditions that it generates are a combination of those of an intense\ncold front and those of a very active warm front\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement does correspond to the definition of severe turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft may be out of control for short periods, occupants are forced violently\nagainst seat belts, loose objects are tossed about.\n",
        "choiceone": "Difficulty in walking, occupants feel strain against seat belts, loose objects move\nabout.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft gets out of control and crashes.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft will be damaged and an emergency landing will be absolutely necessary.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cloud base, reported in the METAR, is the height above\n",
        "answer": "airfield level\n",
        "choiceone": "mean sea level\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pressure altitude of the observation station at the time of observation\n",
        "choicethree": "the highest terrain within a radius of 8 km from the observation station\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative\nto ISA) are expected for a flight over MKC at FL 260?\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees true; 43 knots; ISA +10 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "260 degrees true; 45 knots; ISA -10 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 42 knots; ISA +9 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the contraction VRB in the Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) mean?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction is variable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed is variable throughout the period.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloud base is variable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If squalls are reported at your destination, what wind conditions should you anticipate?\n",
        "answer": "Sudden increases in wind speed of at least 16 knots, rising to 22 knots or more,\nlasting for at least 1 minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "Peak gusts of at least 35 knots for a sustained period of 1 minute or longer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rapid variation in wind direction of at least 20__degrees__ and changes in speed of\nat least 10 knots between peaks and lulls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are some characteristics of unstable air?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nimbostratus clouds and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence and poor surface visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) A planned low-altitude flight from central Oklahoma to western\nTennessee at 12002 is likely to encounter\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery rain over half or more of the area, moderate turbulence, and\nfreezing temperatures above 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous or intermittent rain or rain showers, moderate turbulence, and freezing\ntemperatures below 8,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "showery precipitation covering less than half the area, no turbulence below 18,000\nfeet, and freezing temperatures above 12,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are haze layers cleared or dispersed?\n",
        "answer": "By wind or the movement of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "By convective mixing in cool night air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By evaporation similar to the clearing of fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather difference is found on each side of a \u2018dry line\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Dewpoint difference.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extreme temperature difference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratus versus cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the wind-group at one of the forecast altitudes omitted at a specific location or\nstation in the Winds and Temperatures Aloft Forecast (FD)? When the wind\n\n",
        "answer": "at the altitude is within 1,500 feet of the station elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "is less than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is less than 10 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of either predominantly stratiform or predominantly cumuliform clouds is\ndependent upon the\n",
        "answer": "stability of the air being lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature of the air being lifted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning the radar weather report (SD) for KOKC?|KOKC 1934 LN\n8TRW++4/+ 86/40 164/60 199/115 15W L2425 MT 570 AT 159/65 2|INCH HAIL RPRTD THIS\nCELL\n",
        "answer": "The maximum tops of the cells is 57,000 feet located 65 NM southeast of the station.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are three cells with tops at 11,500, 40,000, and 60,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line of cells is moving 060 degrees with winds reported up to 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which atmospheric factor causes rapid movement of surface fronts?\n",
        "answer": "Upper winds blowing across the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upper low located directly over the surface low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The cold front overtaking and lifting the warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is provided by a Convective Outlook (AC)?\n",
        "answer": "It provides prospects of both general and severe thunderstorm activity during the\nfollowing 24 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "It describes areas of probable severe icing and severe or extreme turbulence during\nthe next 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates areas of probable convective turbulence and the extent of instability in\nthe upper atmosphere (above 500 mb).\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Behind a stationary front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "icated on the Weather Depiction Chart by a continuous smooth line\nenclosing a hatched geographic area?\n",
        "answer": "Reporting stations within the enclosed area are all showing IFR conditions at the\ntime of the report.\n",
        "choiceone": "The entire area has ceilings less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 50 percent of the area enclosed by the smooth line is predicted to have\nIFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which clouds have the greatest turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Towering cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus castellanus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vertical wind shear can be determined directly from the dashed lines on the tropopause\ndata chart. The vertical wind shear that is critical for probability of turbulence is\n",
        "answer": "6 knots or more per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 knots or greater per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater than 8 knots per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 74.) What CAS should be used to maintain the filed TAS at the flight\nplanned altitude if the outside air temperature is +5 degrees C?\n",
        "answer": "133 KCAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "129 KCAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "139 KCAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying into a low-pressure area\nand velocity will be from the\n\nthe Northern Hemisphere, the wind direction\n",
        "answer": "left and increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "left and decreasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "right and decreasing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an SATELP TUS\nflight at 16,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction shift from southwest to east.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease slightly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ions necessary for the formation of cumulonimbus clouds are a lifti\n\n",
        "answer": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With respect to advection fog, which statement is true?\n",
        "answer": "It can appear suddenly during day or night, and it is more persistent than radiation\nfog.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is slow to develop, and dissipates quite rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It forms almost exclusively at night or near daybreak.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type clouds can be expected when an unstable air mass is forced to ascend a\nmountain slope?\n",
        "answer": "Clouds with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Layered clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratified clouds with considerable associated turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which family of clouds is least likely to contribute to structural icing on an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "High clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL)\nduring daylight hours for the circle 2 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant Pressure Analysis Charts contain contours, isotherms and some con\nisotachs. The contours depict\n",
        "answer": "ridges, lows, troughs and highs aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges on the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges corrected to MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What determines the structure or type of clouds which form as a result of air being\nforced to ascend?\n",
        "answer": "The stability of the air before lifting occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "The method by which the air is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The amount of condensation nuclei present after lifting occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true concerning squall lines?\n",
        "answer": "They offer the most intense weather hazards to aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "They form slowly, but move rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They are associated with frontal systems only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area forecasts generally include a forecast period of 18 hours and cover a geographical\n",
        "answer": "area the size of several states.\n",
        "choiceone": "terminal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "area less than 3000 square miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is associated with a temperature inversion?\n",
        "answer": "A stable layer of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "An unstable layer of air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition does advection fog usually form?\n",
        "answer": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm, moist air settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A land breeze blowing a cold air mass over a warm water current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAF) are issued how many times a day and cover what\nperiod of time?\n",
        "answer": "Four times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period.\n",
        "choiceone": "Six times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period including a 4-hour\ncategorical outlook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four times daily and are valid for 12 hours including a 6-hour categorical outlook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the same pressure gradient and den:\ngeostrophic wind will be\n\nat 60\u00b0N, 50\u00b0N and 40\u00b0N the speed of the\n",
        "answer": "greatest at 40\u00b0N\n",
        "choiceone": "the same at all latitudes\n",
        "choicetwo": "greatest at 60\u00b0N\n",
        "choicethree": "least at 50\u00b0N\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under anticyclone conditions in the northern hemisphere, with curved isobars the\nspeed of the gradient wind is\n",
        "answer": "greater than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choiceone": "less than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as the thermal component\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional only to the Coriolis force\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing fog exists if fog droplets\n",
        "answer": "are supercooled\n",
        "choiceone": "are frozen\n",
        "choicetwo": "are freezing very rapidly\n",
        "choicethree": "freeze when temperature falls below zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4297A)\nOn which one of the tracks (dashed lines) is this cross-section to be expected?\n",
        "answer": "Track B-D\n",
        "choiceone": "Track B-C\n",
        "choicetwo": "Track A-D\n",
        "choicethree": "Track A-E\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4314A)\nContinuous freezing rain is observed at an airfield.\n\nWhich of the four diagrams is most likely to reflect temperatures above the airfield\nconcerned?\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 1\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) At which time is IFR weather first predicted at Lubbock (KLBB)?\n",
        "answer": "0100Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "2100Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0400Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying into a low-pressure area\nand velocity will be from the\n\nthe Northern Hemisphere, the wind direction\n",
        "answer": "left and increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "left and decreasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "right and decreasing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average height of the troposphere in the middle latitudes is\n",
        "answer": "37,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "20,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying over the top of a severe thunderstorm, the cloud should be overflown by at\nleast\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet for each 10 knots windspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 feet above any moderate to severe turbulence layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which primary source contains information regarding the expected weather at the\ndestination airport, at the ETA?\n",
        "answer": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low-Level Prog Chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar Summary and Weather Depiction Charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Standing lenticular clouds, in mountainous areas, indicate\n",
        "answer": "turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "an inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What temperature con\naltitude?\n\nindicated if wet snow is encountered at your flight\n",
        "answer": "The temperature is above freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature is below freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You are flying from a warm air mass into a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "RB\" wind entry in a Terminal Aerodome Forecast (TAF) will be\nwind is\n",
        "answer": "3 knots or less.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 knots or less.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 knots or less.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A situation most conducive to the formation of advection fog is\n",
        "answer": "an air mass moving inland from the coastline during the winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a light breeze moving colder air over a water surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a warm, moist air mass settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If squalls are reported at your destination, what wind conditions should you anticipate?\n",
        "answer": "Sudden increases in wind speed of at least 16 knots, rising to 22 knots or more,\nlasting for at least 1 minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "Peak gusts of at least 35 knots for a sustained period of 1 minute or longer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rapid variation in wind direction of at least 20__degrees__ and changes in speed of\nat least 10 knots between peaks and lulls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Dallas (KDAL)?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter setting is 30.07.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tops of the overcast is 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature/dewpoint spread is 8 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A temperature inversion will normally form only\n",
        "answer": "in stable air.\n",
        "choiceone": "in unstable air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when a stratiform layer merges with a cumuliform mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area forecasts generally include a forecast period of 18 hours and cover a geographical\n",
        "answer": "area the size of several states.\n",
        "choiceone": "terminal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "area less than 3000 square miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The body of a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) covers a geographical proximity\nwithin a\n",
        "answer": "5 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 nautical mile radius of the center of an airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 to 10 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is frost considered hazardous to flight operation?\n",
        "answer": "Frost causes early airflow separation resulting in a loss of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost changes the basic aerodynamic shape of the airfoil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frost decreases control effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moisture is added to a parcel of air by\n",
        "answer": "evaporation and sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "sublimation and condensation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evaporation and condensation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination weather!\nshould be obtained from the\n\nformation for an instrument flight\n",
        "answer": "AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airman publications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type weather conditions are covered in the Convective SIGMET?\n",
        "answer": "Embedded thunderstorms, lines of thunderstorms, and thunderstorms with 3/4-inch\nhail or tornadoes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus clouds with tops above the tropopause and thunderstorms with 1/2-\ninch hail or funnel clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any thunderstorm with a severity level of VIP 2 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reporting station originating this Aviation Routine Weather Report has a field\nelevation of 620 feet. If the reported sky cover is one continuous layer, what is its\nthickness? (tops of OVC are reported at 6500 feet)|METAR KMDW 121856Z AUTO\n32005KT 1 1/2SM +RABR OVCO07 17/16 A2980\n",
        "answer": "5,180 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5,800 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,880 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions potentially hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to light aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only to light aircraft operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicates that\nWest Virginia will likely experience\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery precipitation covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "thunderstorms and rain showers covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continuous rain covering less than half of the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In-Flight Aviation Weather Advisories include what type of information?\n",
        "answer": "Forecasts for potentially hazardous flying conditions for enroute aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "State and geographic areas with reported ceilings and visibilities below VFR\nminimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions, turbulence, and icing within a valid period for the listed states.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most midair colli\n\n",
        "answer": "clear days.\n",
        "choiceone": "hazy days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cloudy nights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition produces weather on the lee side of a large lake?\n",
        "answer": "Warm air flowing over a colder lake may produce fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air flowing over a warmer lake may produce advection fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm air flowing over a cool lake may produce rain showers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KMAF 131756Z 02020KT 12SM BKN025 OVC250 27/18 A3009 RMK RAE44.\n\n|Which weather condition is indicated by this METAR report at Midland (KMAF)?\n",
        "answer": "Rain of unknown intensity ended 16 minutes before the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling was at 25,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind was 020 degrees magnetic at 20 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement pertaining to the following Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) is true?\n|TAF|KMEM 091135Z 0915 15005KT 5SM HZ BKNO60|FM1600 VRBO4KT P6SM SKC\n",
        "answer": "SKC in the valid period indicates no significant weather and sky clear.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind in the valid period implies surface winds are forecast to be greater than 5 KTS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction is from 160__degrees__ at 4 KTS and reported vi\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) The chart symbols over southern California on the 12-Hour\n\nSignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicate\n",
        "answer": "pected top of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u2018pected base of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "light turbulence expected above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does wind shear occur?\n",
        "answer": "With either a wind shift or a wind speed gradient at any level in the atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": ":xclusively in thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wherever there is an abrupt decrease in pressure and/or temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time are current AIRMETs broadcast in their entirety by the Hazardous Inflight\nWeather Advisory Service (HIWAS)?\n",
        "answer": "There is a continuous broadcast over selected VORs of Inflight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 and 45 minutes after the hour during the first hour after issuance, and upon\nreceipt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect does haze have on the ability to see traffic or terrain features during flight?\n",
        "answer": "All traffic or terrain features appear to be farther away than their actual distance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Haze causes the eyes to focus at infinity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The eyes tend to overwork in haze and do not detect relative movement easily.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) What type con\nland at San Angelo (KSJT) at 15002?\n\nions can be expected for a flight scheduled to\n",
        "answer": "IFR conditions due to low visibility, rain, and mist.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chance of 1 statute mile visibility and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions due to low ceilings, rain, and fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the pilot obtain TWEB Route Forecast information?\n",
        "answer": "From the TEL TWEB and radio broadcasts.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the ATIS and Pilots Automatic Telephone Weather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From ARTCC and Automated Flight Service Station briefings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unsaturated air flowing up slope will cool at the rate of approximately (dry adiabatic\nlapse rate)\n",
        "answer": "3 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is\n",
        "answer": "an increase of temperature with height\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase of pressure with height\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease of pressure with height\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease of temperature with height\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A katabatic wind blows\n",
        "answer": "down the slope during the night.\n",
        "choiceone": "up the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "down the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicethree": "up the slope during the night.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parcel of unsaturated air is forced to rise through an isothermal layer. So long a\nremains unsaturated, the temperature of the parcel\n\n",
        "answer": "decreases 1\u00b0C per 100m\n",
        "choiceone": "remains constant\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases 0.65\u00b0C per 100m\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes equal to the temperature of the isothermal layer\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favours the development of orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "High relative humidity\n",
        "choiceone": "Absolutely unstable air\n",
        "choicetwo": "Katabatic winds\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear nights\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main factor which contributes to the formation of very low clouds ahead of a warm\nfrontis the\n",
        "answer": "saturation of the cold air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choiceone": "saturation of the warm air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduction of outgoing radiation due to clouds\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air moving over a cold surface\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which METAR report suggests that a thunderstorm is likely in the next few hours?\n",
        "answer": "201350Z 21005KT 9999 SCTO40CB SCT100 26/18 Q1016 TEMPO 24018G30KT TS=\n",
        "choiceone": "201350Z 16004KT 8000 SCT110 OVC220 02/M02 Q1008 NOSIG=\n",
        "choicetwo": "201350Z 34003KT 0800 SN VV002 M02/M04 Q1014 NOSIG=\n",
        "choicethree": "201350Z 04012KT 3000 BR OVC012 04/03 Q1022 BECMG 6000=\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actior\nturbulence?\n\nrecommended regarding an altitude change to get out of jetstream\n",
        "answer": "Descend if ambient temperature is falling.\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend if ambient temperature is rising.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Maintain altitude if ambient temperature is not changing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dashed lines on a Surface Analysis Chart, if depicted,\ngradient is\n\n",
        "answer": "weak.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most frequent type of ground- or surface-based temperature inversion is that\n\nproduced by\n",
        "answer": "radiation on a clear, relatively still night.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air being lifted rapidly aloft in the vicinity of mountainous terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the movement of colder air under warm air, or the movement of warm air over cold\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which clouds have the greatest turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Towering cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus castellanus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A characteristic of the stratosphere is\n",
        "answer": "relatively small changes in temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "an overall decrease of temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a relatively even base altitude of approximately 35,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Strong turbulence in the cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Dallas (KDAL)?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter setting is 30.07.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tops of the overcast is 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature/dewpoint spread is 8 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are favorable for the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Clear sky, little or no wind, small temperature/dew point spread, and over a land\nsurface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloudy sky and a light wind moving saturated warm air over a cool surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAF) are issued how many times a day and cover what\nperiod of time?\n",
        "answer": "Four times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period.\n",
        "choiceone": "Six times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period including a 4-hour\ncategorical outlook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four times daily and are valid for 12 hours including a 6-hour categorical outlook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four families of clouds?\n",
        "answer": "High, middle, low, and those with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus, cumulus, nimbus, and cirrus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds formed by updrafts, fronts, cooling layers of air, and precipitation into warm\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum forecast period for AIRMETs?\n",
        "answer": "Six hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Of the following, whi\nthunderstorms?\n\naccurate regarding turbulence associated with\n",
        "answer": "Outside the cloud, shear turbulence can be encountered 20 miles laterally from a\nsevere storm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Outside the cloud, shear turbulence can be encountered 50 miles laterally from a\nsevere storm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shear turbulence is encountered only inside cumulonimbus clouds or within a 5-\nmile radius of them.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFSS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low-level wind shear may occur when\n",
        "answer": "there is a low-level temperature inversion with strong winds above the inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "surface winds are light and variable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "surface winds are above 15 knots and there is no change in wind direction and\nwindspeed with height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes slight, rapid, and somewhat\nrhythmic bumpiness without appreciable changes in attitude or altitude, less than one-\nthird of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which would increase the stability of an air mass?\n",
        "answer": "Cooling from below.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warming from below.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decrease in water vapor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Below pressure height, each 5 degrees F of positive superheat amounts to\napproximately\n",
        "answer": "1 percent of static lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 percent of net lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 percent of gross lift.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fog produced by frontal activity is a result of saturation due to\n",
        "answer": "evaporation of precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "nocturnal cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "adiabatic cooling.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If airborne radar is indicating an extremely intense thunderstorm echo, tl\nthunderstorm should be avoided by a distance of at least\n",
        "answer": "20 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are the only cloud types forecast in the Terminal Aerodrome Forecast?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus\n",
        "choiceone": "Altocumulus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying low over hilly terrain, ridges, or mountain ranges, the greatest potential\ndanger from turbulent air currents will usually be encountered on the\n",
        "answer": "leeward side when flying into the wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "leeward side when flying with a tailwind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "windward side when flying into the wind.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon is always associated with the passage of a frontal system?\n",
        "answer": "A wind change.\n",
        "choiceone": "An abrupt decrease in pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds, either ahead or behind the front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of either predominantly stratiform or predominantly cumuliform clouds is\ndependent upon the\n",
        "answer": "stability of the air being lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature of the air being lifted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are some characteristics of unstable air?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nimbostratus clouds and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence and poor surface visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A clear area in a line of thunderstorm echoes on a radar scope indicates\n",
        "answer": "an area where precipitation drops are not detected.\n",
        "choiceone": "the absence of clouds in the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area of no convective turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative\nto ISA) are expected for a flight over MKC at FL 260?\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees true; 43 knots; ISA +10 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "260 degrees true; 45 knots; ISA -10 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 42 knots; ISA +9 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type storms are most likely to produce funnel clouds or tornadoes?\n",
        "answer": "Cold front or squall line thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Storms associated with icing and supercooled water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time are current AIRMETs broadcast in their entirety by the Hazardous Inflight\nWeather Advisory Service (HIWAS)?\n",
        "answer": "There is a continuous broadcast over selected VORs of Inflight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 and 45 minutes after the hour during the first hour after issuance, and upon\nreceipt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated by the term \u2018embedded thunderstorms\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are obscured by other types of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms are embedded in a squall line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are predicted to develop in a stable air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unsaturated air flowing up slope will cool at the rate of approximately (dry adiabatic\nlapse rate)\n",
        "answer": "3 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A temperature inversion will normally form only\n",
        "answer": "in stable air.\n",
        "choiceone": "in unstable air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when a stratiform layer merges with a cumuliform mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement pertaining to the life cycle of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "answer": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the mature stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Updrafts continue to develop throughout the dissipating stage of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the dissipating stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an area of converging\n\n",
        "answer": "clouds can be formed\n",
        "choiceone": "convective clouds can be dissolved\n",
        "choicetwo": "stratified clouds can be dissolved\n",
        "choicethree": "clouds can not be formed\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The height of the lifting condensation level is determined by\n",
        "answer": "temperature and dew point at the surface\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature at surface and air pressure\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind and dew point at the surface\n",
        "choicethree": "wet adiabatic lapse rate and dew point at the surface\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Snow grains\n",
        "answer": "fall from stratus or supercooled fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "are normally transparent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "are mainly formed inside altostratus and nimbostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "are typically formed inside a CB, where they are being tossed up and down while\ngrowing to such size that they could no longer be supported in the updraught.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10845A)\nFor an aircraft at FL 40, approaching the front (square 3C) from the direction of square\n3D a potential hazard exists before reaching the front in the form of\n",
        "answer": "clear ice accretion to the airframe\n",
        "choiceone": "severe turbulence associated with CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence and wind shear\n",
        "choicethree": "severe downdrafts from subsiding air\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning the cold front and warm front of a frontal depression in the\nnorthern hemisphere is correct?\n",
        "answer": "The risk of fog is greater ahead of and behind the warm front than ahead of and\nbehind the cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "The precipitation zone of the cold front is in general wider than the precipitation\nzone of the warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "While occluding the warm front always becomes a front aloft.\n",
        "choicethree": "The wind backs more at the warm front than at the cold front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 300 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 300\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 390\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 100\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 50\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interprete this METAR ?\n\n00000KT 0200 R14/0800U R16/P1500U FZFG VV001 m03/m03 Q1022 BECMG 0800=\n",
        "answer": "RVR for runway 14 800 metres, vertical visibility 100 feet, calm, visibility improving to\n800 metres in the next 2 hours\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 200 metres, RVR for runway 16 1500 metres, temperature -3\u00b0C, vertical\nvisibility 100 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 200 feet, RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres, vertical visibility 100\nfeet, fog with hoar frost\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility for runway 14 800 metres, fog with hoar frost, RVR for runway 16 more than\n1500 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does wind shear occur?\n",
        "answer": "With either a wind shift or a wind speed gradient at any level in the atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": ":xclusively in thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wherever there is an abrupt decrease in pressure and/or temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the general direction of movement of a hurricane located in the Caribbean or\n\nGulf of Mexico region?\n\n",
        "answer": "Northwesterly curving to northeasterly.\n",
        "choiceone": "Westerly, until encountering land, then easterly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Counterclockwise over open water, then dissipating outward over land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Test data indicate that ice, snow, or frost having a thickness and roughness similar to\nmedium or coarse sandpaper on the leading edge and upper surface of an airfoil can\n",
        "answer": "reduce lift by as much as 30 percent and increase drag by 40 percent.\n",
        "choiceone": "reduce lift by as much as 50 percent and increase drag by as much as 50 percent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase drag and reduce lift by as much as 25 percent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the single source reference that contains information regarding volcanic\neruption, turbulence, and icing conditions for a specific region?\n",
        "answer": "In-Flight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weather Depiction Chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Area Forecast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station originating the following weather report has a field elevation of 1,300 feet\nMSL. From the bottom of the overcast cloud layer, whatis its thickness? (tops of OVC\nare reported at 3800 feet)|SPECI KOKC 22282 28024G36KT 3/4SM BKNO08 OVC020\n\n28/23 A3000\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moisture is added to a parcel of air by\n",
        "answer": "evaporation and sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "sublimation and condensation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evaporation and condensation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true concerning the hazards of hail?\n",
        "answer": "Hailstones may be encountered in clear air several miles from a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Hail damage in horizontal flight is minimal due to the vertical movement of hail in the\nclouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain at the surface is a reliable indication of no hail aloft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the winds at 2,000 feet above the surface and the\nsurface winds?\n",
        "answer": "The winds at 2,000 feet tend to parallel the isobars while the surface winds cross the\nisobars at an angle toward lower pressure and are weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "The winds at 2,000 feet and the surface winds flow in the same direction, but the\nsurface winds are weaker due to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface winds tend to veer to the right of the winds at 2,000 feet and are usually\nweaker.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 6.) At the 0900 hours sounding and the line plotted from the surface to\n10,000 feet, what temperature must exist at the surface for instability to take place\nbetween these altitudes? Any temperature\n",
        "answer": "more than 68 degrees F.\n",
        "choiceone": "less than 68 degrees F.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less than 43 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in VFR conditions during daylight hours\nfor the circle 4 area?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KSPS 131757Z 09014KT 6SM -RA SCT025 OVC090 24/22 A3005.|SPECI KSPS\n131820Z 01025KT 3SM +RA FC OVC015 22/21 A3000.|Which change took place at\nWichita Falls (KSPS) between 1757 and 1820 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "A funnel cloud was observed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rain became lighter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Atmospheric pressure increased.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes changes in altitude and/or\nattitude more than two-thirds of the time, with the aircraft remaining in positive control at\nall times?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous severe chop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Intermittent moderate turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type service should normally be expected from an En Route Flight Advisory\nService?\n",
        "answer": "Weather advisories pertinent to the type of flight, intended route of flight, and\naltitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe weather information, changes in flight plans, and receipt of position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar vectors for traffic separation, route weather advisories, and altimeter settings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What significant cloud coverage is reported by tt\nMOB 1340Z/SK OVC 025/045 OVC 090\n\npilot report?|KMOB UA/OV 15NW\n",
        "answer": "The top of the lower overcast is 2,500 feet; base and top of second overcast layer is\n4,500 and 9,000 feet, respectively.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three (3) separate overcast layers exist with bases at 250, 7,500 and 9,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The base of the second overcast layer is 2,500 feet; top of second overcast layer is\n7,500 feet; base of third layer is 9,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a difference between an air mass thunderstorm and a steady-state\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Air mass thunderstorm downdrafts and precipitation retard and reverse the updrafts.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air mass thunderstorms produce precipitation which falls outside of the updraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steady-state thunderstorms are associated with local surface heating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An illusion that the aircraft is at a higher altitude than it actually is, is produced by\n",
        "answer": "upsloping terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "atmospheric haze.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downsloping terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The strength and location of the jet stream is normally\n",
        "answer": "weaker and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "stronger and farther north in the winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stronger and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which combination of weather-producing variables would likely result in cum\ntype clouds, good visibility, and showery rain?\n\n",
        "answer": "Unstable, moist air and orographic lifting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stable, moist air and orographic lifting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Unstable, moist air and no lifting mechanism.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) The 12-Hour Significant Weather Prognostic Chart indicates that\neastern Kentucky and eastern Tennessee can expect probable ceilings\n\n",
        "answer": "less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles, and moderate turbulence\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles, and moderate turbulence\nabove 10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated by the term \u2018embedded thunderstorms\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are obscured by massive cloud layers and cannot be seen.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms are embedded within a squall line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are predicted to develop in a stable air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement pertaining to the life cycle of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "answer": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the mature stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Updrafts continue to develop throughout the dissipating stage of a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The beginning of rain at the Earth's surface indicates the dissipating stage of the\nthunderstorm.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What single reference contains information regarding volcanic eruption, that\noccurring or expected to occur?\n",
        "answer": "In-Flight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Terminal Area Forecasts (TAF).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Weather Depiction Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clouds, fog, or dew will always form when\n",
        "answer": "water vapor condenses.\n",
        "choiceone": "water vapor is present.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the temperature and dew point are equal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Below pressure height, each 5 degrees F of positive superheat amounts to\napproximately\n",
        "answer": "1 percent of static lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 percent of net lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 percent of gross lift.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most severe weather conditions, such as destructive winds, heavy hail, and\ntornadoes, are generally associated with\n",
        "answer": "squall lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "slow-moving warm fronts which slope above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fast-moving occluded fronts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4246A)\nAn aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the\npressure surface of the constant pressure chart. Which of the following statements is\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "Wind speed over B is higher than over Paris\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over A\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed over A is higher than over B\n",
        "choicethree": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over Paris\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under anticyclone conditions in the northern hemisphere, with curved isobars the\nspeed of the gradient wind is\n",
        "answer": "greater than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choiceone": "less than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as the thermal component\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional only to the Coriolis force\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When in summer calm and clear conditions exist, a station on the shore of a large body\nof water will experience wind\n",
        "answer": "from the water in daytime and from the land at night\n",
        "choiceone": "continually from land to water\n",
        "choicetwo": "continually from water to the land\n",
        "choicethree": "from the land in daytime and from the water at night\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sea breezes are most likely to occur when\n",
        "answer": "slack pressure gradient and clear skies result in relatively high land temperatures\n",
        "choiceone": "a strong pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions\npersist\n",
        "choicetwo": "a strong pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and clear skies at night\nexist\n",
        "choicethree": "a slack pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions\npersist\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus often is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level\n",
        "choiceone": "poor visibility at surface\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions below the cloud level\n",
        "choicethree": "a high risk of thunderstorms\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer in which the temperature remains constant with height is\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally unstable\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The arctic front is the boundary between:\n",
        "answer": "polar air and arctic air.\n",
        "choiceone": "polar air and tropical air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold polar air and less cold polar air.\n",
        "choicethree": "arctic air and tropical air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a possible consequence of subsidence?\n",
        "answer": "An inversion over a large area with haze, mist.\n",
        "choiceone": "CB-clouds and thunderstorms over a large area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wide spread NS and AS clouds and intense precipitation.\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear air turbulence at higher altitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the following weather messagerepresent?\nEDDM 241200Z 241322 VRBO3KT 1500 BR OVC004 BECMG 1517 00000KT 0500 FG\nVV002 TEMPO 2022 0400 FG Vv001=\n",
        "answer": "9 hour TAF.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 hour TAF.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SPECI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the following METAR:\n\nEDDM 250850Z 33005KT 2000 R26R/P1500N R26L/1500N BR SCT002 OVC003 05/05\nQ1025 NOSIG=\n\nWhich of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Visibility is reduced by water droplets\n",
        "choiceone": "There is a distinct change in RVR observed\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway 26R and runway 26L have the same RVR\n",
        "choicethree": "RVR on runway 26R is increasing\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station originating the following weather report has a field elevation of 1,300 feet\nMSL. From the bottom of the overcast cloud layer, whatis its thickness? (tops of OVC\nare reported at 3800 feet)|SPECI KOKC 22282 28024G36KT 3/4SM BKNO08 OVC020\n\n28/23 A3000\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative\nto ISA) are expected for a flight over TUS at FL 270?\n",
        "answer": "010 degrees true; 5 knots; ISA +13 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "347 degrees magnetic; 5 knots; ISA -1 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "350 degrees true; 5 knots; ISA +5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What temperature con\naltitude?\n\nindicated if wet snow is encountered at your flight\n",
        "answer": "The temperature is above freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature is below freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You are flying from a warm air mass into a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What flight planning information can a pilot derive from constant pressure charts?\n",
        "answer": "Winds and temperatures aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clear air turbulence and icing conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Levels of widespread cloud coverage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Atmospheric pressure changes due to a thunderstorm will be at the lowest value\n",
        "answer": "when the thunderstorm is approaching.\n",
        "choiceone": "during the downdraft and heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "immediately after the rain showers have stopped.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the use of airborne weather-avoidance radar for the recog!\nof certain weather conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "The radarscope provides no assurance of avoiding instrument weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "The avoidance of hail is assured when flying between and just clear of the most\nintense echoes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The clear area between intense echoes indicates that visual sighting of storms can\nbe maintained when flying between the echoes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes slight, rapid, and somewhat\nrhythmic bumpiness without appreciable changes in attitude or altitude, less than one-\nthird of the time?\n",
        "answer": "Occasional light chop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate chop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type cloud is associated with violent turbulence and a tendency toward the\nproduction of funnel clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus mamma.\n",
        "choiceone": "Standing lenticular.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of jetstream can be expected to cause the greater turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "A curving jetstream associated with a deep low-pressure trough.\n",
        "choiceone": "A straight jetstream associated with a low-pressure trough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A jetstream occurring during the summer at the lower latitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which values are used for winds aloft forecasts?\n",
        "answer": "True direction and knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic direction and knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Magnetic direction and MPH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection fog has drifted over a coastal airport during the day. What may tend to\ndissipate or lift this fog into low stratus clouds?\n",
        "answer": "Wind 15 knots or stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nighttime cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which precipitation type normally indicates freezing rain at higher altitudes?\n",
        "answer": "Ice pellets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hail.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A situation most conducive to the formation of advection fog is\n",
        "answer": "an air mass moving inland from the coastline during the winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a light breeze moving colder air over a water surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a warm, moist air mass settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which atmospheric factor causes rapid movement of surface fronts?\n",
        "answer": "Upper winds blowing across the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upper low located directly over the surface low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The cold front overtaking and lifting the warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding high- or low-pressure systems?\n",
        "answer": "A low-pressure area or trough is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Both high- and low-pressure areas are characterized by descending air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 6.) At the 0900 hours sounding and the line plotted from the surface to\n10,000 feet, what temperature must exist at the surface for instability to take place\nbetween these altitudes? Any temperature\n",
        "answer": "more than 68 degrees F.\n",
        "choiceone": "less than 68 degrees F.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less than 43 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type service should normally be expected from an En Route Flight Advisory\nService?\n",
        "answer": "Weather advisories pertinent to the type of flight, intended route of flight, and\naltitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe weather information, changes in flight plans, and receipt of position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar vectors for traffic separation, route weather advisories, and altimeter settings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What causes surface winds to flow across the isobars at an angle rather than parallel to\nthe isobars?\n",
        "answer": "Surface friction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The greater density of the air at the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition produces weather on the lee side of a large lake?\n",
        "answer": "Warm air flowing over a colder lake may produce fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air flowing over a warmer lake may produce advection fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm air flowing over a cool lake may produce rain showers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actior\nturbulence?\n\nrecommended regarding an altitude change to get out of jetstream\n",
        "answer": "Descend if ambient temperature is falling.\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend if ambient temperature is rising.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Maintain altitude if ambient temperature is not changing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather conditions should be expected beneath a low-level temperature\ninversion layer when the relative humidity is high?\n\n",
        "answer": "Smooth air and poor visibility due to fog, haze, or low clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light wind shear and poor visibility due to haze and light rain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulent air and poor visibility due to fog, low stratus-type clouds, and showery\nprecipitation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding actual air temperature and dewpoint temperature spread? The\ntemperature spread\n",
        "answer": "decreases as the relative humidity increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases as the relative humidity decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases as the relative humidity increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is a body of air that\n",
        "answer": "covers an extensive area and has fairly uniform properties of temperature and\nmoisture.\n",
        "choiceone": "has similar cloud formations associated with it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "creates a wind shift as it moves across the Earth's surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To best determine observed weather conditions between weather reporting stations,\nthe pilot should refer to\n",
        "answer": "pilot reports.\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prognostic charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average height of the troposphere in the middle latitudes is\n",
        "answer": "37,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "20,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements applies to the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "It separates the troposphere from the stratosphere\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis, by definition, an isothermal layer\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates a strong temperature lapse rate\n",
        "choicethree": "Itis, by definition, a temperature inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under anticyclone conditions in the northern hemisphere, with curved isobars the\nspeed of the gradient wind is\n",
        "answer": "greater than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choiceone": "less than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as the thermal component\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional only to the Coriolis force\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4246A)\nAn aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the\npressure surface of the constant pressure chart. Which of the following statements is\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "Wind speed over B is higher than over Paris\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over A\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed over A is higher than over B\n",
        "choicethree": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over Paris\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying in the southern hemisphere at 2000 feet, has to turn to the right in order\nto allow for drift. In which direction, relative to the track of the aircraft, is the centre of\nlow pressure ?\n",
        "answer": "In front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Behind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the left.\n",
        "choicethree": "To the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dry adiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "answer": "has a constant fixed value\n",
        "choiceone": "is greater in summer than in winter\n",
        "choicetwo": "is greater during the night than during the day\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases with increasing temperature\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing fog exists if fog droplets\n",
        "answer": "are supercooled\n",
        "choiceone": "are frozen\n",
        "choicetwo": "are freezing very rapidly\n",
        "choicethree": "freeze when temperature falls below zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of weather can usually be expected in a polar maritime air mass over Central\nEurope in the daytime during summer?\n",
        "answer": "Showers and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous rain and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Drizzle and low stratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sky clear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4297A)\nOn which one of the tracks (dashed lines) is this cross-section to be expected?\n",
        "answer": "Track B-D\n",
        "choiceone": "Track B-C\n",
        "choicetwo": "Track A-D\n",
        "choicethree": "Track A-E\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-2388A)\nWhat wind direction will occur at point B?\n",
        "answer": "Southwest\n",
        "choiceone": "East\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southeast\n",
        "choicethree": "Northwest\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Subsidence is:\n",
        "answer": "a downward air flow\n",
        "choiceone": "a horizontal air flow\n",
        "choicetwo": "an upward air flow\n",
        "choicethree": "the same as convection\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which METAR report suggests that a thunderstorm is likely in the next few hours?\n",
        "answer": "201350Z 21005KT 9999 SCTO40CB SCT100 26/18 Q1016 TEMPO 24018G30KT TS=\n",
        "choiceone": "201350Z 16004KT 8000 SCT110 OVC220 02/M02 Q1008 NOSIG=\n",
        "choicetwo": "201350Z 34003KT 0800 SN VV002 M02/M04 Q1014 NOSIG=\n",
        "choicethree": "201350Z 04012KT 3000 BR OVC012 04/03 Q1022 BECMG 6000=\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following messages should be cancelled when the conditions are no\nlonger occurring or no longer expected to occur?\n",
        "answer": "Aerodrome warning\n",
        "choiceone": "Trend forecast\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) At which time is IFR weather first predicted at Lubbock (KLBB)?\n",
        "answer": "0100Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "2100Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0400Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding ridge soaring with the wind direction perpendicular to the\nridge?\n",
        "answer": "If the glider drifts downwind from the ridge and sinks slightly lower than the crest of\nthe ridge, the glider should be turned away from the ridge and a high speed attained.\n",
        "choiceone": "When very close to the surface of the ridge, the glider's speed should be reduced to\nthe minimum sink speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the wind and lift are very strong on the windward side of the ridge, a weak sink\ncondition will exist on the leeward side.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which information section is contained in the Aviation Area Forecast (FA)?\n",
        "answer": "VFR Clouds and Weather (VFR CLDS/WX).\n",
        "choiceone": "Winds aloft, speed and direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In-Flight Aviation Weather Advisories.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition does advection fog usually form?\n",
        "answer": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm, moist air settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A land breeze blowing a cold air mass over a warm water current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by the Special METAR weather observation for KBOI?|SPECI KBOI\n091854Z 32005KT 1 1/2SM RA BR OVC007 17/16 A2990 RMK RAB12\n",
        "answer": "Rain and mist obstructing visibility; rain began at 1812Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rain and fog obscuring two-tenths of the sky; rain began at 1912Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain and overcast at 1200 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFSS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an operational consideration if you fly into rain which freezes on impact?\n",
        "answer": "Temperatures are above freezing at some higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "You have flown into an area of thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You have flown through a cold front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-on-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1,200 feet AGL). Whatis the in flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operations during daylight hours for the circle 1 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four families of clouds?\n",
        "answer": "High, middle, low, and those with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus, cumulus, nimbus, and cirrus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds formed by updrafts, fronts, cooling layers of air, and precipitation into warm\nair.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the characteristics of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Poor visibility, steady precipitation, and stratus-type clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Good visibility, steady precipitation, and stratus-type clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Poor visibility, intermittent precipitation, and cumulus-type clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The general circulation of\nHemisphere is\n\nassociated with a high-pressure area in the Northern\n",
        "answer": "outward, downward, and clockwise.\n",
        "choiceone": "outward, upward, and clockwise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "inward, downward, and clockwise.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an effect of ice, snow, or frost formation on an airplane?\n",
        "answer": "Increased stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increased pitchdown tendencies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increased angle of attack for stalls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of low-level wind shear as it relates to frontal activity?\n",
        "answer": "With a warm front, the most critical period is before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "With a cold front, the most critical period is just before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence will always exist in wind-shear conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anti-icing fluid should provide freezing point protection to\n",
        "answer": "a freezing point no greater than 20 degrees F below the ambient or airplane surface\ntemperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "-20 degrees F ambient temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "+32 degrees F outside temperature or below.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which feature is associated with the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "Abrupt change of temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Absence of wind and turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Absolute upper limit of cloud formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of the cloud is at its maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Surface Analysis Chart, close spacing of the isobars indicates\n",
        "answer": "strong pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "weak pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong temperature gradient.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the single source reference that contains information regarding volcanic\neruption, turbulence, and icing conditions for a specific region?\n",
        "answer": "In-Flight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weather Depiction Chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Area Forecast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does wind shear occur?\n",
        "answer": "With either a wind shift or a wind speed gradient at any level in the atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": ":xclusively in thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wherever there is an abrupt decrease in pressure and/or temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what ways do advection fog, radiation fog, and steam fog differ in their formation or\nlocation?\n",
        "answer": "Radiation fog is restricted to land areas; advection fog is most common along\ncoastal areas; steam fog forms over a water surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advection fog deepens as windspeed increases up to 20 knots; steam fog requires\ncalm or very light wind; radiation fog forms when the ground or water cools the air\nby radiation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steam fog forms from moist air moving over a colder surface; advection fog requires\ncold air over a warmer surface; radiation fog is produced by radiational cooling of\nthe ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum forecast period for AIRMETs?\n",
        "answer": "Six hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four hours.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is generally true when comparing the rate of vertical motion of updrafts with that\nof downdrafts associated with thermals?\n",
        "answer": "Downdrafts have a slower rate of vertical motion than do updrafts.\n",
        "choiceone": "Updrafts and downdrafts move vertically at the same rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Updrafts have a slower rate of vertical motion than do downdrafts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAF) are issued how many times a day and cover what\nperiod of time?\n",
        "answer": "Four times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period.\n",
        "choiceone": "Six times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period including a 4-hour\ncategorical outlook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four times daily and are valid for 12 hours including a 6-hour categorical outlook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather difference is found on each side of a \u2018dry line\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Dewpoint difference.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extreme temperature difference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratus versus cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The strength and location of the jet stream is normally\n",
        "answer": "weaker and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "stronger and farther north in the winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stronger and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an STL MEM MSY\nflight at FL 330?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind shift from west to north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature increase 5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight over the sea at FL 135, the true altitude is 13500 feet; local QNH is 1019\nhPa. What information, if any, can be gained about the air mass in which the aircraft is\nflying?\n",
        "answer": "Itis colder than ISA\n",
        "choiceone": "Its average temperature is the same as ISA\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is warmer than ISA\n",
        "choicethree": "There is insufficient information to make any assumption\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sea breeze is a wind\n",
        "answer": "occurring only in the lower layers of the atmosphere in daytime\n",
        "choiceone": "that reaches up to the tropopause in daytime\n",
        "choicetwo": "blowing at night in mid-latitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "occurring only in mid-latitudes and in daytime\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Of what does lenticular cloud provide evidence?\n",
        "answer": "Mountain waves\n",
        "choiceone": "Jet streams\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratospheric inversions\n",
        "choicethree": "Areas of high level clear air turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following changes of state is latent heat absorbed?\n",
        "answer": "Solid to liquid\n",
        "choiceone": "Liquid to solid\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gas to solid\n",
        "choicethree": "Gas to liquid\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "About ten identical clouds are in the sky, well isolated from one another, dense, with\nwell defined contours, developing vertically in a cauliflower shape. The side of these\nclouds lit by the sun is bright white. Their base, relatively dark, is essentially horizontal\nand at FL 30, and their tops at FL 150. These clouds are\n",
        "answer": "towering Cumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "broken Cumulus humilis\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus castellanus\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratocumulus\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of morning fog before sunrise is possible if\n",
        "answer": "air temperature and dew point are equal or close to one another\n",
        "choiceone": "the wind is strong\n",
        "choicetwo": "the sky is overcast\n",
        "choicethree": "the turbulence in the lower layers is moderate\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of weather can usually be expected in a polar maritime air mass over Central\nEurope in the daytime during summer?\n",
        "answer": "Showers and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous rain and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Drizzle and low stratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sky clear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10845A)\nFor an aircraft at FL 40, approaching the front (square 3C) from the direction of square\n3D a potential hazard exists before reaching the front in the form of\n",
        "answer": "clear ice accretion to the airframe\n",
        "choiceone": "severe turbulence associated with CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence and wind shear\n",
        "choicethree": "severe downdrafts from subsiding air\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If clouds form as a result of very stable, moist air being forced to ascend a mountain\nslope, the clouds will be\n",
        "answer": "stratus type with little vertical development and little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "cirrus type with no vertical development or turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cumulus type with considerable vertical development and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "RB\" wind entry in a Terminal Aerodome Forecast (TAF) will be\nwind is\n",
        "answer": "3 knots or less.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 knots or less.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 knots or less.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary cause of all changes in the Earth's weather is\n",
        "answer": "variation of solar energy received by the Earth's regions.\n",
        "choiceone": "changes in air pressure over the Earth's surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "movement of the air masses.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFSS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KMAF 131756Z 02020KT 12SM BKN025 OVC250 27/18 A3009 RMK RAE44.\n\n|Which weather condition is indicated by this METAR report at Midland (KMAF)?\n",
        "answer": "Rain of unknown intensity ended 16 minutes before the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling was at 25,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind was 020 degrees magnetic at 20 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement pertaining to the following Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) is true?\n|TAF|KMEM 091135Z 0915 15005KT 5SM HZ BKNO60|FM1600 VRBO4KT P6SM SKC\n",
        "answer": "SKC in the valid period indicates no significant weather and sky clear.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind in the valid period implies surface winds are forecast to be greater than 5 KTS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction is from 160__degrees__ at 4 KTS and reported vi\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What type of report is listed for Lubbock (KLBB) at 18182?\n",
        "answer": "A Special METAR weather observation, concerning significant weather changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "An Aviation selected special weather report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A special report concerning very low station pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) The chart symbols over southern California on the 12-Hour\n\nSignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicate\n",
        "answer": "pected top of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u2018pected base of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "light turbulence expected above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The remarks section of the Aviation Routine Weather Report (METAR) contains the\nfollowing coded information. What does it mean?/|RMK FZDZB42 WSHFT 30 FROPA\n",
        "answer": "Wind shift at three zero due to frontal passage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing drizzle with cloud bases below 4,200 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Freezing drizzle below 4,200 feet and wind shear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions result in the formation of frost?\n",
        "answer": "Temperature of the collecting surface is below the dewpoint of surrounding air and\nthe dewpoint is colder than freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature of the collecting surface is at or below freezing and small droplets\nof moisture are falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When dew forms and the temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Surface Analysis Chart, close spacing of the isobars indicates\n",
        "answer": "strong pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "weak pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong temperature gradient.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absence of the sky condition and visibility on an ATIS broadcast specifically\nthat\n\n",
        "answer": "the ceiling is more than 5,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sky condition is clear and visibility is unrestricted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the ceiling is at least 3,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the requirements for the formation of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Sufficient moisture, an unstable lapse rate, and a lifting action.\n",
        "choiceone": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture and an inverted lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which forecast provides specific information concerning expected sky cover, cloud\ntops, visibility, weather, and obstructions to vision in a route format?\n",
        "answer": "Transcribed Weather Broadcast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Area Forecast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Terminal Forecast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vertical wind shear can be determined directly from the dashed lines on the tropopause\ndata chart. The vertical wind shear that is critical for probability of turbulence is\n",
        "answer": "6 knots or more per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 knots or greater per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater than 8 knots per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "Itis an atmospheric condition that may be associated with a low-level temperature\ninversion, a jet stream, or a frontal zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis an atmospheric condition that is associated exclusively with zones of\nconvergence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Coriolis phenomenon in both high- and low-level air masses is the principal\ngenerating force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the contraction VRB in the Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) mean?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction is variable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed is variable throughout the period.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloud base is variable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) of P6SM implies that the\nprevailing visibility is expected to be greater than\n",
        "answer": "6 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 nautical miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 kilometers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed aloft are forecast by this WINDS AND TEMPERATURE\nALOFT FORECAST (FD) for FL390 - '731960\u00b0?\n",
        "answer": "230 degrees at 119 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "131 degrees at 96 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "073 degrees at 196 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What temperature con\naltitude?\n\nindicated if wet snow is encountered at your flight\n",
        "answer": "The temperature is above freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature is below freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You are flying from a warm air mass into a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "It may be associated with either a wind shift or a wind speed gradient at any level in\nthe atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is primarily associated with the lateral vortices generated by thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It usually exists only in the vicinity of thunderstorms, but may be found near a strong\ntemperature inversion.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Dallas (KDAL)?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter setting is 30.07.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tops of the overcast is 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature/dewpoint spread is 8 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The body of a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) covers a geographical proximity\nwithin a\n",
        "answer": "5 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 nautical mile radius of the center of an airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 to 10 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SPECI KGLS 131802Z 10012G21KT 060V140 2SM +SHRA SCT005 BKN035 OVC050CB\n24/23 A2980 RMK RAB\u00a77 WS TKO RWOSL WSHFT 58 FROPA. This SPECI report at\nGalveston (KGLS) indicates which condition?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation started at 57 after the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind steady at 100 degree magnetic at 12 knots, gusts to 21.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet overcast with towering cumulus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 6.) At the soundings taken at 1400 hours, is the atmosphere stable or\nunstable and at what altitudes?\n",
        "answer": "Stable from 10,000 to 13,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stable from 6,000 to 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Unstable from 10,000 to 13,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station originating the following METAR observation has a field elevation of 3,500\nfeet MSL. If the sky cover is one continuous layer, what is the thickness of the cloud\nlayer? (Top of overcast reported at 7,500 feet MSL).|METAR KHOB 151250Z 17006KT\n4SM OVCO05 13/11 A2998\n",
        "answer": "3,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of center of gravity on the spin characteristics of an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A flat spin may develop if the CG is too far aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the CG is too far forward, spin entry will be difficult.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If the CG is too far aft, spins can become high-speed spirals.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the winds at 2,000 feet above the surface and the\nsurface winds?\n",
        "answer": "The winds at 2,000 feet tend to parallel the isobars while the surface winds cross the\nisobars at an angle toward lower pressure and are weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "The winds at 2,000 feet and the surface winds flow in the same direction, but the\nsurface winds are weaker due to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface winds tend to veer to the right of the winds at 2,000 feet and are usually\nweaker.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the terms PROB40 2102 +TSRA as used in a Terminal\nAerodrome Forecasts (TAF)?\n",
        "answer": "Between 2100Z and 02002 there is a forty percent (40%) probability of thunderstorms\nwith heavy rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Probability of heavy thunderstorms with rain showers below 4000 feet at time 2102.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Beginning at 21022 forty percent (40%) probability of heavy thunderstorms and rain\nshowers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will an area of thunderstorm activity, that may grow to severe intensity, be\nindicated on the Severe Weather Outlook Chart?\n",
        "answer": "APCHG within any area.\n",
        "choiceone": "SLGT within cross-hatched areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SVR within any area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In-Flight Aviation Weather Advisories include what type of information?\n",
        "answer": "Forecasts for potentially hazardous flying conditions for enroute aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "State and geographic areas with reported ceilings and visibilities below VFR\nminimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions, turbulence, and icing within a valid period for the listed states.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which forces are balanced in case of geostrophic winds?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure gradient force, Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "Friction force, pressure gradient force, Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure gradient force, Coriolis force, centrifugal force.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pressure gradient force, centrifugal force, friction force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10722A)\nAssuming a generalised zonal system of world climatic and wind circulation, zone \"\nan area of\n\n",
        "answer": "subtropical high pressure systems\n",
        "choiceone": "SE trade winds\n",
        "choicetwo": "travelling low pressure systems\n",
        "choicethree": "NE trade winds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dry adiabatic lapse rate\n",
        "answer": "has a constant fixed value\n",
        "choiceone": "is greater in summer than in winter\n",
        "choicetwo": "is greater during the night than during the day\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases with increasing temperature\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms suddenly by day but not by night\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is formed when the air is unstable\n",
        "choicethree": "It develops slowly and dissipates rapidly\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical zero degree isotherm is\n",
        "answer": "16000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "12000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "19000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10798A)\nThe dotted line labelled \"Y\" represents the\n",
        "answer": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone during January\n",
        "choiceone": "axis of the subtropical jet stream during January\n",
        "choicetwo": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone during July\n",
        "choicethree": "axis of the equatorial jet stream during July\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL)\nduring daylight hours for the circle 2 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high cloud is composed mostly of\n",
        "answer": "ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "ozone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "condensation nuclei.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated if ice pellets are encountered at 8,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain at higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "You are approaching an area of thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You will encounter hail if you continue your flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which would increase the stability of an air mass?\n",
        "answer": "Cooling from below.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warming from below.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decrease in water vapor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf a temperature inversion is encountered immediately after takeoff or during an\napproach to a landing, a potential hazard exists due to\n",
        "answer": "wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong surface winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong convective currents.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the stability of the atmosphere be determined?\n",
        "answer": "Ambient temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Atmospheric pressure at various levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface temperature/dewpoint spread.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of standing lenticular altocumulus clouds is a good indication of\n",
        "answer": "very strong turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "lenticular ice formatiot\n",
        "choicetwo": "heavy icing conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A thermal column is rising from an asphalt parking lot and the wind is from the south at\n12 knots. Which statement would be true?\n",
        "answer": "As altitude is gained, the center of the thermal will be found farther north of the\nparking lot.\n",
        "choiceone": "As altitude is gained, the best lift will be found directly above the parking lot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The slowest rate of sink would be close to the thermal and the fastest rate of sink\nfarther from it.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 152.) What weather conditions are depicted in the area\narrow B on the Radar Summary Chart?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weak to moderate echoes; rain showers increasing in intensity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weak echoes; heavy rain showers; area movement toward the southeast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Strong echoes; moderate rain showers; no cell movement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When total sky cover is few or scattered, the height shown on the Weather Depiction\nChartis the\n",
        "answer": "base of the lowest layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "top of the lowest layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "base of the highest layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steady precipitation, in contrast to showers, preceding a front is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "stratiform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratiform clouds with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cummuliform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an approach, the most important and most easily recognized means of being\nalerted to possible wind shear is monitoring the\n",
        "answer": "power and vertical velocity required to remain on the proper glidepath.\n",
        "choiceone": "amount of trim required to relieve control pressures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "heading changes necessary to remain on the runway centerline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moisture is added to a parcel of air by\n",
        "answer": "evaporation and sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "sublimation and condensation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evaporation and condensation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the cumulus stage of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Beginning of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frequent lightning.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A characteristic of the stratosphere is\n",
        "answer": "relatively small changes in temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "an overall decrease of temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a relatively even base altitude of approximately 35,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) What type con\nland at San Angelo (KSJT) at 15002?\n\nions can be expected for a flight scheduled to\n",
        "answer": "IFR conditions due to low visibility, rain, and mist.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chance of 1 statute mile visibility and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions due to low ceilings, rain, and fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Surface Analysis Chart, close spacing of the isobars indicates\n",
        "answer": "strong pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "weak pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong temperature gradient.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "Itis an atmospheric condition that may be associated with a low-level temperature\ninversion, a jet stream, or a frontal zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis an atmospheric condition that is associated exclusively with zones of\nconvergence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Coriolis phenomenon in both high- and low-level air masses is the principal\ngenerating force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reporting station originating this Aviation Routine Weather Report has a field\nelevation of 620 feet. If the reported sky cover is one continuous layer, what is its\nthickness? (tops of OVC are reported at 6500 feet)|METAR KMDW 121856Z AUTO\n32005KT 1 1/2SM +RABR OVCO07 17/16 A2980\n",
        "answer": "5,180 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5,800 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,880 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Behind a stationary front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The strength and location of the jet stream is normally\n",
        "answer": "weaker and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "stronger and farther north in the winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stronger and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud types would indicate convective turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nimbostratus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a difference between an air mass thunderstorm and a steady-state\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Air mass thunderstorm downdrafts and precipitation retard and reverse the updrafts.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air mass thunderstorms produce precipitation which falls outside of the updraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steady-state thunderstorms are associated with local surface heating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the use of airborne weather-avoidance radar for the recog!\nof certain weather conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "The radarscope provides no assurance of avoiding instrument weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "The avoidance of hail is assured when flying between and just clear of the most\nintense echoes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The clear area between intense echoes indicates that visual sighting of storms can\nbe maintained when flying between the echoes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thunderstorms generally produce the most severe conditions, such as heavy hi\nand destructive winds?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning an isothermal layer in the atmosphere\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "An isothermal layer is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air parcels that are forced to rise through an isothermal layer keep the same\ntemperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The vertical temperature gradient lies between the dry and saturated adiabatic lapse\nrates.\n",
        "choicethree": "An isothermal layer is formed when the air in the layer is well mixed by turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4248A)\nAn aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the\npressure surface of the constant pressure chart. Which of the following statements is\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over A\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher over A than over B\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed over Madrid is higher than over A\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind speed over B is higher than over A\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying in the southern hemisphere at 2000 feet, has to turn to the right in order\nto allow for drift. In which direction, relative to the track of the aircraft, is the centre of\nlow pressure ?\n",
        "answer": "In front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Behind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the left.\n",
        "choicethree": "To the right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal fog is most likely to occur\n",
        "answer": "in advance of a warm front\n",
        "choiceone": "in rear of a warm front\n",
        "choicetwo": "in summer in the early morning\n",
        "choicethree": "in winter in the early morning\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass which originates over the North Atlantic between 50 and 70 degrees north\nand is moving in over Scandinavia is called\n",
        "answer": "maritime polar air.\n",
        "choiceone": "continental arctic air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maritime arctic air.\n",
        "choicethree": "continental polar air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10845A)\nFor an aircraft at FL 40, approaching the front (square 3C) from the direction of square\n3D a potential hazard exists before reaching the front in the form of\n",
        "answer": "clear ice accretion to the airframe\n",
        "choiceone": "severe turbulence associated with CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence and wind shear\n",
        "choicethree": "severe downdrafts from subsiding air\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stationary front is a front in which:\n",
        "answer": "there is no horizontal motion perpendicular to the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "there is no difference in temperature between the two air masses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is no wind on both sides of the front.\n",
        "choicethree": "there are never frontal clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a downburst?\n",
        "answer": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a lower temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a higher temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An extremely strong wind gust in a tropical revolving storm.\n",
        "choicethree": "A small low pressure system where the wind circulates with very high speeds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are necessary for vertical visibility to be reported?\n",
        "answer": "When sky obscured by heavy precipitation and cloud base cannot be measured.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis always reported.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Whenever the lowest ceiling is below 1500 ft above ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "Whenever the lowest cloud base is below 1500 ft above ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the development of convective circulation?\n",
        "answer": "Cool air must sink to force the warm air upward.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm air is less dense and rises on its own accord.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warmer air covers a larger surface area than the cool air; therefore, the warmer air is\nless dense and rises.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anti-icing fluid should provide freezing point protection to\n",
        "answer": "a freezing point no greater than 20 degrees F below the ambient or airplane surface\ntemperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "-20 degrees F ambient temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "+32 degrees F outside temperature or below.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type precipitation is an indication that supercooled water is present?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wet snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ice pellets.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the stability of the atmosphere be determined?\n",
        "answer": "Ambient temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Atmospheric pressure at various levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface temperature/dewpoint spread.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wind shear forecast in the following TAF?|TAF|KCVG 231051Z 231212\n12012KT 4SM -RA BR OVC008|/WS005/27050KT TEMPO 1719 1/2SM -RA FG|FM1930\n09012KT 1SM -DZ BR VV003 BECMG 2021 5SM HZ=\n",
        "answer": "500 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is most appropriate when an envelope over-temperature condition occurs?\n",
        "answer": "Land as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and allow envelope to cool before landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Throw all unnecessary equipment overboard in order to lighten the load.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In-Flight Aviation Weather Advisories include what type of information?\n",
        "answer": "Forecasts for potentially hazardous flying conditions for enroute aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "State and geographic areas with reported ceilings and visibilities below VFR\nminimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions, turbulence, and icing within a valid period for the listed states.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated if ice pellets are encountered at 8,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain at higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "You are approaching an area of thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You will encounter hail if you continue your flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What determines the structure or type of clouds which will form as a result of air being\nforced to ascend?\n",
        "answer": "The stability of the air before lifting occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "The method by which the air is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The relative humidity of the air after lifting occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "icated on the Weather Depiction Chart by a continuous smooth line\nenclosing a hatched geographic area?\n",
        "answer": "Reporting stations within the enclosed area are all showing IFR conditions at the\ntime of the report.\n",
        "choiceone": "The entire area has ceilings less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 50 percent of the area enclosed by the smooth line is predicted to have\nIFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which primary source contains information regarding the expected weather at the\ndestination airport, at the ETA?\n",
        "answer": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low-Level Prog Chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar Summary and Weather Depiction Charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is provided by a Convective Outlook (AC)?\n",
        "answer": "It provides prospects of both general and severe thunderstorm activity during the\nfollowing 24 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "It describes areas of probable severe icing and severe or extreme turbulence during\nthe next 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates areas of probable convective turbulence and the extent of instability in\nthe upper atmosphere (above 500 mb).\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the maximum hazard zone caused by wind shear associated with a\nthunderstorm be found?\n",
        "answer": "On all sides and directly under the thunderstorm cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the southwest side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ahead of the roll cloud or gust front and directly under the anvil cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What visible signs indicate extreme turbulence in thunderstorms?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus clouds, very frequent lightning, and roll clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Base of the clouds near the surface, heavy rain, and hail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low ceiling and visibility, hail, and precipitation static.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type weather conditions are covered in the Convective SIGMET?\n",
        "answer": "Embedded thunderstorms, lines of thunderstorms, and thunderstorms with 3/4-inch\nhail or tornadoes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus clouds with tops above the tropopause and thunderstorms with 1/2-\ninch hail or funnel clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any thunderstorm with a severity level of VIP 2 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapor which air can hold largely depends on\n",
        "answer": "air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability of air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which meteorological environment\nhighest rate of accumulation?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High humidity and freezing temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in the\ncircle 6 area?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix 'nimbus\u2019, used in naming clouds, means a\n",
        "answer": "rain cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "cloud with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dark massive, towering cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What type of report is listed for Lubbock (KLBB) at 18182?\n",
        "answer": "A Special METAR weather observation, concerning significant weather changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "An Aviation selected special weather report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A special report concerning very low station pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is frost considered hazardous to flight operation?\n",
        "answer": "Frost causes early airflow separation resulting in a loss of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost changes the basic aerodynamic shape of the airfoil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frost decreases control effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The body of a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) covers a geographical proximity\nwithin a\n",
        "answer": "5 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 nautical mile radius of the center of an airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 to 10 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A characteristic of the stratosphere is\n",
        "answer": "relatively small changes in temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "an overall decrease of temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a relatively even base altitude of approximately 35,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conclusion(s) can be drawn from a 500-millibar Constant Pressure Chart for a\nplanned flight at FL 180?\n",
        "answer": "Observed temperature, wind, and temperature/dewpoint spread along the proposed\nroute can be approximated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Winds aloft at FL 180 generally flow across the height contours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upper highs, lows, troughs, and ridges will be depicted by the use of lines of equal\npressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum altitude an airship can reach under any given atmospheric condition and\nreturn safely to the surface is determined by\n",
        "answer": "ballonet capacity.\n",
        "choiceone": "the disposable weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ballonet capacity and disposable weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sea breeze is a wind\n",
        "answer": "occurring only in the lower layers of the atmosphere in daytime\n",
        "choiceone": "that reaches up to the tropopause in daytime\n",
        "choicetwo": "blowing at night in mid-latitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "occurring only in mid-latitudes and in daytime\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A katabatic wind blows\n",
        "answer": "down the slope during the night.\n",
        "choiceone": "up the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "down the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicethree": "up the slope during the night.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus often is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level\n",
        "choiceone": "poor visibility at surface\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions below the cloud level\n",
        "choicethree": "a high risk of thunderstorms\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A plain with an average elevation of 500 m (1600 ft) above sea level is covered with a\nuniform AC layer of cloud during the summer months. At what height above the ground\nis the base of this cloud to be expected?\n\n",
        "answer": "7000 - 15000\n",
        "choiceone": "100 - 1500\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 - 7000\n",
        "choicethree": "15000 - 25000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type (genus) is described by the following definition?\n\"Cumulus clouds which are markedly sprouting and are often of great vertical extent;\ntheir bulging upper part frequently resembles a cauliflower.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus capillatus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus fractus\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus humilis\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal fog is most likely to occur\n",
        "answer": "in advance of a warm front\n",
        "choiceone": "in rear of a warm front\n",
        "choicetwo": "in summer in the early morning\n",
        "choicethree": "in winter in the early morning\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favours the development of orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "High relative humidity\n",
        "choiceone": "Absolutely unstable air\n",
        "choicetwo": "Katabatic winds\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear nights\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air masses that are observed most frequently over Western Europe are:\n",
        "answer": "polar air and tropical air.\n",
        "choiceone": "arctic air and polar air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "polar air and equatorial air.\n",
        "choicethree": "arctic air and tropical air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10766A)\nThe weather most likely to be experienced at position \"S\" is\n",
        "answer": "overcast with drizzle and orographic fog\n",
        "choiceone": "scattered thunderstorms and good visibility\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing AS and NS with moderate to heavy rain\n",
        "choicethree": "small amounts of CU with generally good visibility\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sets of con\nthunderstorms?\n\nions are most favourable to the development of\n",
        "answer": "Environmental lapse rate greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate through a great\nvertical extent, high relative humidity and an initial lifting process\n",
        "choiceone": "Extensive isothermal layer, ice particles and water droplets must exist just below the\nfreezing level and orographic lifting\n",
        "choicetwo": "Environmental lapse rate less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate with dew point\nbelow 0\u00b0C and considerable surface heating\n",
        "choicethree": "Environmental lapse rate less than dry adiabatic lapse rate with freezing level below\nthe cloud base, high relative humidity and strong surface winds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stage of thunderstorm development are rotor winds characterized by roll\nclouds most likely to occur ?\n",
        "answer": "Mature stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dissipating stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus stage and mature stage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the colours with which a stationary front is shown on a surface chart?\n",
        "answer": "Red and blue\n",
        "choiceone": "Violet and red\n",
        "choicetwo": "Red and green\n",
        "choicethree": "Blue and violet\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interprete this METAR ?\n\n00000KT 0200 R14/0800U R16/P1500U FZFG VV001 m03/m03 Q1022 BECMG 0800=\n",
        "answer": "RVR for runway 14 800 metres, vertical visibility 100 feet, calm, visibility improving to\n800 metres in the next 2 hours\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 200 metres, RVR for runway 16 1500 metres, temperature -3\u00b0C, vertical\nvisibility 100 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 200 feet, RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres, vertical visibility 100\nfeet, fog with hoar frost\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility for runway 14 800 metres, fog with hoar frost, RVR for runway 16 more than\n1500 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which precipitation type normally indicates freezing rain at higher altitudes?\n",
        "answer": "Ice pellets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hail.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most dangerous features of mountain waves is the turbulent areas in and\n",
        "answer": "below rotor clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "above rotor clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below lenticular clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding actual air temperature and dewpoint temperature spread? The\ntemperature spread\n",
        "answer": "decreases as the relative humidity increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases as the relative humidity decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases as the relative humidity increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are some characteristics of unstable air?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nimbostratus clouds and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence and poor surface visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which correctly describes the purpose of convective SIGMETs (WST)?\n",
        "answer": "They consist of either an observation and a forecast or just a forecast for tornadoes,\nsignificant thunderstorm activity, or hail greater than or equal to 3/4 inch in diameter.\n",
        "choiceone": "They consist of an hourly observation of tornadoes, significant thunderstorm\nactivity, and large hailstone activity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They contain both an observation and a forecast of all thunderstorm and hailstone\nactivity. The forecast is valid for 1 hour only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which feature is associated with the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "Abrupt change of temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Absence of wind and turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Absolute upper limit of cloud formation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the use of airborne weather-avoidance radar for the recog!\nof certain weather conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "The radarscope provides no assurance of avoiding instrument weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "The avoidance of hail is assured when flying between and just clear of the most\nintense echoes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The clear area between intense echoes indicates that visual sighting of storms can\nbe maintained when flying between the echoes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What important information is provided by the Radar Summary Chart that is not shown\non other weather charts?\n",
        "answer": "Lines and cells of hazardous thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Types of precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Areas of cloud cover and icing levels within the clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SPECI KGLS 131802Z 10012G21KT 060V140 2SM +SHRA SCT005 BKN035 OVC050CB\n24/23 A2980 RMK RAB\u00a77 WS TKO RWOSL WSHFT 58 FROPA. This SPECI report at\nGalveston (KGLS) indicates which condition?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation started at 57 after the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind steady at 100 degree magnetic at 12 knots, gusts to 21.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet overcast with towering cumulus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A clear area in a line of thunderstorm echoes on a radar scope indicates\n",
        "answer": "an area where precipitation drops are not detected.\n",
        "choiceone": "the absence of clouds in the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area of no convective turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hazardous Inflight Weather Advisory Service (HIWAS) is a broadcast service over\nselected VORs that provides\n",
        "answer": "continuous broadcast of inflight weather advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "SIGMETs and AIRMETs at 15 minutes and 45 minutes past the hour for the first hour\nafter issuance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SIGMETs, CONVECTIVE SIGMETs and AIRMETs at 15 minutes and 45 minutes past\nthe hour.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The general characteristics of unstable air are\n",
        "answer": "good visibility, showery precipitation, and cumuliform-type clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "good visibility, steady precipitation, and stratiform-type clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "poor visibility, intermittent precipitation, and cumuliform-type clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of standing lenticular altocumulus clouds is a good indication of\n",
        "answer": "very strong turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "lenticular ice formatiot\n",
        "choicetwo": "heavy icing conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Strong turbulence in the cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the requirements for the formation of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Sufficient moisture, an unstable lapse rate, and a lifting action.\n",
        "choiceone": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture and an inverted lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is generally true when comparing the rate of vertical motion of updrafts with that\nof downdrafts associated with thermals?\n",
        "answer": "Downdrafts have a slower rate of vertical motion than do updrafts.\n",
        "choiceone": "Updrafts and downdrafts move vertically at the same rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Updrafts have a slower rate of vertical motion than do downdrafts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) At which time is IFR weather first predicted at Lubbock (KLBB)?\n",
        "answer": "0100Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "2100Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0400Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With respect to advection fog, which statement is true?\n",
        "answer": "It can appear suddenly during day or night, and it is more persistent than radiation\nfog.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is slow to develop, and dissipates quite rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It forms almost exclusively at night or near daybreak.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strong wind shear can be expected\n",
        "answer": "on the low pressure side of a 100-knot jetstream core.\n",
        "choiceone": "where the horizontal wind shear is 15 knots, in a distance equal to 2.5 degrees\nlongitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the 5 degrees C isotherms are spaced 100 NM or closer together.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination weather!\nshould be obtained from the\n\nformation for an instrument flight\n",
        "answer": "AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airman publications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of clouds will be formed if very stable moist air is forced up slope?\n",
        "answer": "Stratified clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "First stratified clouds and then vertical clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical clouds with increasing height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steady precipitation, in contrast to showers, preceding a front is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "stratiform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratiform clouds with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cummuliform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in VFR conditions during daylight hours\nfor the circle 4 area?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KSPS 131757Z 09014KT 6SM -RA SCT025 OVC090 24/22 A3005.|SPECI KSPS\n131820Z 01025KT 3SM +RA FC OVC015 22/21 A3000.|Which change took place at\nWichita Falls (KSPS) between 1757 and 1820 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "A funnel cloud was observed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rain became lighter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Atmospheric pressure increased.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which event usually occurs after an aircraft passes through a front into the colder air?\n",
        "answer": "Atmospheric pressure increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature/dewpoint spread decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction shifts to the left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather is predicted by the term VCTS in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are expected in the vicinity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thunderstorms may occur over the station and within 50 miles of the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are expected between 5 and 25 miles of the runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are characteristics of an unstable cold air mass moving over a warm surface?\n",
        "answer": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds, smooth air, and poor visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ice pellets encountered during flight are normally evidence that\n",
        "answer": "freezing rain exists at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicates that\nWest Virginia will likely experience\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery precipitation covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "thunderstorms and rain showers covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continuous rain covering less than half of the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the cumulus stage of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Roll cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Beginning of rain at the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4247A)\nAn aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the\npressure surface of the constant pressure chart. Which of the following statements is\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude will be higher over A than over B\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over A\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed over A is higher than over B\n",
        "choicethree": "Pressure gradient at A and at B is the same\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sea breezes are most likely to occur when\n",
        "answer": "slack pressure gradient and clear skies result in relatively high land temperatures\n",
        "choiceone": "a strong pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions\npersist\n",
        "choicetwo": "a strong pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and clear skies at night\nexist\n",
        "choicethree": "a slack pressure gradient, relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions\npersist\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type (genus) is described by the following definition?\n\"Cumulus clouds which are markedly sprouting and are often of great vertical extent;\ntheir bulging upper part frequently resembles a cauliflower.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus capillatus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus fractus\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus humilis\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characterizes a stationary front ?\n",
        "answer": "The surface wind has its direction parallel to the front\n",
        "choiceone": "The surface wind has its direction perpendicular to the front\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warm air moves at approximately half the speed of the cold air\n",
        "choicethree": "The weather conditions that it generates are a combination of those of an intense\ncold front and those of a very active warm front\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical zero degree isotherm is\n",
        "answer": "16000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "12000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "19000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4370A)\nWhat is the mean temperature deviation from ISA for the route Frankfurt - Rome at FL\n180?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0C colder than ISA\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0C warmer than ISA\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\u00b0C colder than ISA\n",
        "choicethree": "10\u00b0C warmer than ISA\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the development of convective circulation?\n",
        "answer": "Cool air must sink to force the warm air upward.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm air is less dense and rises on its own accord.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warmer air covers a larger surface area than the cool air; therefore, the warmer air is\nless dense and rises.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anti-icing fluid should provide freezing point protection to\n",
        "answer": "a freezing point no greater than 20 degrees F below the ambient or airplane surface\ntemperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "-20 degrees F ambient temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "+32 degrees F outside temperature or below.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type precipitation is an indication that supercooled water is present?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wet snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ice pellets.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the stability of the atmosphere be determined?\n",
        "answer": "Ambient temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Atmospheric pressure at various levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface temperature/dewpoint spread.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wind shear forecast in the following TAF?|TAF|KCVG 231051Z 231212\n12012KT 4SM -RA BR OVC008|/WS005/27050KT TEMPO 1719 1/2SM -RA FG|FM1930\n09012KT 1SM -DZ BR VV003 BECMG 2021 5SM HZ=\n",
        "answer": "500 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is most appropriate when an envelope over-temperature condition occurs?\n",
        "answer": "Land as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and allow envelope to cool before landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Throw all unnecessary equipment overboard in order to lighten the load.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In-Flight Aviation Weather Advisories include what type of information?\n",
        "answer": "Forecasts for potentially hazardous flying conditions for enroute aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "State and geographic areas with reported ceilings and visibilities below VFR\nminimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions, turbulence, and icing within a valid period for the listed states.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated if ice pellets are encountered at 8,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain at higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "You are approaching an area of thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You will encounter hail if you continue your flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What determines the structure or type of clouds which will form as a result of air being\nforced to ascend?\n",
        "answer": "The stability of the air before lifting occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "The method by which the air is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The relative humidity of the air after lifting occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "icated on the Weather Depiction Chart by a continuous smooth line\nenclosing a hatched geographic area?\n",
        "answer": "Reporting stations within the enclosed area are all showing IFR conditions at the\ntime of the report.\n",
        "choiceone": "The entire area has ceilings less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 50 percent of the area enclosed by the smooth line is predicted to have\nIFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which primary source contains information regarding the expected weather at the\ndestination airport, at the ETA?\n",
        "answer": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low-Level Prog Chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar Summary and Weather Depiction Charts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is provided by a Convective Outlook (AC)?\n",
        "answer": "It provides prospects of both general and severe thunderstorm activity during the\nfollowing 24 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "It describes areas of probable severe icing and severe or extreme turbulence during\nthe next 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates areas of probable convective turbulence and the extent of instability in\nthe upper atmosphere (above 500 mb).\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the maximum hazard zone caused by wind shear associated with a\nthunderstorm be found?\n",
        "answer": "On all sides and directly under the thunderstorm cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the southwest side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ahead of the roll cloud or gust front and directly under the anvil cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What visible signs indicate extreme turbulence in thunderstorms?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus clouds, very frequent lightning, and roll clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Base of the clouds near the surface, heavy rain, and hail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low ceiling and visibility, hail, and precipitation static.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type weather conditions are covered in the Convective SIGMET?\n",
        "answer": "Embedded thunderstorms, lines of thunderstorms, and thunderstorms with 3/4-inch\nhail or tornadoes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus clouds with tops above the tropopause and thunderstorms with 1/2-\ninch hail or funnel clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any thunderstorm with a severity level of VIP 2 or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapor which air can hold largely depends on\n",
        "answer": "air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability of air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which meteorological environment\nhighest rate of accumulation?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High humidity and freezing temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in the\ncircle 6 area?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix 'nimbus\u2019, used in naming clouds, means a\n",
        "answer": "rain cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "cloud with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dark massive, towering cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What type of report is listed for Lubbock (KLBB) at 18182?\n",
        "answer": "A Special METAR weather observation, concerning significant weather changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "An Aviation selected special weather report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A special report concerning very low station pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is frost considered hazardous to flight operation?\n",
        "answer": "Frost causes early airflow separation resulting in a loss of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost changes the basic aerodynamic shape of the airfoil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frost decreases control effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The body of a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) covers a geographical proximity\nwithin a\n",
        "answer": "5 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 nautical mile radius of the center of an airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 to 10 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A characteristic of the stratosphere is\n",
        "answer": "relatively small changes in temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "an overall decrease of temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a relatively even base altitude of approximately 35,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conclusion(s) can be drawn from a 500-millibar Constant Pressure Chart for a\nplanned flight at FL 180?\n",
        "answer": "Observed temperature, wind, and temperature/dewpoint spread along the proposed\nroute can be approximated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Winds aloft at FL 180 generally flow across the height contours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upper highs, lows, troughs, and ridges will be depicted by the use of lines of equal\npressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum altitude an airship can reach under any given atmospheric condition and\nreturn safely to the surface is determined by\n",
        "answer": "ballonet capacity.\n",
        "choiceone": "the disposable weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ballonet capacity and disposable weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sea breeze is a wind\n",
        "answer": "occurring only in the lower layers of the atmosphere in daytime\n",
        "choiceone": "that reaches up to the tropopause in daytime\n",
        "choicetwo": "blowing at night in mid-latitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "occurring only in mid-latitudes and in daytime\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A katabatic wind blows\n",
        "answer": "down the slope during the night.\n",
        "choiceone": "up the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "down the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicethree": "up the slope during the night.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus often is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level\n",
        "choiceone": "poor visibility at surface\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions below the cloud level\n",
        "choicethree": "a high risk of thunderstorms\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A plain with an average elevation of 500 m (1600 ft) above sea level is covered with a\nuniform AC layer of cloud during the summer months. At what height above the ground\nis the base of this cloud to be expected?\n\n",
        "answer": "7000 - 15000\n",
        "choiceone": "100 - 1500\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 - 7000\n",
        "choicethree": "15000 - 25000 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type (genus) is described by the following definition?\n\"Cumulus clouds which are markedly sprouting and are often of great vertical extent;\ntheir bulging upper part frequently resembles a cauliflower.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus capillatus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus fractus\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus humilis\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal fog is most likely to occur\n",
        "answer": "in advance of a warm front\n",
        "choiceone": "in rear of a warm front\n",
        "choicetwo": "in summer in the early morning\n",
        "choicethree": "in winter in the early morning\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favours the development of orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "High relative humidity\n",
        "choiceone": "Absolutely unstable air\n",
        "choicetwo": "Katabatic winds\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear nights\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air masses that are observed most frequently over Western Europe are:\n",
        "answer": "polar air and tropical air.\n",
        "choiceone": "arctic air and polar air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "polar air and equatorial air.\n",
        "choicethree": "arctic air and tropical air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10766A)\nThe weather most likely to be experienced at position \"S\" is\n",
        "answer": "overcast with drizzle and orographic fog\n",
        "choiceone": "scattered thunderstorms and good visibility\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing AS and NS with moderate to heavy rain\n",
        "choicethree": "small amounts of CU with generally good visibility\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sets of con\nthunderstorms?\n\nions are most favourable to the development of\n",
        "answer": "Environmental lapse rate greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate through a great\nvertical extent, high relative humidity and an initial lifting process\n",
        "choiceone": "Extensive isothermal layer, ice particles and water droplets must exist just below the\nfreezing level and orographic lifting\n",
        "choicetwo": "Environmental lapse rate less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate with dew point\nbelow 0\u00b0C and considerable surface heating\n",
        "choicethree": "Environmental lapse rate less than dry adiabatic lapse rate with freezing level below\nthe cloud base, high relative humidity and strong surface winds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stage of thunderstorm development are rotor winds characterized by roll\nclouds most likely to occur ?\n",
        "answer": "Mature stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dissipating stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus stage and mature stage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the colours with which a stationary front is shown on a surface chart?\n",
        "answer": "Red and blue\n",
        "choiceone": "Violet and red\n",
        "choicetwo": "Red and green\n",
        "choicethree": "Blue and violet\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interprete this METAR ?\n\n00000KT 0200 R14/0800U R16/P1500U FZFG VV001 m03/m03 Q1022 BECMG 0800=\n",
        "answer": "RVR for runway 14 800 metres, vertical visibility 100 feet, calm, visibility improving to\n800 metres in the next 2 hours\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 200 metres, RVR for runway 16 1500 metres, temperature -3\u00b0C, vertical\nvisibility 100 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 200 feet, RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres, vertical visibility 100\nfeet, fog with hoar frost\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility for runway 14 800 metres, fog with hoar frost, RVR for runway 16 more than\n1500 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A temperature inversion will normally form only\n",
        "answer": "in stable air.\n",
        "choiceone": "in unstable air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when a stratiform layer merges with a cumuliform mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an SATELP TUS\nflight at 16,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction shift from southwest to east.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease slightly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of weather can only be directly observed during flight and then reported in a\nPIREP?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and structural icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Jetstream-type winds and icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Level of the tropopause and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What is the forecast temperature at ATL for the 3,000-foot level?\n",
        "answer": "Not reported.\n",
        "choiceone": "+6 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "+6 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed aloft are forecast by this WINDS AND TEMPERATURE\nALOFT FORECAST (FD) for FL390 - '750649\u00b0?\n",
        "answer": "250 degrees at 106 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "350 degrees at 64 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "150 degrees at 6 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What situation is most conducive to the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Warm, moist air over low, flatland areas on clear, calm nights.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist, tropical air moving over cold, offshore water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The movement of cold air over much warmer water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The remarks section of the Aviation Routine Weather Report (METAR) contains the\nfollowing coded information. What does it mean?/|RMK FZDZB42 WSHFT 30 FROPA\n",
        "answer": "Wind shift at three zero due to frontal passage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing drizzle with cloud bases below 4,200 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Freezing drizzle below 4,200 feet and wind shear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud types would indicate convective turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nimbostratus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the maximum hazard zone caused by wind shear associated with a\nthunderstorm be found?\n",
        "answer": "On all sides and directly under the thunderstorm cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the southwest side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ahead of the roll cloud or gust front and directly under the anvil cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are favorable for the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Clear sky, little or no wind, small temperature/dew point spread, and over a land\nsurface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloudy sky and a light wind moving saturated warm air over a cool surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hazardous wind shear is commonly encountered\n",
        "answer": "in areas of temperature inversion and near thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "near warm or stationary frontal activity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when the wind velocity is stronger than 35 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wind system associated with a low-pressure area in the Northern Hemisphere is\n",
        "answer": "a cyclone and is caused by Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "an anticyclone and is caused by descending cold air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an anticyclone and is caused by Coriolis force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement concerning thermals.\n",
        "answer": "Strong thermals have proportionately increased sink in the air between them.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thermals are unaffected by winds aloft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A thermal invariably remains directly above the surface area from which it\ndeveloped.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station originating the following weather report has a field elevation of 1,300 feet\nMSL. From the bottom of the overcast cloud layer, whatis its thickness? (tops of OVC\nare reported at 3800 feet)|SPECI KOKC 22282 28024G36KT 3/4SM BKNO08 OVC020\n\n28/23 A3000\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the winds at 2,000 feet above the surface and the\nsurface winds?\n",
        "answer": "The winds at 2,000 feet tend to parallel the isobars while the surface winds cross the\nisobars at an angle toward lower pressure and are weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "The winds at 2,000 feet and the surface winds flow in the same direction, but the\nsurface winds are weaker due to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface winds tend to veer to the right of the winds at 2,000 feet and are usually\nweaker.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL)\nduring daylight hours for the circle 2 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicates that\nWest Virginia will likely experience\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery precipitation covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "thunderstorms and rain showers covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continuous rain covering less than half of the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Atmospheric pressure changes due to a thunderstorm will be at the lowest value\n",
        "answer": "when the thunderstorm is approaching.\n",
        "choiceone": "during the downdraft and heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "immediately after the rain showers have stopped.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reporting station originating this Aviation Routine Weather Report has a field\nelevation of 620 feet. If the reported sky cover is one continuous layer, what is its\nthickness? (tops of OVC are reported at 6500 feet)|METAR KMDW 121856Z AUTO\n32005KT 1 1/2SM +RABR OVCO07 17/16 A2980\n",
        "answer": "5,180 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5,800 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,880 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strong wind shear can be expected\n",
        "answer": "on the low pressure side of a 100-knot jetstream core.\n",
        "choiceone": "where the horizontal wind shear is 15 knots, in a distance equal to 2.5 degrees\nlongitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the 5 degrees C isotherms are spaced 100 NM or closer together.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by the Special METAR weather observation for KBOI?|SPECI KBOI\n091854Z 32005KT 1 1/2SM RA BR OVC007 17/16 A2990 RMK RAB12\n",
        "answer": "Rain and mist obstructing visibility; rain began at 1812Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rain and fog obscuring two-tenths of the sky; rain began at 1912Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain and overcast at 1200 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A clear area in a line of thunderstorm echoes on a radar scope indicates\n",
        "answer": "an area where precipitation drops are not detected.\n",
        "choiceone": "the absence of clouds in the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area of no convective turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is frost considered hazardous to flight operation?\n",
        "answer": "Frost causes early airflow separation resulting in a loss of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost changes the basic aerodynamic shape of the airfoil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frost decreases control effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum altitude an airship can reach under any given atmospheric condition and\nreturn safely to the surface is determined by\n",
        "answer": "ballonet capacity.\n",
        "choiceone": "the disposable weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ballonet capacity and disposable weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following combinations of weather producing variables would likely result\ncumuliform-type clouds, good visibility, rain showers, and possible clear-type icing in\nclouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Unstable, moist air, and orographic lifting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Unstable, moist air, and no lifting mechanism.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stable, dry air, and orographic lifting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the cumulus stage of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Beginning of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frequent lightning.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A characteristic of the stratosphere is\n",
        "answer": "relatively small changes in temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "an overall decrease of temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a relatively even base altitude of approximately 35,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning an isothermal layer in the atmosphere\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "An isothermal layer is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air parcels that are forced to rise through an isothermal layer keep the same\ntemperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The vertical temperature gradient lies between the dry and saturated adiabatic lapse\nrates.\n",
        "choicethree": "An isothermal layer is formed when the air in the layer is well mixed by turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by QFE?\n",
        "answer": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation, reduced to mean sea\nlevel in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pressure at MSL in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The present atmospheric pressure at an aerodrome converted to mean sea level in\naccordance with the actual conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When advection fog has developed, what may tend to di\nstratus clouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Wind stronger than 15 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms suddenly by day but not by night\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is formed when the air is unstable\n",
        "choicethree": "It develops slowly and dissipates rapidly\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characterizes a stationary front ?\n",
        "answer": "The surface wind has its direction parallel to the front\n",
        "choiceone": "The surface wind has its direction perpendicular to the front\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warm air moves at approximately half the speed of the cold air\n",
        "choicethree": "The weather conditions that it generates are a combination of those of an intense\ncold front and those of a very active warm front\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-2388A)\nWhat wind direction will occur over the sea at point F?\n",
        "answer": "South\n",
        "choiceone": "Northeast\n",
        "choicetwo": "Northwest\n",
        "choicethree": "Southeast\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a favourable synoptic situation for the development of a Scirocco?\n",
        "answer": "Low pressure area in the western part of the Mediterranean Sea\n",
        "choiceone": "High pressure area over Italy\n",
        "choicetwo": "Extension of the Azores high pressure area over the Alps\n",
        "choicethree": "High pressure area in the western part of the Mediterranean Sea\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sets of con\nthunderstorms?\n\nions are most favourable to the development of\n",
        "answer": "Environmental lapse rate greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate through a great\nvertical extent, high relative humidity and an initial lifting process\n",
        "choiceone": "Extensive isothermal layer, ice particles and water droplets must exist just below the\nfreezing level and orographic lifting\n",
        "choicetwo": "Environmental lapse rate less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate with dew point\nbelow 0\u00b0C and considerable surface heating\n",
        "choicethree": "Environmental lapse rate less than dry adiabatic lapse rate with freezing level below\nthe cloud base, high relative humidity and strong surface winds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a downburst?\n",
        "answer": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a lower temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a higher temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An extremely strong wind gust in a tropical revolving storm.\n",
        "choicethree": "A small low pressure system where the wind circulates with very high speeds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative\nto ISA) are expected for a flight over MKC at FL 260?\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees true; 43 knots; ISA +10 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "260 degrees true; 45 knots; ISA -10 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 42 knots; ISA +9 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the contraction VRB in the Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) mean?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction is variable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed is variable throughout the period.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloud base is variable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If squalls are reported at your destination, what wind conditions should you anticipate?\n",
        "answer": "Sudden increases in wind speed of at least 16 knots, rising to 22 knots or more,\nlasting for at least 1 minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "Peak gusts of at least 35 knots for a sustained period of 1 minute or longer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rapid variation in wind direction of at least 20__degrees__ and changes in speed of\nat least 10 knots between peaks and lulls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are some characteristics of unstable air?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nimbostratus clouds and good surface visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence and poor surface visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) A planned low-altitude flight from central Oklahoma to western\nTennessee at 12002 is likely to encounter\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery rain over half or more of the area, moderate turbulence, and\nfreezing temperatures above 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous or intermittent rain or rain showers, moderate turbulence, and freezing\ntemperatures below 8,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "showery precipitation covering less than half the area, no turbulence below 18,000\nfeet, and freezing temperatures above 12,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are haze layers cleared or dispersed?\n",
        "answer": "By wind or the movement of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "By convective mixing in cool night air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By evaporation similar to the clearing of fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather difference is found on each side of a \u2018dry line\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Dewpoint difference.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extreme temperature difference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratus versus cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the wind-group at one of the forecast altitudes omitted at a specific location or\nstation in the Winds and Temperatures Aloft Forecast (FD)? When the wind\n\n",
        "answer": "at the altitude is within 1,500 feet of the station elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "is less than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is less than 10 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of either predominantly stratiform or predominantly cumuliform clouds is\ndependent upon the\n",
        "answer": "stability of the air being lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature of the air being lifted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning the radar weather report (SD) for KOKC?|KOKC 1934 LN\n8TRW++4/+ 86/40 164/60 199/115 15W L2425 MT 570 AT 159/65 2|INCH HAIL RPRTD THIS\nCELL\n",
        "answer": "The maximum tops of the cells is 57,000 feet located 65 NM southeast of the station.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are three cells with tops at 11,500, 40,000, and 60,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line of cells is moving 060 degrees with winds reported up to 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which atmospheric factor causes rapid movement of surface fronts?\n",
        "answer": "Upper winds blowing across the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upper low located directly over the surface low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The cold front overtaking and lifting the warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is provided by a Convective Outlook (AC)?\n",
        "answer": "It provides prospects of both general and severe thunderstorm activity during the\nfollowing 24 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "It describes areas of probable severe icing and severe or extreme turbulence during\nthe next 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates areas of probable convective turbulence and the extent of instability in\nthe upper atmosphere (above 500 mb).\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do squall lines most often develop?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "In an occluded front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Behind a stationary front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "icated on the Weather Depiction Chart by a continuous smooth line\nenclosing a hatched geographic area?\n",
        "answer": "Reporting stations within the enclosed area are all showing IFR conditions at the\ntime of the report.\n",
        "choiceone": "The entire area has ceilings less than 1,000 feet and/or visibility less than 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 50 percent of the area enclosed by the smooth line is predicted to have\nIFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which clouds have the greatest turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Towering cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus castellanus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vertical wind shear can be determined directly from the dashed lines on the tropopause\ndata chart. The vertical wind shear that is critical for probability of turbulence is\n",
        "answer": "6 knots or more per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 knots or greater per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater than 8 knots per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 74.) What CAS should be used to maintain the filed TAS at the flight\nplanned altitude if the outside air temperature is +5 degrees C?\n",
        "answer": "133 KCAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "129 KCAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "139 KCAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying into a low-pressure area\nand velocity will be from the\n\nthe Northern Hemisphere, the wind direction\n",
        "answer": "left and increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "left and decreasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "right and decreasing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an SATELP TUS\nflight at 16,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction shift from southwest to east.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease slightly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ions necessary for the formation of cumulonimbus clouds are a lifti\n\n",
        "answer": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With respect to advection fog, which statement is true?\n",
        "answer": "It can appear suddenly during day or night, and it is more persistent than radiation\nfog.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is slow to develop, and dissipates quite rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It forms almost exclusively at night or near daybreak.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type clouds can be expected when an unstable air mass is forced to ascend a\nmountain slope?\n",
        "answer": "Clouds with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choiceone": "Layered clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratified clouds with considerable associated turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which family of clouds is least likely to contribute to structural icing on an aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "High clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clouds with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL)\nduring daylight hours for the circle 2 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant Pressure Analysis Charts contain contours, isotherms and some con\nisotachs. The contours depict\n",
        "answer": "ridges, lows, troughs and highs aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges on the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "highs, lows, troughs, and ridges corrected to MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What determines the structure or type of clouds which form as a result of air being\nforced to ascend?\n",
        "answer": "The stability of the air before lifting occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "The method by which the air is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The amount of condensation nuclei present after lifting occurs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues.\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below basic VFR; otherwise, hourly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true concerning squall lines?\n",
        "answer": "They offer the most intense weather hazards to aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "They form slowly, but move rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They are associated with frontal systems only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area forecasts generally include a forecast period of 18 hours and cover a geographical\n",
        "answer": "area the size of several states.\n",
        "choiceone": "terminal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "area less than 3000 square miles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is associated with a temperature inversion?\n",
        "answer": "A stable layer of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "An unstable layer of air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition does advection fog usually form?\n",
        "answer": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm, moist air settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A land breeze blowing a cold air mass over a warm water current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAF) are issued how many times a day and cover what\nperiod of time?\n",
        "answer": "Four times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period.\n",
        "choiceone": "Six times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period including a 4-hour\ncategorical outlook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four times daily and are valid for 12 hours including a 6-hour categorical outlook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the same pressure gradient and den:\ngeostrophic wind will be\n\nat 60\u00b0N, 50\u00b0N and 40\u00b0N the speed of the\n",
        "answer": "greatest at 40\u00b0N\n",
        "choiceone": "the same at all latitudes\n",
        "choicetwo": "greatest at 60\u00b0N\n",
        "choicethree": "least at 50\u00b0N\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under anticyclone conditions in the northern hemisphere, with curved isobars the\nspeed of the gradient wind is\n",
        "answer": "greater than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choiceone": "less than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as the thermal component\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional only to the Coriolis force\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing fog exists if fog droplets\n",
        "answer": "are supercooled\n",
        "choiceone": "are frozen\n",
        "choicetwo": "are freezing very rapidly\n",
        "choicethree": "freeze when temperature falls below zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4297A)\nOn which one of the tracks (dashed lines) is this cross-section to be expected?\n",
        "answer": "Track B-D\n",
        "choiceone": "Track B-C\n",
        "choicetwo": "Track A-D\n",
        "choicethree": "Track A-E\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4314A)\nContinuous freezing rain is observed at an airfield.\n\nWhich of the four diagrams is most likely to reflect temperatures above the airfield\nconcerned?\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 1\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the characteristics of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Poor visibility; steady precipitation; stratus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Good visibility; steady precipitation; stratus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Poor visibility; intermittent precipitation; cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Surface Analysis Chart depicts\n",
        "answer": "actual frontal positions, pressure patterns, temperature, dewpoint, wind, weather,\nand obstructions to vision at the valid time of the chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "frontal locations and expected movement, pressure centers, cloud coverage, and\nobstructions to vision at the time of chart transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "actual pressure distribution, frontal systems, cloud heights and coverage,\ntemperature, dewpoint, and wind at the time shown on the chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 201 and 201A.) What type of weather information would normally be\nexpected to be available from the Weather Data Source at Ogden-Hinckley?\n",
        "answer": "Cloud height, weather, obstructions to vision, temperature, dewpoint, altimeter,\nsurface winds, and any pertinent remarks.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cloud basesitops, obstructions to vision, altimeter, winds, precipitation, and the\nintensity of the precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloud height, obstructions to vision, temperature, dewpoint, altimeter, wind data,\nand density altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are necessary for the formation of upslope fog?\n",
        "answer": "Moist, stable air being moved over gradually rising ground by a wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A clear sky, little or no wind, and 100 percent relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain falling through stratus clouds and a 10- to 25-knot wind moving the\nprecipitation up the slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 146.) What was the ceiling at Walnut Ridge (KARG)?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,400 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Virga is best described as\n",
        "answer": "streamers of precipitation trailing beneath clouds which evaporates before reaching\nthe ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "wall cloud torrents trailing beneath cumulonimbus clouds which dissipate before\nreaching the ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turbulent areas beneath cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 150.) The Weather Depiction Chart indicates that the coastal sections of\nTexas and Louisiana are reporting\n",
        "answer": "VFR conditions with scattered clouds at 3,200 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "all ceilings at or above 20,000 feet with visibilities of 20 miles or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "marginal VFR conditions due to broken ceilings of 3,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What important information is provided by the Radar Summary Chart that is not shown\non other weather charts?\n",
        "answer": "Lines and cells of hazardous thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Types of precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Areas of cloud cover and icing levels within the clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What was the local Central Standard Time of the Aviation Routine\nWeather Report at Austin (KAUS)?\n",
        "answer": "11:53 a.m.\n",
        "choiceone": "5:53 p.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:53 p.m.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix 'nimbus\u2019, used in naming clouds, means a\n",
        "answer": "rain cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "cloud with extensive vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dark massive, towering cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type turbulence should be reported when it causes changes in altitude and/or\nattitude more than two-thirds of the time, with the aircraft remaining in positive control at\nall times?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous severe chop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Intermittent moderate turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are downdrafts in a mature thunderstorm hazardous?\n",
        "answer": "Downdrafts are kept cool by cold rain which tends to accelerate the downward\nvelocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Downdrafts converge toward a central location under the storm after striking the\nsurface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Downdrafts become warmer than the surrounding air and reverse into an updraft\nbefore reaching the surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do the maximum winds associated with the jetstream usually occur?\n",
        "answer": "In the vicinity of breaks in the tropopause on the polar side of the jet core.\n",
        "choiceone": "Below the jet core where a long straight stretch of the jetstream is located.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the equatorial side of the jetstream where moisture has formed cirriform clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time are current AIRMETs broadcast in their entirety by the Hazardous Inflight\nWeather Advisory Service (HIWAS)?\n",
        "answer": "There is a continuous broadcast over selected VORs of Inflight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 and 45 minutes after the hour during the first hour after issuance, and upon\nreceipt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are characteristics of a cold air mass moving over a warm surface?\n",
        "answer": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds, smooth air, and poor visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Strong turbulence in the cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot planning to depart at 1100Z on an IFR flight is particularly concerned about the\nhazard of icing. What sources reflect the most accurate information on icing conditions\n(current and forecast) at the time of departure?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot weather reports (PIREPs), AIRMETs, and SIGMETs.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low-Level Significant Weather Prognostic Chart, and the Area Forecast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Area Forecast, and the Freezing Level Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type service should normally be expected from an En Route Flight Advisory\nService?\n",
        "answer": "Weather advisories pertinent to the type of flight, intended route of flight, and\naltitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe weather information, changes in flight plans, and receipt of position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar vectors for traffic separation, route weather advisories, and altimeter settings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions result in the formation of frost?\n",
        "answer": "Temperature of the collecting surface is below the dewpoint of surrounding air and\nthe dewpoint is colder than freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature of the collecting surface is at or below freezing and small droplets\nof moisture are falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When dew forms and the temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steady precipitation, in contrast to showers, preceding a front is an indication of\n",
        "answer": "stratiform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratiform clouds with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cummuliform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL)\nduring daylight hours for the circle 2 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) At which time is IFR weather first predicted at Lubbock (KLBB)?\n",
        "answer": "0100Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "2100Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0400Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying over the top of a severe thunderstorm, the cloud should be overflown by at\nleast\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet for each 10 knots windspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 feet above any moderate to severe turbulence layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are indicated on a Weather Depiction Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Actual sky cover, visibility restrictions, and type of precipitation at reporting stations.\n",
        "choiceone": "Forecast ceilings and visibilities over a large geographic area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Actual en route weather conditions between reporting stations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which precipitation type normally indicates freezing rain at higher altitudes?\n",
        "answer": "Ice pellets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hail.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) What type con\nland at San Angelo (KSJT) at 15002?\n\nions can be expected for a flight scheduled to\n",
        "answer": "IFR conditions due to low visibility, rain, and mist.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chance of 1 statute mile visibility and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions due to low ceilings, rain, and fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Of the following, whi\nthunderstorms?\n\naccurate regarding turbulence associated with\n",
        "answer": "Outside the cloud, shear turbulence can be encountered 20 miles laterally from a\nsevere storm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Outside the cloud, shear turbulence can be encountered 50 miles laterally from a\nsevere storm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shear turbulence is encountered only inside cumulonimbus clouds or within a 5-\nmile radius of them.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under anticyclone conditions in the northern hemisphere, with curved isobars the\nspeed of the gradient wind is\n",
        "answer": "greater than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choiceone": "less than the geostrophic wind\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as the thermal component\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional only to the Coriolis force\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When in summer calm and clear conditions exist, a station on the shore of a large body\nof water will experience wind\n",
        "answer": "from the water in daytime and from the land at night\n",
        "choiceone": "continually from land to water\n",
        "choicetwo": "continually from water to the land\n",
        "choicethree": "from the land in daytime and from the water at night\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When advection fog has developed, what may tend to di\nstratus clouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Wind stronger than 15 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomen:\nCumulonimbus with thunderstorm ?\n\nleast likely to lead to the formation of a\n",
        "answer": "Ground radiation\n",
        "choiceone": "Convection\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convergence\n",
        "choicethree": "Orographic lifting\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In towering cumulus clouds\n",
        "answer": "strong updraughts occur and the temperature in the cloud is higher than in the\nsurrounding air at the same height\n",
        "choiceone": "strong updraughts occur and the temperature in the cloud is lower than in the\nsurrounding air at the same height\n",
        "choicetwo": "weak vertical air motion exists and the temperature in the cloud is lower than in the\nsurrounding air at the same height\n",
        "choicethree": "weak vertical air motion exists and the temperature in the cloud is higher than in the\nsurrounding air at the same height\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of ice pellets at the surface is the evidence that:\n",
        "answer": "temperatures are above freezing at some higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "choicethree": "after take-off you can climb to a higher altitude without encountering more than light\nicing conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are necessary for vertical visibility to be reported?\n",
        "answer": "When sky obscured by heavy precipitation and cloud base cannot be measured.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis always reported.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Whenever the lowest ceiling is below 1500 ft above ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "Whenever the lowest cloud base is below 1500 ft above ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following messages should be cancelled when the conditions are no\nlonger occurring or no longer expected to occur?\n",
        "answer": "Aerodrome warning\n",
        "choiceone": "Trend forecast\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for a DSM LIT SHV\nflight at 12,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction shift from northwest to southeast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What visible signs indicate extreme turbulence in thunderstorms?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus clouds, very frequent lightning, and roll clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Base of the clouds near the surface, heavy rain, and hail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low ceiling and visibility, hail, and precipitation static.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an SATELP TUS\nflight at 16,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction shift from southwest to east.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease slightly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather is predicted by the term VCTS in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are expected in the vicinity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thunderstorms may occur over the station and within 50 miles of the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are expected between 5 and 25 miles of the runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the temperature at one of the forecast altitudes omitted at a specific location or\nstation in the Winds and Temperatures Aloft Forecast (FD)?\n\n",
        "answer": "For the 3,000-foot altitude (level) or when the level is within 2,500 feet of station\nelevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the temperature is standard for that altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the winds are omitted for that altitude (level).\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During departure, under conditions of suspected low-level wind shear, a sudden\ndecrease in headwind will cause\n",
        "answer": "a loss in airspeed equal to the decrease in wind velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "a gain in airspeed equal to the decrease in wind velocity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "no change in airspeed, but groundspeed will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time are current AIRMETs broadcast in their entirety by the Hazardous Inflight\nWeather Advisory Service (HIWAS)?\n",
        "answer": "There is a continuous broadcast over selected VORs of Inflight Weather Advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 and 45 minutes after the hour during the first hour after issuance, and upon\nreceipt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Every 15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ice pellets encountered during flight are normally evidence that\n",
        "answer": "freezing rain exists at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition does advection fog usually form?\n",
        "answer": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm, moist air settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A land breeze blowing a cold air mass over a warm water current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strong wind shear can be expected\n",
        "answer": "on the low pressure side of a 100-knot jetstream core.\n",
        "choiceone": "where the horizontal wind shear is 15 knots, in a distance equal to 2.5 degrees\nlongitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the 5 degrees C isotherms are spaced 100 NM or closer together.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by the Special METAR weather observation for KBOI?|SPECI KBOI\n091854Z 32005KT 1 1/2SM RA BR OVC007 17/16 A2990 RMK RAB12\n",
        "answer": "Rain and mist obstructing visibility; rain began at 1812Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rain and fog obscuring two-tenths of the sky; rain began at 1912Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain and overcast at 1200 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type frontal system is normally crossed by the jetstream?\n",
        "answer": "Occluded front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold front and warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In-Flight Aviation Weather Advisories include what type of information?\n",
        "answer": "Forecasts for potentially hazardous flying conditions for enroute aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "State and geographic areas with reported ceilings and visibilities below VFR\nminimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions, turbulence, and icing within a valid period for the listed states.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination weather!\nshould be obtained from the\n\nformation for an instrument flight\n",
        "answer": "AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airman publications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most dangerous features of mountain waves is the turbulent areas in and\n",
        "answer": "below rotor clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "above rotor clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below lenticular clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to a high- or low-pressure system?\n",
        "answer": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of descending air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A low-pressure area or trough is an area of descending air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative\nto ISA) are expected for a flight over MKC at FL 260?\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees true; 43 knots; ISA +10 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "260 degrees true; 45 knots; ISA -10 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 42 knots; ISA +9 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most midair colli\n\n",
        "answer": "clear days.\n",
        "choiceone": "hazy days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cloudy nights.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are haze layers cleared or dispersed?\n",
        "answer": "By wind or the movement of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "By convective mixing in cool night air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By evaporation similar to the clearing of fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The general circulation of\nHemisphere is\n\nassociated with a high-pressure area in the Northern\n",
        "answer": "outward, downward, and clockwise.\n",
        "choiceone": "outward, upward, and clockwise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "inward, downward, and clockwise.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the air temperature is +8 degrees C at an elevation of 1,350 feet and a standard\n(average) temperature lapse rate exists, what will be the approximate freezing level?\n",
        "answer": "5,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,350 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do the maximum winds associated with the jetstream usually occur?\n",
        "answer": "In the vicinity of breaks in the tropopause on the polar side of the jet core.\n",
        "choiceone": "Below the jet core where a long straight stretch of the jetstream is located.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the equatorial side of the jetstream where moisture has formed cirriform clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The strength and location of the jet stream is normally\n",
        "answer": "weaker and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "stronger and farther north in the winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stronger and farther north in the summer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absence of the sky condition and visibility on an ATIS broadcast indicates that\n",
        "answer": "the ceiling is at least 5,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "weather conditions are at or above VFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the sky condition is clear and visibility is unrestricted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "It can be present at any level and can exist in both a horizontal and vertical direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis present at only lower levels and exists in a horizontal direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itis present at any level and exists in only a vertical direction.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer in which the temperature remains constant with height is\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally unstable\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type (genus) is described by the following definition?\n\"Cumulus clouds which are markedly sprouting and are often of great vertical extent;\ntheir bulging upper part frequently resembles a cauliflower.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus capillatus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus fractus\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus humilis\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground\n",
        "choiceone": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night\n",
        "choicethree": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a\nsinking air mass\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10766A)\nThe weather most likely to be experienced at position \"S\" is\n",
        "answer": "overcast with drizzle and orographic fog\n",
        "choiceone": "scattered thunderstorms and good visibility\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing AS and NS with moderate to heavy rain\n",
        "choicethree": "small amounts of CU with generally good visibility\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stationary front is a front in which:\n",
        "answer": "there is no horizontal motion perpendicular to the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "there is no difference in temperature between the two air masses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is no wind on both sides of the front.\n",
        "choicethree": "there are never frontal clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clear ice is dangerous because it\n",
        "answer": "is heavy and is difficult to remove from the aircraft surfaces\n",
        "choiceone": "is translucent and only forms at the leading edges\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not translucent and forms at the leading edges\n",
        "choicethree": "spreads out and contains many air particles\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct concerning a mountain ridge where a marked mount\nwave has been reported ?\n",
        "answer": "Ragged altocumulus lenticularis represents moderate/severe turbulence\n",
        "choiceone": "There are always rotor clouds\n",
        "choicetwo": "The atmosphere is unstable at the level of the mountain tops\n",
        "choicethree": "The axis of a rotor is horizontal and perpendicular to the mountains\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the colours with which a stationary front is shown on a surface chart?\n",
        "answer": "Red and blue\n",
        "choiceone": "Violet and red\n",
        "choicetwo": "Red and green\n",
        "choicethree": "Blue and violet\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) What type con\nland at San Angelo (KSJT) at 15002?\n\nions can be expected for a flight scheduled to\n",
        "answer": "IFR conditions due to low visibility, rain, and mist.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chance of 1 statute mile visibility and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR conditions due to low ceilings, rain, and fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The remarks section of the Aviation Routine Weather Report (METAR) contains the\nfollowing coded information. What does it mean?/|RMK FZDZB42 WSHFT 30 FROPA\n",
        "answer": "Wind shift at three zero due to frontal passage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing drizzle with cloud bases below 4,200 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Freezing drizzle below 4,200 feet and wind shear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 151.) The chart symbols over southern California on the 12-Hour\n\nSignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicate\n",
        "answer": "pected top of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u2018pected base of moderate turbulent layer to be 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "light turbulence expected above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Terminal Aerodrome Forecasts (TAF) are issued how many times a day and cover what\nperiod of time?\n",
        "answer": "Four times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period.\n",
        "choiceone": "Six times daily and are usually valid for a 24 hour period including a 4-hour\ncategorical outlook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Four times daily and are valid for 12 hours including a 6-hour categorical outlook.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If clouds form as a result of very stable, moist air being forced to ascend a mountain\nslope, the clouds will be\n",
        "answer": "stratus type with little vertical development and little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "cirrus type with no vertical development or turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cumulus type with considerable vertical development and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absence of the sky condition and visibility on an ATIS broadcast indicates that\n",
        "answer": "the ceiling is at least 5,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "weather conditions are at or above VFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the sky condition is clear and visibility is unrestricted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed aloft are forecast by this WINDS AND TEMPERATURE\nALOFT FORECAST (FD) for FL390 - '731960\u00b0?\n",
        "answer": "230 degrees at 119 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "131 degrees at 96 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "073 degrees at 196 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding high- or low-pressure systems?\n",
        "answer": "A low-pressure area or trough is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A high-pressure area or ridge is an area of rising air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Both high- and low-pressure areas are characterized by descending air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reporting station originating this Aviation Routine Weather Report has a field\nelevation of 620 feet. If the reported sky cover is one continuous layer, what is its\nthickness? (tops of OVC are reported at 6500 feet)|METAR KMDW 121856Z AUTO\n32005KT 1 1/2SM +RABR OVCO07 17/16 A2980\n",
        "answer": "5,180 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5,800 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,880 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is indicated by the term \u2018embedded thunderstorms\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms are obscured by massive cloud layers and cannot be seen.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms are embedded within a squall line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms are predicted to develop in a stable air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which event usually occurs after an aircraft passes through a front into the colder air?\n",
        "answer": "Atmospheric pressure increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature/dewpoint spread decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind direction shifts to the left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The body of a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) covers a geographical proximity\nwithin a\n",
        "answer": "5 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 nautical mile radius of the center of an airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 to 10 statute mile radius from the center of an airport runway complex.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the pilot obtain TWEB Route Forecast information?\n",
        "answer": "From the TEL TWEB and radio broadcasts.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the ATIS and Pilots Automatic Telephone Weather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From ARTCC and Automated Flight Service Station briefings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SPECI KGLS 131802Z 10012G21KT 060V140 2SM +SHRA SCT005 BKN035 OVC050CB\n24/23 A2980 RMK RAB\u00a77 WS TKO RWOSL WSHFT 58 FROPA. This SPECI report at\nGalveston (KGLS) indicates which condition?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation started at 57 after the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind steady at 100 degree magnetic at 12 knots, gusts to 21.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet overcast with towering cumulus.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 9.) The Severe Weather Outlook Chart depicts\n",
        "answer": "areas of probable severe thunderstorms by the use of single hatched areas on the\nchart.\n",
        "choiceone": "areas of forecast, severe or extreme turbulence, and areas of severe icing for the\nnext 24 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "areas of general thunderstorm activity (excluding severe) by the use of hatching on\nthe chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an STL MEM MSY\nflight at FL 330?\n",
        "answer": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind shift from west to north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature increase 5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather feature occurs at altitude levels near the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "Maximum winds and narrow wind shear zones.\n",
        "choiceone": "Abrupt temperature increase above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thin layers of cirrus (ice crystal) clouds at the tropopause level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type service should normally be expected from an En Route Flight Advisory\nService?\n",
        "answer": "Weather advisories pertinent to the type of flight, intended route of flight, and\naltitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe weather information, changes in flight plans, and receipt of position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar vectors for traffic separation, route weather advisories, and altimeter settings.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which meteorological condition does the term \u2018dew point' refer?\n",
        "answer": "The temperature to which air must be cooled to become saturated.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature at which condensation and evaporation are equal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature at which dew will always form.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A situation most conducive to the formation of advection fog is\n",
        "answer": "an air mass moving inland from the coastline during the winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a light breeze moving colder air over a water surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a warm, moist air mass settling over a cool surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are indicated on a Weather Depiction Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Actual sky cover, visibility restrictions, and type of precipitation at reporting stations.\n",
        "choiceone": "Forecast ceilings and visibilities over a large geographic area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Actual en route weather conditions between reporting stations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What condition is reported at Dallas (KDAL)?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter setting is 30.07.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tops of the overcast is 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature/dewpoint spread is 8 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which response most closely interprets the following PIREP?|UA/OV OKC 063064/TM\n1522/FLO80/TP C172/TA -04/WV 245040/TB LGT/RM IN CLR\n",
        "answer": "64 nautical miles on the 63 degrees radial from Oklahoma City VOR at 1522 UTC,\nflight level 8,000 ft. Type of aircraft is a Cessna 172.\n",
        "choiceone": "Reported by a Cessna 172, turbulence and light rime icing in climb to 8,000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "63 nautical miles on the 64 degrees radial from Oklahoma City, thunderstorm and\nlight rain at 1522 UTC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 145.) What weather improvement was reported at Lubbock (KLBB)\nbetween 1750 and 1818 UTC?\n",
        "answer": "The vertical visibility improved by 2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "The wind shift and frontal passage at 1812Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature and dewpoint spread improved.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important characteristic of wind shear?\n",
        "answer": "Itis an atmospheric condition that may be associated with a low-level temperature\ninversion, a jet stream, or a frontal zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis an atmospheric condition that is associated exclusively with zones of\nconvergence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Coriolis phenomenon in both high- and low-level air masses is the principal\ngenerating force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation is advection fog most likely to form?\n",
        "answer": "An air mass moving inland from the coast in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "A light breeze blowing colder air out to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm, moist air settling over a warmer surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which layer is most of the atmospheric humidity concentrated ?\n",
        "answer": "Troposphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratopause.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is\n",
        "answer": "an increase of temperature with height\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase of pressure with height\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease of pressure with height\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease of temperature with height\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFF at an airfield in a location 69 metres below sea level is 1030 hPa. The air\ntemperature is 10\u00b0C lower than a standard atmosphere.\n\nDescribe the QNH?\n",
        "answer": "More than 1030 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "Less than 1030 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1030 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an area of converging\n\n",
        "answer": "clouds can be formed\n",
        "choiceone": "convective clouds can be dissolved\n",
        "choicetwo": "stratified clouds can be dissolved\n",
        "choicethree": "clouds can not be formed\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A katabatic wind blows\n",
        "answer": "down the slope during the night.\n",
        "choiceone": "up the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "down the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicethree": "up the slope during the night.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When advection fog has developed, what may tend to di\nstratus clouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Wind stronger than 15 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an adiabatic process\n",
        "answer": "heat is neither added nor lost\n",
        "choiceone": "heat is added\n",
        "choicetwo": "heat is lost\n",
        "choicethree": "the temperature does not change\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main factor which contributes to the formation of very low clouds ahead of a warm\nfrontis the\n",
        "answer": "saturation of the cold air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choiceone": "saturation of the warm air by rain falling into it and evaporating\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduction of outgoing radiation due to clouds\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air moving over a cold surface\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special air-report\n",
        "answer": "may trigger a SIGMET message\n",
        "choiceone": "may be the reason for closing an airport due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be the reason for closing a part of an airway due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicethree": "is used to produce better aerodrome forecasts (TAF)\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A temperature inversion will normally form only\n",
        "answer": "in stable air.\n",
        "choiceone": "in unstable air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when a stratiform layer merges with a cumuliform mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What will be the wind and temperature trend for an SATELP TUS\nflight at 16,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction shift from southwest to east.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature decrease slightly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Windspeed decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMETs are issued as a warning of weather conditions which are hazardous\n",
        "answer": "to all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "particularly to heavy aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "particularly to light airplanes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of weather can only be directly observed during flight and then reported in a\nPIREP?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence and structural icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Jetstream-type winds and icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Level of the tropopause and turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What is the forecast temperature at ATL for the 3,000-foot level?\n",
        "answer": "Not reported.\n",
        "choiceone": "+6 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "+6 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed aloft are forecast by this WINDS AND TEMPERATURE\nALOFT FORECAST (FD) for FL390 - '750649\u00b0?\n",
        "answer": "250 degrees at 106 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "350 degrees at 64 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "150 degrees at 6 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What situation is most conducive to the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Warm, moist air over low, flatland areas on clear, calm nights.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist, tropical air moving over cold, offshore water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The movement of cold air over much warmer water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The remarks section of the Aviation Routine Weather Report (METAR) contains the\nfollowing coded information. What does it mean?/|RMK FZDZB42 WSHFT 30 FROPA\n",
        "answer": "Wind shift at three zero due to frontal passage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing drizzle with cloud bases below 4,200 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Freezing drizzle below 4,200 feet and wind shear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud types would indicate convective turbulence?\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nimbostratus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the maximum hazard zone caused by wind shear associated with a\nthunderstorm be found?\n",
        "answer": "On all sides and directly under the thunderstorm cell.\n",
        "choiceone": "In front of the thunderstorm cell (anvil side) and on the southwest side of the cell.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ahead of the roll cloud or gust front and directly under the anvil cloud.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions are favorable for the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Clear sky, little or no wind, small temperature/dew point spread, and over a land\nsurface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist air moving over colder ground or water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cloudy sky and a light wind moving saturated warm air over a cool surface.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hazardous wind shear is commonly encountered\n",
        "answer": "in areas of temperature inversion and near thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "near warm or stationary frontal activity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when the wind velocity is stronger than 35 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wind system associated with a low-pressure area in the Northern Hemisphere is\n",
        "answer": "a cyclone and is caused by Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "an anticyclone and is caused by descending cold air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an anticyclone and is caused by Coriolis force.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement concerning thermals.\n",
        "answer": "Strong thermals have proportionately increased sink in the air between them.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thermals are unaffected by winds aloft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A thermal invariably remains directly above the surface area from which it\ndeveloped.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station originating the following weather report has a field elevation of 1,300 feet\nMSL. From the bottom of the overcast cloud layer, whatis its thickness? (tops of OVC\nare reported at 3800 feet)|SPECI KOKC 22282 28024G36KT 3/4SM BKNO08 OVC020\n\n28/23 A3000\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the winds at 2,000 feet above the surface and the\nsurface winds?\n",
        "answer": "The winds at 2,000 feet tend to parallel the isobars while the surface winds cross the\nisobars at an angle toward lower pressure and are weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "The winds at 2,000 feet and the surface winds flow in the same direction, but the\nsurface winds are weaker due to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface winds tend to veer to the right of the winds at 2,000 feet and are usually\nweaker.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomenon signals the beginning of the mature stage of a\nthunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "The start of rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "The appearance of an anvil top.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Growth rate of cloud is maximum.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL)\nduring daylight hours for the circle 2 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ignificant Weather Prognostic Chart indicates that\nWest Virginia will likely experience\n",
        "answer": "continuous or showery precipitation covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "thunderstorms and rain showers covering half or more of the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continuous rain covering less than half of the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Atmospheric pressure changes due to a thunderstorm will be at the lowest value\n",
        "answer": "when the thunderstorm is approaching.\n",
        "choiceone": "during the downdraft and heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "immediately after the rain showers have stopped.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reporting station originating this Aviation Routine Weather Report has a field\nelevation of 620 feet. If the reported sky cover is one continuous layer, what is its\nthickness? (tops of OVC are reported at 6500 feet)|METAR KMDW 121856Z AUTO\n32005KT 1 1/2SM +RABR OVCO07 17/16 A2980\n",
        "answer": "5,180 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5,800 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,880 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strong wind shear can be expected\n",
        "answer": "on the low pressure side of a 100-knot jetstream core.\n",
        "choiceone": "where the horizontal wind shear is 15 knots, in a distance equal to 2.5 degrees\nlongitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the 5 degrees C isotherms are spaced 100 NM or closer together.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by the Special METAR weather observation for KBOI?|SPECI KBOI\n091854Z 32005KT 1 1/2SM RA BR OVC007 17/16 A2990 RMK RAB12\n",
        "answer": "Rain and mist obstructing visibility; rain began at 1812Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rain and fog obscuring two-tenths of the sky; rain began at 1912Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain and overcast at 1200 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A clear area in a line of thunderstorm echoes on a radar scope indicates\n",
        "answer": "an area where precipitation drops are not detected.\n",
        "choiceone": "the absence of clouds in the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area of no convective turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is frost considered hazardous to flight operation?\n",
        "answer": "Frost causes early airflow separation resulting in a loss of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost changes the basic aerodynamic shape of the airfoil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frost decreases control effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum altitude an airship can reach under any given atmospheric condition and\nreturn safely to the surface is determined by\n",
        "answer": "ballonet capacity.\n",
        "choiceone": "the disposable weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ballonet capacity and disposable weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following combinations of weather producing variables would likely result\ncumuliform-type clouds, good visibility, rain showers, and possible clear-type icing in\nclouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Unstable, moist air, and orographic lifting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Unstable, moist air, and no lifting mechanism.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stable, dry air, and orographic lifting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the cumulus stage of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Beginning of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frequent lightning.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A characteristic of the stratosphere is\n",
        "answer": "relatively small changes in temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "an overall decrease of temperature with an increase in altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a relatively even base altitude of approximately 35,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning an isothermal layer in the atmosphere\ncorrect?\n",
        "answer": "An isothermal layer is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air parcels that are forced to rise through an isothermal layer keep the same\ntemperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The vertical temperature gradient lies between the dry and saturated adiabatic lapse\nrates.\n",
        "choicethree": "An isothermal layer is formed when the air in the layer is well mixed by turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by QFE?\n",
        "answer": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation, reduced to mean sea\nlevel in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pressure at MSL in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The present atmospheric pressure at an aerodrome converted to mean sea level in\naccordance with the actual conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When advection fog has developed, what may tend to di\nstratus clouds?\n\n",
        "answer": "Wind stronger than 15 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms suddenly by day but not by night\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is formed when the air is unstable\n",
        "choicethree": "It develops slowly and dissipates rapidly\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characterizes a stationary front ?\n",
        "answer": "The surface wind has its direction parallel to the front\n",
        "choiceone": "The surface wind has its direction perpendicular to the front\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warm air moves at approximately half the speed of the cold air\n",
        "choicethree": "The weather conditions that it generates are a combination of those of an intense\ncold front and those of a very active warm front\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-2388A)\nWhat wind direction will occur over the sea at point F?\n",
        "answer": "South\n",
        "choiceone": "Northeast\n",
        "choicetwo": "Northwest\n",
        "choicethree": "Southeast\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a favourable synoptic situation for the development of a Scirocco?\n",
        "answer": "Low pressure area in the western part of the Mediterranean Sea\n",
        "choiceone": "High pressure area over Italy\n",
        "choicetwo": "Extension of the Azores high pressure area over the Alps\n",
        "choicethree": "High pressure area in the western part of the Mediterranean Sea\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sets of con\nthunderstorms?\n\nions are most favourable to the development of\n",
        "answer": "Environmental lapse rate greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate through a great\nvertical extent, high relative humidity and an initial lifting process\n",
        "choiceone": "Extensive isothermal layer, ice particles and water droplets must exist just below the\nfreezing level and orographic lifting\n",
        "choicetwo": "Environmental lapse rate less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate with dew point\nbelow 0\u00b0C and considerable surface heating\n",
        "choicethree": "Environmental lapse rate less than dry adiabatic lapse rate with freezing level below\nthe cloud base, high relative humidity and strong surface winds\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a downburst?\n",
        "answer": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a lower temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a higher temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An extremely strong wind gust in a tropical revolving storm.\n",
        "choicethree": "A small low pressure system where the wind circulates with very high speeds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a SIGMET alert is announced, how can information contained in the SIGMET be\nobtained?\n",
        "answer": "By contacting the nearest Flight contol center\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC will announce the hazard and advise when information will be provided in the\nFlight control center broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By contacting a weather watch station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what ways do advection fog, radiation fog, and steam fog differ in their formation or\nlocation?\n",
        "answer": "Radiation fog is restricted to land areas; advection fog is most common along\ncoastal areas; steam fog forms over a water surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advection fog deepens as windspeed increases up to 20 knots; steam fog requires\ncalm or very light wind; radiation fog forms when the ground or water cools the air\nby radiation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steam fog forms from moist air moving over a colder surface; advection fog requires\ncold air over a warmer surface; radiation fog is produced by radiational cooling of\nthe ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which meteorological condition does the term \u2018dew point' refer?\n",
        "answer": "The temperature to which air must be cooled to become saturated.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature at which condensation and evaporation are equal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature at which dew will always form.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 147.) At which time is IFR weather first predicted at Lubbock (KLBB)?\n",
        "answer": "0100Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "2100Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0400Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KMAF 131756Z 02020KT 12SM BKN025 OVC250 27/18 A3009 RMK RAE44.\n\n|Which weather condition is indicated by this METAR report at Midland (KMAF)?\n",
        "answer": "Rain of unknown intensity ended 16 minutes before the hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling was at 25,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind was 020 degrees magnetic at 20 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the requirements for the formation of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Sufficient moisture, an unstable lapse rate, and a lifting action.\n",
        "choiceone": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture and an inverted lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are characteristics of a cold air mass moving over a warm surface?\n",
        "answer": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumuliform clouds, turbulence, and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds, smooth air, and poor visibility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What types of fog depend upon a wind in order to exist?\n",
        "answer": "Advection fog and up slope fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Steam fog and down slope fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Precipitation-induced fog and ground fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions necessary for the formation of stratiform clouds are a lifting action and\n",
        "answer": "stable, moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable, dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable, moist air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition produces weather on the lee side of a large lake?\n",
        "answer": "Warm air flowing over a colder lake may produce fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air flowing over a warmer lake may produce advection fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm air flowing over a cool lake may produce rain showers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "METAR KIFSO 031053Z VRBO2KT 7SM MIFG SKC 15/14 A3012 RMK SLP993 Gilli/\n701500139 56012/||In the above METAR, the SLP993 6//// indicates\n",
        "answer": "sea-level pressure 999.3 hectopascals and an indeterminable amount of\nprecipitation has occurred over the last 3 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea-level pressure 999.3 hectopascals which in the last 6 hours has dropped .4\nhectopascals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sea-level pressure 999.3 hectopascals and in the last 6 hours that four-tenths of an\ninch of precipitation has fallen.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What situation is most conducive to the formation of radiation fog?\n",
        "answer": "Warm, moist air over low, flatland areas on clear, calm nights.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist, tropical air moving over cold, offshore water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The movement of cold air over much warmer water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Developing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the\ndowndrafts?\n\ncycle of a thunderstorm, which stage is characterized predominately by\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the terms PROB40 2102 +TSRA as used in a Terminal\nAerodrome Forecasts (TAF)?\n",
        "answer": "Between 2100Z and 02002 there is a forty percent (40%) probability of thunderstorms\nwith heavy rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Probability of heavy thunderstorms with rain showers below 4000 feet at time 2102.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Beginning at 21022 forty percent (40%) probability of heavy thunderstorms and rain\nshowers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the development of convective circulation?\n",
        "answer": "Cool air must sink to force the warm air upward.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm air is less dense and rises on its own accord.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warmer air covers a larger surface area than the cool air; therefore, the warmer air is\nless dense and rises.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absence of the sky condition and visibility on an ATIS broadcast specifically\nthat\n\n",
        "answer": "the ceiling is more than 5,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sky condition is clear and visibility is unrestricted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the ceiling is at least 3,000 feet and visibility is 5 miles or more.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A thermal column is rising from an asphalt parking lot and the wind is from the south at\n12 knots. Which statement would be true?\n",
        "answer": "As altitude is gained, the center of the thermal will be found farther north of the\nparking lot.\n",
        "choiceone": "As altitude is gained, the best lift will be found directly above the parking lot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The slowest rate of sink would be close to the thermal and the fastest rate of sink\nfarther from it.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 6.) With regard to the soundings taken at 1400 hours, between what\naltitudes could optimum thermalling be expected at the time of the sounding?\n",
        "answer": "From 2,500 to 6,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 6,000 to 10,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 13,000 to 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is provided by the Radar Summary Chart that is not shown on other\nweather charts?\n",
        "answer": "Lines and cells of hazardous thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ceilings and precipitation between reporting stations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Areas of cloud cover and icing levels within the clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the cumulus stage of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Beginning of rain at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frequent lightning.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of low-level wind shear as it relates to frontal activity?\n",
        "answer": "With a warm front, the most critical period is before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "With a cold front, the most critical period is just before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence will always exist in wind-shear conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the characteristics of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Poor visibility, steady precipitation, and stratus-type clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Good visibility, steady precipitation, and stratus-type clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Poor visibility, intermittent precipitation, and cumulus-type clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 74.) What CAS should be used to maintain the filed TAS at the flight\nplanned altitude if the outside air temperature is +5 degrees C?\n",
        "answer": "133 KCAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "129 KCAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "139 KCAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wind direction and speed aloft are forecast by this WINDS AND TEMPERATURE\nALOFT FORECAST (FD) for FL390 - '731960\u00b0?\n",
        "answer": "230 degrees at 119 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "131 degrees at 96 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "073 degrees at 196 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the effect of fronts on soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "Frequently, the air behind a cold front provides excellent soaring for several days.\n",
        "choiceone": "A slow moving front provides the strongest lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Good soaring conditions usually exist after passage of a warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination weather!\nshould be obtained from the\n\nformation for an instrument flight\n",
        "answer": "AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airman publications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather difference is found on each side of a \u2018dry line\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Dewpoint difference.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extreme temperature difference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratus versus cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of weather can one expect from moist, unstable air, and very warm surface\ntemperatures?\n",
        "answer": "Strong updrafts and cumulonimbus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fog and low stratus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous heavy precipitation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ceiling is defined as the height of the\n",
        "answer": "lowest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that is reported as broken or\novercast.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest layer of clouds or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers over 6/10 of the\nsky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest layer of clouds that contributed to the overall overcast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wind shear forecast in the following TAF?|TAF|KCVG 231051Z 231212\n12012KT 4SM -RA BR OVC008|/WS005/27050KT TEMPO 1719 1/2SM -RA FG|FM1930\n09012KT 1SM -DZ BR VV003 BECMG 2021 5SM HZ=\n",
        "answer": "500 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 feet AGL from 270 degrees at 50 KT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is\n",
        "answer": "an increase of temperature with height\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase of pressure with height\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease of pressure with height\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease of temperature with height\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFF at an airfield in a location 69 metres below sea level is 1030 hPa. The air\ntemperature is 10\u00b0C lower than a standard atmosphere.\n\nDescribe the QNH?\n",
        "answer": "More than 1030 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "Less than 1030 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1030 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10845A)\nFor an aircraft at FL 40, approaching the front (square 3C) from the direction of square\n3D a potential hazard exists before reaching the front in the form of\n",
        "answer": "clear ice accretion to the airframe\n",
        "choiceone": "severe turbulence associated with CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence and wind shear\n",
        "choicethree": "severe downdrafts from subsiding air\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of front / occlusion usually moves the fastest?\n",
        "answer": "Cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold occlusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "Warm occlusion.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the typical weather conditions in a cold air pool in summer?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation is predominant\n",
        "choiceone": "Generally fine weather, thunderstorms in the afternoon or evening\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fine weather with thunderstorms in the morning or forenoon\n",
        "choicethree": "Ground fog formation is common\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a downburst?\n",
        "answer": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a lower temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choiceone": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a higher temperature than the\nsurrounding air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An extremely strong wind gust in a tropical revolving storm.\n",
        "choicethree": "A small low pressure system where the wind circulates with very high speeds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct concerning a mountain ridge where a marked mount\nwave has been reported ?\n",
        "answer": "Ragged altocumulus lenticularis represents moderate/severe turbulence\n",
        "choiceone": "There are always rotor clouds\n",
        "choicetwo": "The atmosphere is unstable at the level of the mountain tops\n",
        "choicethree": "The axis of a rotor is horizontal and perpendicular to the mountains\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interprete this METAR ?\n\n00000KT 0200 R14/0800U R16/P1500U FZFG VV001 m03/m03 Q1022 BECMG 0800=\n",
        "answer": "RVR for runway 14 800 metres, vertical visibility 100 feet, calm, visibility improving to\n800 metres in the next 2 hours\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 200 metres, RVR for runway 16 1500 metres, temperature -3\u00b0C, vertical\nvisibility 100 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 200 feet, RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres, vertical visibility 100\nfeet, fog with hoar frost\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility for runway 14 800 metres, fog with hoar frost, RVR for runway 16 more than\n1500 metres\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL)\nduring daylight hours for the circle 2 area?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of low-level wind shear as it relates to frontal activity?\n",
        "answer": "With a warm front, the most critical period is before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "With a cold front, the most critical period is just before the front passes the airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence will always exist in wind-shear conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are jetstreams normally located?\n",
        "answer": "At the tropopause where intensified temperature gradients are located.\n",
        "choiceone": "In areas of strong low pressure systems in the stratosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In a single continuous band, encircling the Earth, where there is a break between the\nequatorial and polar tropopause.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying over the top of a severe thunderstorm, the cloud should be overflown by at\nleast\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet for each 10 knots windspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 feet above any moderate to severe turbulence layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather feature occurs at altitude levels near the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "Maximum winds and narrow wind shear zones.\n",
        "choiceone": "Abrupt temperature increase above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thin layers of cirrus (ice crystal) clouds at the tropopause level.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of standing lenticular altocumulus clouds is a good indication of\n",
        "answer": "very strong turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "a jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "heavy icing conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 149.) What is the forecast temperature at ATL for the 3,000-foot level?\n",
        "answer": "Not reported.\n",
        "choiceone": "+6 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "+6 degrees F.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing Point Depressant (FPD) fluids are highly soluble in water; however,\n",
        "answer": "ice is slow to absorb it, and to melt when in contact with it.\n",
        "choiceone": "ice is slow to absorb it but fast to melt when in contact with FPD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ice absorbs it very fast but is slow to melt when in contact with it.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If squalls are reported at your destination, what wind conditions should you anticipate?\n",
        "answer": "Sudden increases in wind speed of at least 16 knots, rising to 22 knots or more,\nlasting for at least 1 minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "Peak gusts of at least 35 knots for a sustained period of 1 minute or longer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rapid variation in wind direction of at least 20__degrees__ and changes in speed of\nat least 10 knots between peaks and lulls.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a Terminal Aerodrome Forecast (TAF) of P6SM implies that the\nprevailing visibility is expected to be greater than\n",
        "answer": "6 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 nautical miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 kilometers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are haze layers cleared or dispersed?\n",
        "answer": "By wind or the movement of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "By convective mixing in cool night air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By evaporation similar to the clearing of fog.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When soaring in the vicinity of mountain ranges, the greatest potential danger from\nvertical and rotor-type currents will usually be encountered on the\n\n",
        "answer": "leeward side when flying into the wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "leeward side when flying with a tailwind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "windward side when flying into the wind.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ice pellets encountered during flight are normally evidence that\n",
        "answer": "freezing rain exists at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination weather!\nshould be obtained from the\n\nformation for an instrument flight\n",
        "answer": "AFSS.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airman publications.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Atmospheric pressure changes due to a thunderstorm will be at the lowest value\n",
        "answer": "when the thunderstorm is approaching.\n",
        "choiceone": "during the downdraft and heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "immediately after the rain showers have stopped.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 2.) What approximate wind direction, speed, and temperature (relative to\nISA) should a pilot expect when planning for a flight over EMI at FL 270?\n",
        "answer": "265 degrees true; 100 knots; ISA +3 degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees true; 110 knots; ISA +5 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 degrees magnetic; 100 knots; ISA -5 degrees C.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the characteristics of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Poor visibility; steady precipitation; stratus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Good visibility; steady precipitation; stratus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Poor visibility; intermittent precipitation; cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which would increase the stability of an air mass?\n",
        "answer": "Cooling from below.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warming from below.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decrease in water vapor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an approach, the most important and most easily recognized means of being\nalerted to possible wind shear is monitoring the\n",
        "answer": "power and vertical velocity required to remain on the proper glidepath.\n",
        "choiceone": "amount of trim required to relieve control pressures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "heading changes necessary to remain on the runway centerline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unsaturated air flowing up slope will cool at the rate of approximately (dry adiabatic\nlapse rate)\n",
        "answer": "3 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees C per 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sudden penetration of fog can create the illusion of\n",
        "answer": "pitching up.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitching down.\n",
        "choicetwo": "leveling off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What temperature con\naltitude?\n\nindicated if wet snow is encountered at your flight\n",
        "answer": "The temperature is above freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature is below freezing at your altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You are flying from a warm air mass into a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum weather conditions must be forecast for your ETA at an alternate airport,\nthat has only a VOR approach with standard alternate minimums, for the airport to be\nlisted as an alternate on the IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "800-foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "800-foot ceiling and 1 statute mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000-foot ceiling and visibility to allow descent from minimum en route altitude\n(MEA), approach, and landing under basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type storms are most likely to produce funnel clouds or tornadoes?\n",
        "answer": "Cold front or squall line thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Storms associated with icing and supercooled water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the requirements for the formation of a thunderstorm?\n",
        "answer": "Sufficient moisture, an unstable lapse rate, and a lifting action.\n",
        "choiceone": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture and an inverted lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which atmospheric factor causes rapid movement of surface fronts?\n",
        "answer": "Upper winds blowing across the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upper low located directly over the surface low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The cold front overtaking and lifting the warm front.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal waves normally form on\n",
        "answer": "slow moving cold fronts or stationary fronts.\n",
        "choiceone": "slow moving warm fronts and strong occluded fronts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rapidly moving cold fronts or warm fronts.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements applies to the tropopause?\n",
        "answer": "It separates the troposphere from the stratosphere\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis, by definition, an isothermal layer\n",
        "choicetwo": "Itindicates a strong temperature lapse rate\n",
        "choicethree": "Itis, by definition, a temperature inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by QFE?\n",
        "answer": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation, reduced to mean sea\nlevel in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pressure at MSL in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The present atmospheric pressure at an aerodrome converted to mean sea level in\naccordance with the actual conditions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When in summer calm and clear conditions exist, a station on the shore of a large body\nof water will experience wind\n",
        "answer": "from the water in daytime and from the land at night\n",
        "choiceone": "continually from land to water\n",
        "choicetwo": "continually from water to the land\n",
        "choicethree": "from the land in daytime and from the water at night\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which jet stream blows all year round, over the northern hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The subtropical jet stream.\n",
        "choiceone": "The polar night jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The equatorial jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "The arctic jet stream.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider a parcel of air being forced upwards in the atmosphere. The lapse rate of the\nsurrounding air is less than the saturated adiabatic lapse rate. After the initial force is no\nlonger effective, the parcel of air\n\n",
        "answer": "will tend to descend to its original altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "will tend to ascend further.\n",
        "choicetwo": "will tend to remain at the new altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "will become conditionally unstable.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of fog is likely to form when air having temperature of 15\u00b0C and dew point of\n12\u00b0C blows at 10 knots over a sea surface having temperatures of 5\u00b0C ?\n",
        "answer": "Advection fog\n",
        "choiceone": "Radiation fog\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steam fog\n",
        "choicethree": "Frontal fog\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass which originates over the North Atlantic between 50 and 70 degrees north\nand is moving in over Scandinavia is called\n",
        "answer": "maritime polar air.\n",
        "choiceone": "continental arctic air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maritime arctic air.\n",
        "choicethree": "continental polar air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10845A)\nFor an aircraft at FL 40, approaching the front (square 3C) from the direction of square\n3D a potential hazard exists before reaching the front in the form of\n",
        "answer": "clear ice accretion to the airframe\n",
        "choiceone": "severe turbulence associated with CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence and wind shear\n",
        "choicethree": "severe downdrafts from subsiding air\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characterizes a stationary front ?\n",
        "answer": "The surface wind has its direction parallel to the front\n",
        "choiceone": "The surface wind has its direction perpendicular to the front\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warm air moves at approximately half the speed of the cold air\n",
        "choicethree": "The weather conditions that it generates are a combination of those of an intense\ncold front and those of a very active warm front\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special air-report\n",
        "answer": "may trigger a SIGMET message\n",
        "choiceone": "may be the reason for closing an airport due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be the reason for closing a part of an airway due to meteorological conditions\n",
        "choicethree": "is used to produce better aerodrome forecasts (TAF)\n",
        "source": "Completed/MET\\met atpl (9).pdf"
    }
]